<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Springer International Publishing</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Biffl</surname></persName>
							<email>stefan.biffl@tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Information Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Wien</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Information Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Christian Doppler Laboratory for Security and Quality Improvement in the Production System Lifecycle (CDL-SQI)</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Wien</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
							<email>matthias.eckhart@tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Information Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Wien</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">SBA Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
							<email>arndt.lueder@ovgu.de</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Information Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Wien</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Otto-v.-Guericke University/IAF</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Magdeburg</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Edgar</forename><surname>Weippl</surname></persName>
							<email>edgar.weippl@tuwien.ac.at</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Information Systems Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Technische Universität Wien</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">SBA Research</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Vienna</settlement>
									<country key="AT">Austria</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Security and Quality in Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</title>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="29"/>
							<date type="published" when="2019" />
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-25312-7_1</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:21+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Complex cyber-physical systems</term>
					<term>Engineering process</term>
					<term>Multidisciplinary engineering</term>
					<term>AutomationML</term>
					<term>Information security</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Providing Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPSs) more efficiently and faster is a goal that requires improvements in engineering process for producing high-quality, advanced engineering artifacts. Furthermore, information security must be a top priority when engineering C-CPSs as the engineering artifacts represent assets of high value.</p><p>This chapter overviews the engineering process of C-CPSs, typically longrunning technical systems, such as industrial manufacturing systems and continuous processing systems. This chapter also covers major areas of requirements that include: (a) processes with intensive generation of engineering artifacts; (b) challenges regarding dependencies and complexity of engineering artifacts, stemming from variants of a product and the associated production process for a family of products; (c) management of model and consistency rules for dependencies between model parts; (d) the internationalization of the engineering process with partners on different levels of trust; and (e) the security of the engineering processes, such as confidentiality of engineering plans, and the security of the systems to be engineered, such as security aspects in the design phase.</p><p>For selected requirement areas, the chapter discusses several approaches for quality improvement from business informatics that addresses important classes of requirements, but introduces new complexity to the engineering process. Therefore, the chapter reviews information security improvement approaches for engineering</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPSs), typically longrunning and software-intensive technical systems, such as critical infrastructures or industrial production systems and their associated products, is a multidisciplinary, model-driven, and data-driven engineering process that often involves conflicting economic, quality, and security interests, risks, and issues. Quality is a key concern in the engineering process to enable engineers to provide technical systems effectively and efficiently, with a focus on sufficient system quality, particularly on safety and on value to customers. Information security has become increasingly important with growing networking capabilities of technical systems and the rise of the Internet, as the engineering environments and the resulting technical systems are part of a network that allows new kinds of attacks on data and systems. Past cyber-attacks against safety-critical systems, for example, a sewage treatment plant <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">(Slay and Miller 2008)</ref> or a steel mill <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">(Lee et al. 2014)</ref>, demonstrated the devastating consequences that could result from inadequate security measures. Besides potential physical damages, cyber-attacks may also cause silent losses because of intellectual property theft. While practitioners agree that addressing security concerns is crucial for establishing a foundation for system safety and quality, many companies hesitate to introduce sufficient security mechanisms and processes in their environments as well as in their products and engineering processes as they lack methods and information for risk assessment and often cannot relate the benefits to the associated extra cost and reduced usability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Scope of the Book</head><p>Providing software-intensive technical systems more efficiently and faster requires improvements of engineering process quality and, often, global cooperation in distributed engineering that requires improvements in security considerations for engineering processes. As a novel research approach, we consider the combination of quality improvement and information security for analyzing and improving engineering processes. Quality improvement contributions tend to make engineering processes faster and more efficient by reducing avoidable rework. On the other hand, even if stakeholders deem security fundamental, they may have difficulties in arguing the considerable extra cost of resources in engineering processes. Therefore, a balance of quality improvement and security would be desirable, a balance that overall reduces the resources required for engineering processes and introduces an adequate level of security, which is necessary for sustainable engineering in a globally distributed environment.  Contributions to Scientific Communities Automation Systems Engineering. One family of Software-Intensive Technical Systems are Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPSs). Following the Encyclopedia of Business Informatics,1 a Cyber-Physical System (CPS) is defined as a system of communicating components that have both physical and data processing parts. They usually establish a hierarchy of technical system components that are controlled in a closed-loop structure.</p><p>This closed loop is established by measuring the state of the technical system using appropriate sensors, deciding on necessary control actions within an information processing system based on measured state and behavior specification, and executing these control actions by actors <ref type="bibr">(VDI 2206</ref><ref type="bibr">(VDI 2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">Lunze 2016</ref>). Thus, information processing is essential for the behavior quality of the technical system.</p><p>Cyber-Physical Systems range from very simple embedded systems, such as drives or rotary encoders, up to very large systems, such as production systems, power plants, energy transmission systems, air planes, and train systems. In this book, such Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPSs) are considered, characterized by the nature of such systems and the fact that • They require significant effort, material, and financial means.</p><p>• Their life cycle is measured in decades.</p><p>• Their system behavior is complex.</p><p>• Their economic and social impact is significant.</p><p>Within the engineering processes of a C-CPS, information about the overall structure and the mechanical, electrical, etc., construction of the applicable sensors and actors is required in conjunction with the specification of the intended behavior as input. This information must have sufficiently high quality to finally ensure system safety and economic efficiency <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">(Schnieder 1999</ref>). In addition, the engineering results of information processing are required within virtual commissioning and commissioning of the C-CPS <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">(Strahilov and Hämmerle 2017)</ref>. Thus, it is obvious that engineering processes of C-CPS require information exchange between engineering disciplines, involved engineers of possibly different legal entities, and involved engineering tools.</p><p>Contributions in this book consider requirements, risks, and solutions to guarantee the security and quality of C-CPS. Involved engineers and project managers will be enabled to identify possible quality and security challenges they have to cope with. In addition, possible measures are described assisting involved staff to handle the identified challenges.</p><p>C-CPS Software and System Quality Analysis and Improvement. Typical assumptions for research in quality assurance and improvement for small softwareintensive systems that are safe and easy to reset as well as for business software systems that use standard operating systems and hardware and do not rely on specific real-time hardware may not hold for long-running technical systems, such as critical 1http://www.enzyklopaedie-der-wirtschaftsinformatik.de/lexikon/informationssysteme/ Sektorspezifische-Anwendungssysteme/cyber-physische-systeme infrastructure or industrial production systems. Therefore, researchers in quality assurance and improvement can benefit from better understanding challenges on quality assurance and quality improvement coming from the engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems based on the use cases and requirements presented in Part I. The use cases and methods for software and system quality analysis and improvement discussed in Part II, such as engineering process analysis, model-based systems engineering, or test automation, provide researchers with insights from in-depth examples that can be adapted to a range of similar but different applications. Finally, the security threats and countermeasures discussed in Part III provide nonexperts in information security with insights into issues to consider when designing quality improvements in engineering contexts. Therefore, researchers and practitioners can take away requirements and building blocks for future methods and tools from the discussion of quality improvement approaches to address selected challenges from automation systems engineering. Information Security. Researchers in the information security area gain a comprehensive understanding of the security challenges involved in engineering Complex Cyber-Physical Systems. Furthermore, the proposed concepts for securing the engineering process will allow them to evaluate other approaches in order to determine whether they can be applied to overcome these challenges. Since this book also covers security aspects that go beyond protecting the engineering process, researchers gain insights into how the security of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems can be enhanced by integrating security into the engineering phase. Finally, the discussed open challenges may motivate scholars to develop and pursue new research directions.</p><p>The remainder of the chapter is structured as follows: Sect. 1.2 introduces Engineering Processes for Software-Intensive Systems and requirements for quality and security improvement. Section 1.3 discusses business informatics approaches for quality improvement that address classes of requirements from engineering software-intensive systems, but may introduce unwanted IT security risks and requirements. Section 1.4 analyzes potential security issues that may be encountered when engineering software-intensive systems. Based on this analysis, the section defines security requirements that must be met; otherwise, these issues may result in compromised engineering processes, which eventually also affect the security of the systems to be developed. Section 1.5 provides an overview on the book parts and the contributions of the chapters to address advanced engineering process requirements. Section 1.6 suggests relevant contributions in this book for selected reader groups.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2">Engineering Processes for Software-Intensive Systems</head><p>This section introduces an engineering process view on the engineering of longrunning software-intensive technical systems, such as industrial manufacturing systems and continuous processing systems, and derives major areas of requirements. 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . . 5</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.1">Background</head><p>Our daily life is characterized by technical systems that make our life easier, more comfortable, and safer compared with the lives of our ancestors. These systems create, distribute, maintain, and dispose goods, energy, and information relevant for our lives. Some of these systems are designed for a very long life span, for example, nuclear power plants or production systems in the process industry running several decades. Some of these systems have a medium long life span, for example, production systems, wind mills, or ships running about one decade. And some of them have only a very short lifespan, like rockets. All of these technical systems (fulfill at least three of the four characteristics of a C-CPS) have in common the need to be designed, established, and controlled. Therefore, appropriate information processing systems are required to establish C-CPS. Especially, the control of the behavior of these systems is a critical problem requiring high-quality, safe, and secure software systems. Therefore, such systems are considered cyber-physical systems combining physical parts (establishing the mechanical, electrical, electronical, etc., construction) and cyber parts (establishing the information processing for control of behavior) <ref type="bibr">(Zanero 2017;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">Monostori 2014;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">Lee 2008)</ref>.</p><p>The engineering of such cyber-physical systems comprises usually the phases requirement collection, architecture design, implementation, test, deployment, and operation. In all phases, the duality of hardware and software needs to be considered <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">(Gruhn et al. 2017)</ref>. Considering requirement collection, architecture design, implementation, and operation of these systems is of dual nature. On the one hand, the proper system behavior has to be achieved regarding the reason why the system is designed. In case of a nuclear power plant or a wind mill, proper system behavior is the correct current and voltage intended over time, in case of a ship or a rocket proper system behavior is proper transportation conditions enabling proper transport services; and in case of a production system proper system behavior is the proper product creation. In all cases, the intended output of the system drives the correct behavior.</p><p>One special type of long-living C-CPS are production systems. These systems possess a duality of products to be produced by executing production processes and the production system executing the production processes. Both system kinds need to be engineered and depend on each other. Here, the so-called PPR concept, concerning product design, production process design, and production resource design, provides the background <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Biffl et al. 2017a)</ref>. Their life cycle and their engineering are detailed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">Biffl et al. (2017b)</ref>. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>.1 illustrates the engineering process steps and selected domain expert roles for engineering a C-CPS.</p><p>Within such a C-CPS, the product definition as the first step of the engineering process provides both the behavior specification as well as technical, economic, environmental, legal, etc., bordering conditions. As an example, a rolling mill shall be considered. Starting point of the rolling mill engineering is the product definition of the rolled steel. Thereby, the production process of the intended steel coils is defined and steel properties, such as steel type and mass, are given. This specification is from the information point of view similar to the definition of the intended current flow in a power plant or the transport behavior of a rocket. Usually, the product definition is provided by a product designer as first stakeholder of the engineering process. As indicated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">Foehr et al. (2013)</ref>, the product definition is accompanied by a description of the intended product quality, which is a requirement for the production process execution and, thereby, for the technical and behavioral properties of the production system. For a rolling mill, the product definition is given by the intended material thickness and material properties resulting in a set of necessary milling steps with milling pressure and cooling properties.</p><p>The product definition is succeeded by the preliminary design of the production system. Within this second phase, the production system designer as second involved stakeholder develops the overall system structure by assigning manufacturing resources to the different required production process steps of the product. In a steel mill, this overall system structure defines for example the number of mating roles, the length of the transport system (and thereby the number of transport roles), and the number of cooling units.</p><p>Exploiting the developed overall system, design groups of discipline-specific engineers covering mechanical, electrical, automation, etc. engineering act as the next stakeholders in the third production system engineering (PSE) process phase. They detail the production system design in the different engineering disciplines in a parallel and round-trip-driven way leading to a system specification in such detail that it can be physically established. For a rolling mill for example, the mechanical engineering defines type and location of drives and roles of the different required types, the electrical engineering defines their wiring related to electrical power transmission and control signal exchange, and the automation system engineering implements the necessary control system parts required to drive the roles dependent on the intended steel quality. The next phase in the production system engineering process contains its physical realization based on the developed engineering artifacts by several involved installation and ramp-up specialists as last set of stakeholders. As indicated by <ref type="bibr">Lüder et al. (2017a, b)</ref>, the involved stakeholders exchange engineering information along the complete life cycle of the production system. Therefore, they require standardized information exchange technologies as indicated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">Lüder et al. (2017c)</ref>. The intended increasing digitalization of a wide range of technical systems following approaches like Industry 4.0 or Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT) establishes additional intentions to the engineering. The different components of technical systems shall be accompanied by their digital representation realized as the management shell of the Industry 4.0 component or the digital shadow in the IoT world. Using this digital representation, necessary activities like system maintenance and system optimization can be simplified and improved, leading to safer, more environmental-protective, and more economic systems. Thus, also stakeholders like users, maintainers, etc., come into play for the high-quality and secure engineering process.</p><p>Another main development direction in the engineering of production systems is the increasing use of system knowledge. This covers for example the reuse of existing artifacts, the system-wide standardization of components, the application of system family architectures, etc. This trend is mainly addressed by engineering organization improvement approaches as for example in VDI Guideline 3695 <ref type="bibr">(2009)</ref>. Comparing the engineering and use of other types of C-CPS with the engineering and use of production systems, it is easy to see that they usually involve similar life cycle phases and sets of stakeholders <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">(Lindemann 2007</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.2.2">Research Questions</head><p>The intended quality and security improvement of engineering processes of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPS) initially requires an improvement of the understanding of these processes to enable the identification of possible impacts of quality and security improvement approaches that have been developed in information sciences. Thus, the initial research question considered in this book is related to a detailed knowledge about structure, behavior, and further characteristics of engineering processes for C-CPS.</p><p>RQ1a: What Are Typical Characteristics of Engineering Processes for Long-Running Software-Intensive Technical Systems? As indicated earlier, an engineering process of C-CPS establishes a network of engineering activities connected by information exchange. The different involved engineering disciplines step-by-step enrich the overall model system of the intended technical system. Each discipline works with its own models, while all related models need to be kept consistent, that is, there are model-crossing consistency rules to be considered. In addition, models of early engineering phases are applied to generate further models of higher level of detail. Information science consists of different software-related disciplines. In addition, model-driven software engineering <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Brambilla et al. 2017</ref>) is well known. But software engineering (in the context of engineering a C-CPS) is of limited disciplinerelated variance. Thus, the applicability of security and quality improvement measures from information sciences for improvement of C-CPS is unclear. The applicability is likely to strongly depend on the characteristics of the model creation and use within the established engineering network.</p><p>Within engineering networks of C-CPS, not only cyclic information exchange following round-trip engineering, merging of engineering information, and handling intended and unintended (not to be disclosed) but also incomplete engineering information occurs. In addition, the involved engineering disciplines might have model elements with similar semantic but different syntactic representations leading to the misinterpretation of exchanged information.</p><p>To understand the characteristics of engineering processes for C-CPS and to derive requirements related to quality and security improvement in Part I of this book, three engineering processes coming from different industries are described in detail. In one chapter, the topic of interrelation of model-driven C-CPS engineering with the models of other life cycle phases of C-CPS is discussed in order to derive specific data quality requirements and dependencies as inputs to Part II and Part III of this book.</p><p>RQ1b: What Are the Requirement Areas from Engineering Processes for Long-Running Software-Intensive Technical Systems That Require Informatics Contributions? Mostly, engineering processes are considered similar to business processes. Therefore, the accumulated requirements usually focus on economic issues. However, engineering processes of C-CPS are based on a detailed engineering data logistics, which has to ensure the availability of engineering information at the right point at the right moment with the right costs and (most important) with the right quality. Quality in this case means as correct as necessary at a point in the engineering process.</p><p>Correctness can be impacted in different ways: models may be inadequate, incomplete, or contradicting, etc. This incorrectness can be a result of unintended behavior (like erroneous tool use) but also from intended behavior (like maliciously changed data). Availability of engineering information can be considered as a straightforward process management issue. However, in parallel engineering, it might be intentional to provide incomplete data temporarily to shorten the overall project duration. In this case, the manager needs to identify at which point in time and in the process the engineering data providers have to provide information at which degree of completeness.</p><p>Both problems can be summarized under the term engineering data quality. Requirement areas for quality improvement include (QI1) processes with iterative generation of engineering artifacts (like round-trip engineering); (QI2) challenges regarding dependencies and complexity of engineering artifacts stemming from 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . . 9 variants of intended system behaviors; and (QI3) management of model and consistency rules for dependencies between model parts. Requirements areas for IT security include (Sect. 1.1) the internationalization of the engineering process with partners on different levels of trust; and (Sect. 1.2) security, such as the confidentiality of engineering plans and traceable changes to engineering artifacts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3">Requirements for Quality Improvement</head><p>For selected requirement areas, this section discusses approaches for quality improvement from business informatics that can address classes of requirements. However, some quality improvement approaches tend to introduce new complexity to the engineering process and security risks that require further research to address.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3.1">Background</head><p>Companies that engineer Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPS), such as industrial production systems based on third-party components, aim at developing systems of sufficient quality in an efficient manner. These systems typically are part of a family of similar but different systems and require for their efficient engineering, capabilities for modeling, refactoring, and reusing system variants, ideally incorporating in new designs the lessons learned from the operation and maintenance of systems in the family.</p><p>In this context, several trends in engineering C-CPS require capabilities for quality improvement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>System Aspects</head><p>The Industry 4.0 vision aims at developing flexible C-CPSs that require stronger capabilities for engineering more complex systems. These systems may have capabilities for self-adaptation making their validation more difficult. The engineering of families of C-CPS requires mastering the dependencies between complex engineering artifacts both between engineering discipline model views and between variants of the system in the family and the associated production process. These dependencies complicate the management of versioning and consistency checking.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Process Aspects</head><p>The development of C-CPSs in short innovation cycles supports the trend of moving from traditional paper-based waterfall process to a modern agile iterative software-and data-based engineering process. To shorten the project duration, parallel engineering requires automating the information exchange following round-trip engineering and advanced change management capabilities for merging of engineering information coming from several disciplines at different levels of maturity and completeness. To make engineering more efficient, the automated engineering requires capabilities for automated checking of model- crossing consistency rules, for generating engineering artifacts, and engineering organization improvement (VDI 3695 2009) for better cooperation of engineering disciplines.</p><p>To make engineering cheaper, companies cooperate globally requiring capabilities for the internationalization of the engineering process and associated information security. Unfortunately, the applicability of security and quality improvement measures from information sciences and business informatics remains unclear due to important differences in the industrial context, such as limitations from regulations and technology.</p><p>Business Requirements Requirements for quality definition, assurance, and improvement come from stakeholders <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Biffl et al. 2017a)</ref>. System operators and maintainers require C-CPSs that enable providing services, for example, for production, effectively and efficiently; systems that are easy to set up, train, maintain, extend, and analyze for service optimization. Technology providers of components and tools for engineering require the C-CPS to follow established system architecture standards and influence the solution space in engineering projects considerably. Regulators require the C-CPS to follow established validation standards to ensure surpassing minimal quality levels for safety and the environment. Domain experts and system engineers from several discipline-specific workgroups require an engineering process that allows them to work effectively and efficiently in parallel on enriching the engineering plans and configuration as design information becomes more specific and valid along the development process. Project and quality managers require an overview on the discipline contributions to the engineering process to allow assessing whether the engineering data providers have provided their information on a sufficient degree of completeness, accuracy, and validity.</p><p>These system and process aspects as well as stakeholder requirements concern quality aspects and capabilities for quality assurance and improvement.</p><p>Quality According to IEEE (ISO Square 2014), software and systems quality refers to two aspects: (a) the degree to which a system, component, or process meets specified requirements; and (b) the degree to which a system, component, or process meets customer or user needs or expectations. While the first aspect refers to the verification of software and systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">(Kaner et al. 1999)</ref>, the latter aspect refers to validation of software and systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">(Myers and Sandler 1979)</ref>. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">Gilb (2005)</ref> introduced the Planguage to define quality requirements for improving systems engineering in quickly changing environments. Assessing the quality of a C-CPS, for example, an industrial production system, concerns system capabilities and technical parameters, and requires capabilities for system validation regarding well-defined quality requirements. Assessing the quality of processes, for example, engineering and production processes, such as process capabilities, effectiveness, efficiency, duration, cost, or risk, requires capabilities for engineering process analysis as well as for representing and processing knowledge on the system, the processes, and their relationships during engineering and operation <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">(Schleipen et al. 2015)</ref>. Assessing the quality of data, for example, engineering artifacts, data, and knowledge, such as completeness, correctness, adequacy, consistency, accuracy, validity, and understandability for humans and machines (as foundation for Industry 4.0 functions) requires capabilities for advanced engineering data management, such as the data logistics between workgroups coming from different disciplines.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Software Engineering Challenges in a C-CPS Engineering Context</head><p>Software tools and data processing are a core foundation for automating engineering process. Unfortunately, software tools are often designed for addressing the requirements of one engineering discipline and do not know or care about partner disciplines or project aspects. Over the last decades, domain experts with systems engineering background have moved from using software tools toward configuring software tools, and toward writing software scripts and home-grown tools of increasing size, complexity, and importance to running an engineering project.</p><p>Unfortunately, many domain experts do not have the software engineering experience to make informed software design decisions, leading to considerable technical debt in data models and in software, for example, scripts that exchange engineering artifacts and data or generate engineering artifacts. The symptoms of technical debt can be found easily when analyzing engineering processes and project experiences in a typical medium-to-large engineering company regarding the modeling and management of dependencies, such as model-crossing consistency rules, between engineering artifacts coming from different disciplines, cyclic information exchange between engineering workgroups, merging of engineering information coming from several data providers, and handling of incomplete engineering information. Therefore, engineering processes of C-CPS that depend on a detailed engineering data logistics to ensure the availability of engineering information at the right point at the right moment with the right costs and (most important) with the right quality, tend in practice to be error-prone and costly, and require strong capabilities for quality assurance and improvement.</p><p>Quality Assurance This is a way of preventing mistakes and defects in manufactured products and avoiding problems when delivering solutions or services to customers, which ISO 9000 (2015) defines as "part of quality management focused on providing confidence that quality requirements will be fulfilled." Quality assurance (QA) includes in the software and systems engineering lifecycle capabilities for constructive QA, to make sufficient quality more likely to achieve, and for analytic QA, such as system validation and process analysis. Constructive quality assurance <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">(Tian 2005</ref>; Laporte and April 2018) includes processes to plan and control a software or systems engineering project, that is, by defining individual steps within the system life cycle and methods that support individual steps along the engineering project. In the context of software engineering, examples include model-driven engineering <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Borky and Bradley 2018;</ref><ref type="bibr">Whittle et al. 2019</ref>) and test-driven engineering aiming at enabling the construction of high-quality products based on defined processes with integrated quality assurance approaches. Analytic quality assurance <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">(Wagner 2007)</ref> refers to methods and tools aiming at identifying defects effectively and efficiently along the system life cycle. While static quality assurance approaches, such as reviewing (Zhu 2016), are applicable to non-executable artifacts, such as models or specification documents including (software) code documents, dynamic quality assurance approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">(Kenett et al. 2018)</ref>, such as software and system tests, require executable code and/or models within an engineering and test environment.</p><p>Quality Improvement According to the Shewhart cycle for learning and improvement (PDSA; <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">Deming 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">Deming , 1993</ref> or the Japanese Plan-Do-Check-Act (PDCA; <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">Sokovic et al. 2010</ref>) cycle, quality improvement refers to analyzing the state of the practice, such as quality improvement in the software and systems engineering lifecycles; identifying and implementing improvement actions; evaluating implemented improvements; and adjusting knowledge for further improvements in the context of a continuous improvement strategy <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">(Ning et al. 2010)</ref>. Often, quality assurance and improvement is organized in a quality assurance ecosystem <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Bosch 2009;</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">Axelsson and Skoglund 2016)</ref>. Quality improvement approaches typically focus on the improvement of processes and organizations in the context of standards, such as ISO 9001 <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">(Hoyle 2017)</ref>, CMMI <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Beth et al. 2011)</ref>, and SPICE <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Abowd et al. 2018)</ref>, and methods and tools, typically following the PDSA <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(Deming 1986</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Deming , 1993</ref> or the PDCA approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">(Sokovic et al. 2010)</ref>. While these approaches for quality assurance and improvement have been used successfully in business software engineering contexts, their application to the engineering processes of C-CPS requires considerable adaptations that require empirical validation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.3.2">Research Questions</head><p>Business informatics has successfully improved and automated business processes with software in diverse areas, such as business administration, government, and health care. Business informatics approaches, such as agile software development, test-driven development, and DevOps, have the potential to significantly improve the capabilities of software engineering teams to deliver software solutions faster, more efficiently, more flexibly, and with higher quality. Therefore, the adaptation of successful business informatics approaches to the engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPS) could be promising to address requirements of stakeholders that look similar in both areas.</p><p>However, the engineering of C-CPS has characteristics that differ in important ways from typical business software engineering contexts, such as real-time hardware capabilities, the cooperation of several engineering disciplines with widely varying models that depend on each other, and requirements for safety that limit the direct application of business informatics approaches. Therefore, we look in Part II of this book at the following overarching research questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ2: How Can Proven Business Informatics Approaches Be Adapted for Improving the Engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems?</head><p>From this research question, we derive the following research questions that consider both (a) the potential of better quality improvement capabilities for engineering C-CPS, such as more effective dependency management between engineering disciplines, and (b) security 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>13</head><p>implications that may come from interventions of quality improvement approaches, such as centralizing and integrating engineering knowledge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ2a: How Can Approaches Adapted from Business Informatics Address Quality Improvement Requirements Coming from Characteristics of C-CPS Engineering?</head><p>This research question concerns first the identification of promising business informatics approaches, such as agile software development, business process analysis, knowledge representation, model-based engineering, test-driven development, and variability management for addressing selected trends in the engineering of C-CPS.</p><p>For the selected business informatics approaches, the book chapters will discuss how these approaches are likely to address selected requirements coming from the engineering of C-CPS, in particular, different characteristics of engineering business software solutions and C-CPS that require the adaptation of business informatics approaches. Finally, the book chapters in Part II will identify interventions to the engineering of C-CPS, such as changes to the engineering process, models, methods, or mechanisms to facilitate quality improvement and addressing important requirements of C-CPS stakeholders.</p><p>RQ2b: Which Interventions of Quality Improvement Approaches Are Likely to Introduce or Increase Information Security Requirements and Risks? Following the goal of the book, toward combining approaches from quality improvement and information security improvement, we will analyze the interventions to the engineering of C-CPS identified when answering RQ2a, such as centrally accessible data repositories and the collaboration with partially trusted and untrusted parties, regarding their impact on information security requirements, capabilities, and risks. For example, an open question is how a secure round-trip engineering process can be implemented and applied in automation systems development-a major management goal of PSE is the reduction of PSE resource needs, while securing any process tends to add complexity and resource requirements. As a result, we will introduce a model on how selected factors from the domains of C-CPS engineering, quality improvement, and security improvement influence each other as foundation for analyzing where the combination of approaches from quality improvement and information security improvement is most relevant to enable the comparison of options that consider both quality and security solution aspects. Finally, we will discuss options for combining security with quality improvement approaches, such as the early consideration of typical security requirements and contributions in adapted quality assurance and improvement methods, for example, when applying the VDI guideline 3695 for engineering organization improvement or for representing security as a system quality in variability handling approaches. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4">Security Considerations for the Engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems</head><p>This section discusses security concerns that arise in the context of engineering Complex Cyber-Physical Systems (C-CPSs). Based on this, we derive requirements and, in further consequence, research questions that aim to address these security concerns.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4.1">Background</head><p>Similar to the part that discusses security, this section covers security issues related to engineering C-CPSs from two different points of view. First, we provide background information for the chapters on securing the engineering process and then give context to the chapters that deal with the aspects to be considered for developing more secure C-CPSs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4.1.1">Securing the Engineering Process</head><p>As introduced in Sect. 1.2.1, the engineering of C-CPSs represents a multidisciplinary process that involves the exchange of engineering-related information among stakeholders. As part of each engineering step, artifacts are created, managed, and edited by engineers who make use of domain-specific tools. These engineering artifacts may then also serve as an input for subsequent engineering steps. As a result, a data logistics solution that is seamlessly integrated into the engineering workflow, coupled with the use of a common data exchange format (e.g., AutomationML), may improve the engineering efficiency and, in further consequence, increase the overall quality of the engineering process. However, considering that the exchanged data not only includes valuable know-how about the system to be developed but also poses a severe security and safety threat if altered with malicious intent, protecting the engineering data logistics is paramount. For instance, adversaries may attempt to obtain the exchanged engineering data for the purpose of industrial espionage or even tamper with blueprints to implant flaws into the system's design, allowing them to exploit these vulnerabilities during operation (Weippl and <ref type="bibr">Kieseberg 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kieseberg , 2018</ref>. Thus, the data logistics system is an attractive target for cyber-attacks, especially if it is similar to a data repository that provides a central point of access to all engineering artifacts. This issue is exacerbated by the fact that engineering projects may be executed by globally distributed teams, some of which may even belong to external companies (i.e., subcontractors) (Weippl and Kieseberg 2017). Consequently, engineering data must be protected against external threat actors (i.e., individuals who are not involved in engineering projects and launch attacks via the 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>15</head><p>Internet or Intranet) and insider threats (i.e., employees who sabotage engineering activities or leak data).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Challenges and Requirements</head><p>There are several research challenges that must be overcome to work toward a secure engineering process while keeping engineering efficiency and quality high. First, a lack of understanding about potential attack vectors and the threats to assets of the data logistics solution may result in inaccurate risk assessments, which would affect the treatment of risks. In other words, if security risks are not thoroughly analyzed, the data logistics system may not be adequately protected against cyber threats, or the implemented countermeasures may undermine its value for improving the engineering workflow. To give a concrete example, current tools within the engineering toolchain lack a fine-grained access control mechanism (Weippl and Kieseberg 2017), meaning that engineering artifacts may be disclosed to subjects that do not even require access to these resources. On the other hand, if standardized access control solutions are introduced without considering the peculiarities of engineering projects, a decrease in productivity is inevitable. Thus, research is required to study how existing security approaches can be tailored to fit the needs of engineering projects while paying attention to achieving a fair balance between meeting engineering quality and security requirements. Still, research in this area would benefit from insights gained from prior works that deal with threat modeling and risk assessment related to the exchange of engineering information.</p><p>Second, novel security methods that guarantee the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of engineering data at rest as well as at transit are required. The primary challenge in this regard is to provide seamless integration of these security methods into engineering toolchains of different kinds. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">Hundt and Lüder (2012)</ref>, there are three main types of engineering toolchains, viz., "One Tool for All," "Best of Breed," and "Integration Framework." As the authors point out, these approaches vary in terms of the achieved level of integration into engineering activities, which in turn drives the complexity of information models and flows. Thus, security methods that attempt to accomplish the aforementioned security goals in engineering processes must be able to cope with the complexity that each tool integration approach entails. Considering that the tools used within the engineering process are often proprietary, equipping existing closed-source engineering tools with security features represents an additional issue. In this context, developing secure interfaces to engineering tools that lack security features may be a promising approach to tackle this challenge. Yet, it is also worth mentioning that establishing a secure engineering workflow is not only a technical but also an organizational task. Identifying the security gaps in the underlying business processes of the engineering lifecycle lays the foundation for setting up organizational security policies in order to comply with governance and legal requirements.</p><p>Third, ensuring the traceability of processed and shared engineering data represents an essential requirement for data logistics solutions. In particular, information about the origins of data, who modified what, when, and how is vital for creating an audit trail. The recorded events can then be monitored to detect suspicious activity from engineers, enabling security analysts to resolve potential issues in a timely manner. Additionally, reviewing the audit trail for further investigations of security incidents may assist them in taking reactive security measures. In this way, secure collaboration between engineers may be fostered. Besides protecting valuable engineering artifacts from security threats, meeting this requirement may also prevent data inconsistencies and thereby provide round-trip engineering support. However, thus far, it remains unclear how such traceability features can be implemented in data logistics systems. Fourth, countering industrial espionage in the context of engineering C-CPSs deserves more attention from both academia and industry. Intellectual property theft represents a severe threat for vendors and systems integrators, especially if collaborating with third parties, such as local suppliers, is required (Weippl and Kieseberg 2017). Thus, novel techniques for protecting know-how are needed to prevent adversaries from stealing knowledge or at least being able to hold them legally accountable for their wrongdoing. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kieseberg and Weippl (2018)</ref>, there are two concepts that may be adopted to address this challenge, viz., obfuscation (i.e., modifying data in a way that it is no longer useful for adversaries) and watermarking (i.e., hiding additional information for the purpose of detecting data leaks and tracing misuse). Although methods from both categories have been extensively researched (e.g., code obfuscation, privacy, digital watermarking), it is still unknown how these methods can be applied to engineering artifacts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4.1.2">Considering Security Aspects Along the Engineering Phase</head><p>The realization of the Industry 4.0 vision <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">(Kagermann et al. 2013</ref>) demands extensive connectivity capabilities of technical systems. In fact, ubiquitous connectivity as an enabler for efficiency improvements and cost reductions can be considered as one of the driving forces behind the Information Technology (IT) and Operational Technology (OT) convergence <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">(Hahn 2016</ref>). However, with the ever-increasing need to interconnect OT systems, which are clearly related to C-CPSs, the number of points of attacks grows likewise, causing the risk of cyber-attacks to rise. This issue is aggravated by the fact that inherently insecure OT systems become exposed to cyber threats. The reason for the increased susceptibility of OT systems is that stakeholders of engineering projects tend to give more weight to availability than other security goals, such as confidentiality and integrity <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">(Ullrich et al. 2016</ref>). However, with the IT/OT convergence, which signifies the end of air-gapped OT systems, information security becomes a pressing issue. Moreover, considering that the lifecycle of technical systems is approx. 15-30 years <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">(Macaulay and Singer 2016)</ref>, legacy systems represent a long-lasting risk factor. Legacy systems often lack fundamental security features and may also not be updatable because of (1) the lack of patches, (2) missing testing capabilities, (3) inefficient patch deployment techniques, and (4) the necessity of undergoing recertification upon patching (Weippl and <ref type="bibr">Kieseberg 2017</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">Kieseberg , 2018</ref>. However, even if patching would be a viable option, flaws in the design of systems may render security updates ineffective. According to 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . . a recent report published by <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">Dragos, Inc. (2018)</ref>, this seems to be the case for 64% of the vulnerability patches for OT components that have been released in 2017. To resolve this problem, engineers must consider security aspects already early on in the systems' lifecycle, that is, the engineering phase. While in the software industry this is a long-established practice, as for example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">McGraw (2004</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">McGraw ( , 2006</ref> and Microsoft <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">(Howard and Lipner 2006)</ref> proposed their concepts for the development of secure software more than a decade ago, the industrial informatics community took the first steps in this direction just a couple of years ago <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">(Schmittner et al. 2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Challenges and Requirements</head><p>The combined safety and security development lifecycle proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Schmittner et al. (2015)</ref> represents a valuable contribution that may be used as a starting point. Yet, given its generic nature, it may be too coarse to assist stakeholders of C-CPSs engineering projects in their dayto-day work. In particular, engineers may benefit from a variant of the lifecycle discussed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Schmittner et al. (2015)</ref> that is tailored to the subprocesses typically involved in the engineering of C-CPSs (e.g., plant design, electrical planning).</p><p>By rigorously following such a security development lifecycle for complex cyberphysical systems, information security may be established as an integral part of the engineering process and thereby foster a security-aware culture in each engineering discipline. In this way, the industrial systems' architecture in its entirety would be designed with security in mind, covering the (1) hardware, (2) firmware, (3) software, (4) network, and (5) process layer <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">(McLaughlin et al. 2016</ref>). However, the key challenge in this context is to identify the specific security activities that either fit within the realm of each engineering subprocess or that do not entail a radical restructuring of the engineering workflow. Furthermore, engineers would benefit from tool-supported security activities or practices that augment the traditional C-CPSs engineering process. Thus, the development of tools that aim to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the security development lifecycle for complex cyberphysical systems poses a further research challenge. One emerging research area that may prove to be beneficial in overcoming this challenge is the concept of digital twins. For instance, <ref type="bibr">Eckhart and Ekelhart (2018a, b)</ref> introduced security-related use cases of digital twins, such as penetration testing. Although these use cases may be applicable in the engineering phase, <ref type="bibr">Eckhart and Ekelhart (2018a, b)</ref> barely touch on the specific applications within the engineering process, leaving great room for exploring this subject in more detail. Furthermore, given that the connectivity of C-CPSs significantly increases in light of Industry 4.0, securing communications technologies deserves more focus in the engineering process. As a matter of fact, wireless connectivity seems to be one of the building blocks of the Industrial Internet of Things (IIoT), meaning that its wide adoption can be expected in the years to come. Yet, from a security perspective, this may increase the risk of a cyber-attack, as adversaries no longer need to work their way forward to the (wired) control network, nor do they require (on-site) physical access; instead, they can launch attacks against control devices if they are within reach of wireless networks <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Stouffer et al. 2015)</ref>. In response to the increased level of risk that systems with wireless network capabilities may pose, the NIST SP 800-82 guideline <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">(Stouffer et al. 2015)</ref> recommends that they should only be deployed in industrial settings that have a low impact. Still, given their susceptibility to cyberattacks,2 research in the areas of wireless network security and IIoT security, in general, with an emphasis on engineering and design aspects, is required. On a final note, it must be ensured that the C-CPSs to be engineered operate not only in a secure but also safe manner. As <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">Ullrich et al. (2016)</ref> correctly point out, this can be achieved by considering security and safety aspects jointly in the engineering process, such as defined in the lifecycle proposed by <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">Schmittner et al. (2015)</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.4.2">Research Questions</head><p>As indicated in Sect. 1.4.1, improving the security of C-CPSs requires securing the engineering process, on the one hand, and considering security aspects when engineering these systems, on the other hand. In this way, cyber threats targeting the engineering process (e.g., with the objective to implant vulnerabilities into the systems' design) can be mitigated while ensuring that these systems have been engineered with security in mind. Since Part III of this book aims to help organizations in achieving these security improvements by addressing some of the challenges discussed in the previous subsection, we have defined the following two research questions: In essence, the book chapters that attempt to answer this research question will provide a guide to hardening a data logistics solution and discuss novel methods to reduce the risk of tampering with engineering artifacts and information disclosure. Answering this research question requires the introduction of a risk-based approach to exchanging engineering information by means of centrally accessible data repositories. Furthermore, an investigation of data integrity threats and information theft is needed to fend off targeted attacks against data repositories that aim to sabotage systems' engineering or steal know-how of high value. This will allow readers to gain an in-depth understanding of the threats pertaining to engineering data logistics and how they can be mitigated with the security concepts presented.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RQ3b: How Can the Security of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems Be Enhanced by Considering Security Aspects During the Engineering Phase?</head><p>This research question focuses on the security challenges and requirements discussed in the second part of Sect. 1.4.1. In particular, selected security improvement approaches, which aim at supporting engineers to develop C-CPSs with security in mind, will be 2See, e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">Radmand et al. (2010)</ref> for a taxonomy of attacks against wireless sensor networks that are used in industrial environments. discussed. To answer this research question, the book chapters will examine ( <ref type="formula">1</ref>) novel concepts that may support security activities within the lifecycle of C-CPSs, (2) measures to protect the connectivity layer of these systems, and (3) recent approaches to designing them in a way that they are able to tolerate arbitrary faults, which is especially important if they are deployed in safety-critical environments. In this way, readers will be equipped with novel concepts that can be applied during the engineering phase in order to develop more secure C-CPSs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.5">Book Structure</head><p>This book discusses challenges and solutions for quality and security improvements for design processes of long-running technical systems, such as design process integrity, that differ from well-known processes, methods, and mechanisms from business software engineering. The authors consider how a combination of quality and security viewpoints can help to improve engineering processes of longrunning technical systems in a way that allows practitioners to introduce sufficient security considerations. An example for such a combination would be a data logistics system that improves the effectiveness and efficiency of work groups in industrial engineering, such as mechanical, electrical, and software engineering.</p><p>The introduction of such a data logistics system raises new information security risks as the integrated engineering models provide more information for a hacker on the planned product that would be interesting intellectual property to leak to competitors and would provide intelligence knowledge to plan systematic attacks on the resulting product in operation. Therefore, the book is structured in three parts to cover security and quality improvements in the engineering of long-running technical systems. Application examples for long-running technical systems will come mainly from the area of industrial production systems such as automotive, steel works, power plant, or oil production (including the vision of Industry 4.0), but the considerations will be applicable to the engineering of a wide range of traditional and future technical systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.5.1">Part I: Product Engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems</head><p>Part I on Engineering Networks as application context discusses challenges and approaches for the C-CPS engineering processes including key stakeholders, structured engineering methods, engineering data quality, reuse of engineering know-how, and data security in engineering. During the C-CPS lifecycle and the installation of the system, information processing concerns the creation, change, exchange, and use of engineering data and artifacts in order to characterize, design, configure, and verify the future C-CPS and its parts. C-CPSs, such as production systems as manufacturing cells or steel mills, power generation and distribution systems like wind mills and HVAC stations, and transportation systems like trains control powerful and risky physical processes and must meet domain-specific safety, environmental, and quality standards. Meeting these standards is challenging for traditional technical systems and even more challenging for Complex Cyber-Physical Systems according to the Industry 4.0 vision. Thus Part I collects challenges and requirements regarding information management and exchange to ensure sufficient quality and security of engineering data. Chapters with their contributions to the overall book in Part I are the following.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 2: Engineering in an International Context-Risks and Challenges</head><p>This chapter discusses risks and challenges based on the increased globalization of engineering of C-CPS. This chapter discusses possible organizational structures and reachable performance resulting from increasing globalization and digitalization on systems engineering. It describes best practice for internationalization strategies and collects requirement to information management resulting from these strategies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 3: Managing Complexity Within the Engineering of Product and Production Systems</head><p>This chapter displays the complexity problem emerging from the required parallelization of engineering of products (i.e., cars) and production systems (i.e., car production) in automotive industry. Starting from a detailed presentation of the engineering process the relevance of engineering data within the complexity management is considered and challenges to information management to be solved to improve process management, change management (required to cope with late product changes within the production system engineering), and knowledge management are named.</p><p>Chapter 4: Engineering of Signaling Systems This chapter discusses the engineering within a strongly regulated field of rail-based public transport systems that is an example of very safety critical systems. Thus, their engineering is very quality and security sensitive. The chapter considers the general structure of the engineering of rail systems focusing on the engineering of signaling systems within them. Based on this process discussion the chapter gives challenges on the engineering tools (and tool chains), engineering processes, and engineering data.</p><p>Chapter 5: On the Need for Data-Driven Model-Based Engineering This chapter motivates requirements for linking system design-time models to run-time models as foundation for improving the design-time models based on the analysis of data from operation. The chapter considers the evolutionary aspects of the engineering data creation process and derives challenges to be tackled when integrating runtime and design-time models and processes. As a theoretical solution a Temporal Model Framework is presented. This framework is applied in three illustrative use cases that discuss technology/methodology candidates to be used within a technical architecture for connecting design-time models and run-time models to improve design-time models. 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>21</head><p>Chapter 6: On Testing Data-Intensive Software Systems This chapter motivates with illustrating use cases the need for novel testing approaches beyond purely functional behavior, in particular, as data foundations increasingly become a significant part of the system under test, beyond input and context parameters. The chapter discusses the role of data in testing systems and requirements for appropriate testing approaches for data-intensive software. The chapter provides a state-of-the-art survey on testing of data-intensive software. The chapter extends the testing dimensions of software systems based on the observation that data quality and systems of systems thinking become more relevant in data-intensive software systems.</p><p>In total, the collected challenges in the chapters of Part I can be categorized as follows:</p><p>• Challenges related to the increasing digitalization of CPS in general and C-CPS in special including challenges of data/model integration • Challenges related to the required guarantee of high-quality, consistent, and faultfree engineering information within and crossing involved engineering disciplines and lifecycle phases • Challenges related to information management within engineering networks like version and responsibility management • Challenges related to knowledge use and protection like variant management and run-time data application • Challenges related to the confidentiality of engineering information • Challenges related to the required business processes and their secure execution</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.5.2">Part II: Engineering Quality Improvement</head><p>Part II on Engineering Quality Improvement discusses processes, methods, models, and mechanisms for quality assurance, analysis, and improvement in the engineering of long-running technical systems with consideration of supporting sufficient IT security. Quality improvement aspects in production system families include more efficient testing, more efficient reuse, efficient refactoring, and efficient data/model exchange between work groups in multidisciplinary engineering. This part will point out target qualities that IT security should defend and methods and mechanisms that introduce new IT security risks.</p><p>First, Chaps. 7 and 8 discuss the engineering process improvement in general. Chapter 7 provides a method for product/ion-aware analysis of production system engineering (PSE) processes to reduce risks coming from the insufficient representation of knowledge on the product to be produced and on the planned production process during PSE and operation. Chapter 8 introduces a method for efficient Engineering Data Exchange in PSE to enable the frequent synchronization of parallel workgroups in production system engineering (PSE) to reduce the risk of diverging local data views and avoidable rework. Second, Chap. 9 considers how to improve testing of software-intensive systems. Chapter 9 focuses on the reuse of test artifacts in similar but different test environments. Finally, Chap. 10 discusses a method for comprehensive analysis of product variants in a family of production systems for collapsing redundant parts and identifying reusable parts in order to reduce the size of the system variants and to facilitate better quality assurance. Therefore, readers gain insights into a variety of approaches to improve engineering quality for addressing requirements raised in Part I of this book for making better informed decisions in the design and improvement of PSE processes. Further, Part II brings up security threats as input to the security methods addressed in Part III of this book.</p><p>Chapter 7: Product/ion-Aware Analysis of Multidisciplinary Systems Engineering Processes This chapter discusses use cases that show how insufficient explicit representation of knowledge on product and production process characteristics can raise risks in later PSE stages and operation. Reporting on a case study, the chapter discusses strengths and limitations of traditional business and engineering process analysis methods. Based on these findings, it introduces a product/ion-aware engineering process analysis (PPR EPA) method and the notation for a product/ionaware data processing map (PPR DPM) that enables advanced analyses of PPR knowledge needs and gaps. The chapter considers requirements for storing PPR knowledge as foundation for PPR knowledge retrieval during the PSE process. Finally, the chapter discusses security issues that PPR EPA can identify as input to a subsequent security analysis.</p><p>Chapter 8: Engineering Data Logistics for Agile Automation Systems Engineering This chapter motivates requirements of efficient Engineering Data Exchange (EDEx) as foundation for the frequent synchronization of parallel workgroups in production system engineering (PSE) to reduce the risk of diverging local data views, effort for rework, and unclear project progress assessment. The chapter introduces the illustrating use case round-trip engineering (RTE) and derives requirements for (a) a process for negotiating data elements requested by data consumers and matching to data elements coming from data providers; and (b) a data exchange method and mechanism for executing the agreed data exchanges between domain experts and their data sources and sinks. The chapter introduces the Engineering Data Exchange (EDEx) process facilitated by an EDEx information system (EDExIS). As there is no suitable out-of-the-box technology to link discipline-specific views on data, the chapter introduces a software architecture based on AutomationML data models that address these challenges. It reports on a case study to evaluate the data negotiation process and the data exchange software architecture with representative use cases from real-world engineering environments. Finally, the chapter discusses security issues that an EDExIS can help address and identifies new security threats as input to a subsequent security analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 9: Efficient and Flexible Test Automation in Production Systems</head><p>Engineering This chapter motivates the need for test automation in production system engineering (PSE) and discusses strengths and limitations of traditional testing approaches in PSE with illustrating use cases. The chapter focuses on the reuse 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>23</head><p>of testing artifacts in similar but different PSE environments. Based on the Behavior Driven Development (BDD) approach, the chapter introduces a BDD-to-test-code weaving approach that allows representing BDD concepts in a language-independent model for the efficient generation of test source code in different test frameworks. The chapter demonstrates the feasibility of the key capabilities of the BDD-to-test-code weaving approach based on a prototype and discusses practical application cases.</p><p>The chapter discusses security issues that reusing test automation constructs can help address. Further, the chapter identifies new security threats as input to a subsequent security analysis.</p><p>Chapter 10: Reengineering Variants of Matlab/Simulink Software Systems This chapter motivates the need for a comprehensive analysis of product variants in a family of production systems in order to identify the systems variability and their relations. It provides illustrative use cases that demonstrate the impact of variability on system quality and risk. The chapter introduces a technique to capture coursegrained variability as foundation for the identification of similar and redundant parts. By collapsing redundant parts and identifying reusable parts, the approach allows reducing the size of the system variants and facilitates better quality assurance. Based on knowledge about the relations between system variants from the portfolio analysis, affected software systems can be identified across variant boundaries, mitigating security concerns for the entire product portfolio. Finally, the chapter discusses security issues that the variant analysis of MATLAB/Simulink system portfolios can help address and identifies new security threats as input to a subsequent security analysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.5.3">Part III: Engineering Security Improvement</head><p>Part III on Engineering Security Improvement discusses novel methods to enhance the security of C-CPSs. More specifically, the methods proposed in this part will not only deal with the protection of the engineering process itself but also address security aspects that ought to be considered when designing these systems. Thus, the objective of this part of the book is twofold. First, Chap. 11 provides a security assessment of a data repository used to exchange engineering artifacts, followed by Chap. 12, which examines security concepts and technologies that may be leveraged to mitigate industrial espionage and the manipulation of engineering data. Second, Chap. 13 discusses the design and run-time aspects of secure C-CPSs, and thereby lays the foundation for subsequent chapters that touch on the security-by-design principle for C-CPSs. After that, Chap. 14 explains how the concept of digital twins can be used to improve the security of C-CPSs throughout their lifecycle, starting from the engineering to the operation phase. Furthermore, Chaps. 15 and 16 address security concerns that emerge due to the increasing connectivity of these systems. Finally, Chap. 17 provides valuable insights into Byzantine fault tolerance (BFT) and how safety-critical distributed systems can be designed to achieve this property. In this way, readers gain insights into security threats and adequate countermeasures concerning C-CPSs, allowing them to integrate profound scientific knowledge in their decision-making process during engineering activities.</p><p>Chapter 11: Security Analysis and Improvement of Data Logistics in AutomationML-Based Engineering Networks This chapter investigates the security flaws of the state of practice regarding the exchange of engineering data. Furthermore, it provides a systematic approach to designing secure central data repositories, specifically tailored to engineering environments. To ensure that threats pertaining to these central data repositories are adequately considered, the chapter demonstrates how threat modeling can be applied in the context of engineering data exchange. Based on this, the chapter proposes practical countermeasures that mitigate the identified threats while maintaining the efficiency of engineering workflows. Finally, the chapter provides an overview of counterexamples and mistakes to avoid, which further supports the risk treatment process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 12: Securing Information Against Manipulation in the Production</head><p>Systems Engineering Process This chapter discusses methods that aim to ensure the integrity of engineering data, and to identify leakages to unauthorized parties, which may also provide the means for holding them legally accountable for their malicious actions. The security concepts proposed in this chapter supplement Chap. 11, as protecting the data exchange does not prevent insiders (e.g., employees) or third parties that are involved in the engineering process (e.g., contractors) from manipulating or stealing engineering artifacts. In particular, the chapter covers concepts that provide proof of ownership, proof of correctness, and the ability to track leaked engineering data. In this way, readers develop a thorough understanding of methods that can be used to protect engineering knowledge against manipulation or theft.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 13: Design and Run-Time Aspects of Secure Cyber-Physical Systems</head><p>This chapter provides an introduction to the principle of security by design for CPSs and associated run-time aspects. Based on a discussion of the CPSs threat landscape, the chapter reviews methods for detecting and preventing attacks, which may be worth implementing when engineering these systems. The chapter then delves into the monitoring of run-time behavior of CPSs for security purposes. In particular, the authors discuss key aspects and requirements for implementing runtime security monitoring in CPSs based on existing work in this field. Owing to the use case presented, readers will be able to understand the concrete security challenges and issues that emerge in an industrial context. Finally, the chapter discusses the implications of the findings and suggests directions for further research in this area. 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>25</head><p>twins can be used to conduct security tests in the design, testing, and commissioning phases, while the replication of states to digital twins, so that they follow the states of their physical counterparts, may reveal intrusions. The chapter completes with an extensive analysis of challenges and open questions that are worth studying in future work.</p><p>Chapter 15: Radio Frequency Security in Industrial Engineering Processes This chapter addresses the need for securing wireless communication technologies of C-CPSs. First it outlines radio frequency technologies that are used in an industrial setting and then points out security shortcomings. Based on this analysis, practical countermeasures against the identified attack vectors are proposed. Due to the fact that security flaws that have its origins in the design are costly to fix, the chapter also shows how approaches to security testing can be applied in the engineering phase of wireless systems. As strategic initiatives, such as Industry 4.0, motivate the adoption of wireless technologies, an in-depth analysis of the security of radio frequency communication represents a valuable contribution to the book at hand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Chapter 16: Secure and Safe IIoT Systems via Machine and Deep Learning</head><p>Approaches This chapter reviews security and safety challenges for Internet of Things (IoT) applications in industrial environments. Similar to Chap. 15, this work addresses both the security and safety concerns emerging from connectivity capabilities, which have to be considered jointly during the engineering phase, as both influence each other. On the one hand, security concerns arise from the expanding attack surface of C-CPSs due to the increasing connectivity on all levels of the industrial automation pyramid. On the other hand, safety concerns magnify the consequences of traditional security attacks. Based on the thorough analysis of potential security and safety issues of Industrial IoT (IIoT) systems, the chapter surveys machine and deep learning (ML/DL) methods that can be applied to counter the security and safety threats that emerge in this context. In particular, the chapter explores how ML/DL methods can be leveraged in the engineering phase for designing more secure and safe IoT-enabled C-CPSs. However, the peculiarities of IoT environments (e.g., resource-constrained devices with limited memory, energy, and computational capabilities) still represent a barrier to the adoption of these methods. Thus, this chapter also discusses the limitations of ML/DL methods for IoT security and how they might be overcome in future work by pursuing the suggested research directions.</p><p>Chapter 17: Revisiting Practical Byzantine Fault Tolerance Through the Lens of Blockchains This chapter discusses how blockchain technologies have rekindled an interest in the topic of Byzantine fault tolerance (BFT) that reaches well beyond the hype behind cryptocurrencies. This topic is highly relevant for the engineering of safety-critical systems, especially if they constitute distributed systems. Being able to tolerate not just crash or omission failures, but potentially arbitrary and malicious (i.e., Byzantine) behavior of a subset of a system's components can greatly improve its resilience and security. The vast improvement in computing power, networking, and hardware costs over the last 20 years has greatly diminished the impact of the overhead that is incurred for achieving Byzantine fault tolerance (BFT) and it should no longer be perceived as impractical or infeasible for real-world applications. It is essential that safety-critical systems are engineered in a way that allows them to tolerate Byzantine failures, and Blockchain technologies introduce many new paradigms and techniques that can be seen as complementary to classical BFT approaches. This chapter examines how blockchain technologies relate to classical Byzantine fault tolerance and outlines which aspects need to be considered when making design decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.6">Who Shall Read This Book?</head><p>This book is intended for several target groups. Computer science researchers will be enabled to identify research issues related to the development of new methods, architectures, and technologies for quality and security improvements in multidisciplinary engineering, pushing forward the current state of the art.</p><p>Researchers on the engineering of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems will get a better understanding of the challenges and requirements of multidisciplinary engineering that will guide them in future research and development activities on quality and security improvements. Engineers and managers with engineering background will be able to get a better understanding of the benefits and limitations of applicable methods, architectures, and technologies for selected use cases. 1 Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</p><note type="other">29</note><p>Weippl, E., &amp; <ref type="bibr">Kieseberg, P. (2017)</ref>. Security in cyber-physical production systems: A roadmap to improving IT-security in the production system lifecycle. In AEIT international annual conference (pp. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr">[6]</ref>. IEEE. Whittle, J., <ref type="bibr">Hutchinson, J., &amp; Rouncefield, M. (2019)</ref>. Model-driven development -A practical approach. Abingdon: Routledge. Zanero, S. <ref type="bibr">(2017, April)</ref>. Cyber-physical systems. Computer, 50(4), <ref type="bibr">14-16. Zhu, Y.-M. (2016)</ref>. Software reading techniques: Twenty techniques for more effective software review and inspection. New York: Apress. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>1</head><label></label><figDesc>Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>3</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 1 . 1</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Fig. 1.1 Domain expert roles in the engineering of C-CPSs, typically long-running industrial production systems</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_18"><head>RQ3a:</head><label></label><figDesc>Which Security Concepts Mitigate Cyber Threats Targeting the Engineering Process of Complex Cyber-Physical Systems? This research question deals with the security challenges and requirements presented in the first part of Sect. 1.4.1.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_19"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . . 19</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_25"><head>Chapter 14 :</head><label>14</label><figDesc>Digital Twins for Cyber-Physical Systems Security-State of the Art and Outlook This chapter explores security-specific use cases of the concept of digital twins and provides suggestions on how they may be put into practice. The chapter aims to demonstrate that digital twins can holistically improve the security of CPSs by applying security measures in various phases of their lifecycle. In particular, the chapter shows that the simulation aspects of digital</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">t r a c k ers of t w a r e . c o m</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-. . .</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Acknowledgments</head><p>The financial support by the Christian Doppler Research Association, the Austrian Federal Ministry for Digital and Economic Affairs, and the National Foundation for Research, Technology, and Development is gratefully acknowledged.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automotive spice essentials: Automotive spice v3.1 -at a glance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Abowd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Hörmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Vanamali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Schnetzer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>Kugler Maag</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quality assurance in software ecosystems: A systematic literature mapping and research agenda</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jakob</forename><surname>Axelsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mats</forename><surname>Skoglund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jss.2015.12.020</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Systems and Software</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Journal of Systems and Software</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0164-1212</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="2016-04" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CMMI for development: Guidelines for process integration and product improvement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Beth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chrissis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Konrad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<publisher>Addison Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to the Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Biffl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Detlef</forename><surname>Gerhard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-56345-9_1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Biffl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-56345-9</idno>
		<editor>&amp; Gerhard, D.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cham</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Effective Model-Based Systems Engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Borky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Bradley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-95669-5</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cham</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Software Ecosystems -- Implications for Strategy, Business Model and Architecture</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Bosch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/splc.2011.10</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2011 15th International Software Product Line Conference</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Pittsburgh</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="119" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction to Security and Quality Improvement in Complex Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Biffl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edgar</forename><surname>Weippl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-25312-7_1</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Security and Quality in Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Model-Driven Software Engineering in Practice: Second Edition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marco</forename><surname>Brambilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jordi</forename><surname>Cabot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manuel</forename><surname>Wimmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2200/s00751ed2v01y201701swe004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Synthesis Lectures on Software Engineering</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Synthesis Lectures on Software Engineering</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">2328-3319</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2328-3327</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="207" />
			<date type="published" when="2017-03-30" />
			<publisher>Morgan &amp; Claypool Publishers LLC</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Out of the Crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Deming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7551/mitpress/11457.001.0001</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The new economics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Deming</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993" />
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dragos Tesisatçı &apos;444&quot;88&quot;48&apos; Tesisatçı Dragos</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Inc</forename><surname>Dragos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4016/45089.01</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dragos.com/media/2017-Review-Industrial-Control-Vulnerabilities.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-03-15" />
			<publisher>SciVee, Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hanover, MD</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Security-Aware Virtual Environments for Digital Twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Ekelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3198458.3198464</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical System Security</title>
				<meeting>the 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical System Security</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-05-22" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Specification-based State Replication Approach for Digital Twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Ekelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3264888.3264892</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security and PrivaCy</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 Workshop on Cyber-Physical Systems Security and PrivaCy</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-01-15" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="23" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methodology for consideration of product quality within factory automation engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Foehr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Jager</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Turrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Petrali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pagani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/icit.2013.6505866</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2013 IEEE International Conference on Industrial Technology (ICIT)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cape Town</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-02" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1333" to="1338" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planguage Basics and Process Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Gilb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lindsey</forename><surname>Brodie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/b978-075066507-0/50005-2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Competitive Engineering</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="34" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Engineering cyber-physical systems, within H. Fujita, A. Selamat, S. Omatu, new trends in intelligent software -Methodologies, tools, and techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gruhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Gries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Hesenius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ollesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Ur Rehmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Schwenzfeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Wahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Wessling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 16th SoMeT</title>
				<meeting>16th SoMeT<address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IOS Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Operational Technology and Information Technology in Industrial Control Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-32125-7_4</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Information Security</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="68" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Howard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lipner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The security development lifecycle</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Redmond</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Microsoft Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ISO 9000 Quality Systems Handbook-updated for the ISO 9001: 2015 standard</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hoyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4324/9781315642192</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Increasing the quality of an organization&apos;s outputs</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Abingdon</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Routledge</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017-07-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of a method for the implementation of interoperable tool chains applying mechatronical thinking &amp;#x2014; Use case engineering of logic control</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lorenz</forename><surname>Hundt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Luder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/etfa.2012.6489661</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 2012 IEEE 17th International Conference on Emerging Technologies &amp; Factory Automation (ETFA 2012)</title>
				<meeting>2012 IEEE 17th International Conference on Emerging Technologies &amp; Factory Automation (ETFA 2012)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-09" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">9000</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Emerging technologies &amp; factory automation (ETFA)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Systems and software engineering. Systems and software Quality Requirements and Evaluation (SQuaRE). Guide to SQuaRE</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3403/30289026</idno>
		<idno>ISO/IEC 25000:2014.</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date>2014</date>
			<publisher>BSI British Standards</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chancen von Industrie 4.0 nutzen</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Kagermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Helbig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hellinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>&amp;wahlster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-662-53254-6_12</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbuch Industrie 4.0 Bd.4</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Forschungsunion</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="248" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Final report of the Industrie 4.0 working group</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kaner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">Q</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Testing computer software</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Hoboken, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analytic Methods in Systems and Software Testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kenett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Ruggeri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Faltin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781119357056</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-07-26" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Security challenges in cyber-physical production systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kieseberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Weippl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International conference on software quality</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Software Quality Assurance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claude</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Laporte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alain</forename><surname>April</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781119312451</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-11-08" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber Physical Systems: Design Challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/isorc.2008.25</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2008 11th IEEE International Symposium on Object and Component-Oriented Real-Time Distributed Computing (ISORC)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="363" to="369" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Optimal Denial-of-Service Attack Policy against Wireless Industrial Control Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Assante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1201/b19629-9</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Cyber Security for Industrial Control Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-03-23" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Methodische Entwicklung technischer Produkte</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Udo</forename><surname>Lindemann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-642-01423-9</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009" />
			<publisher>Springer Berlin Heidelberg</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Berlin</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fundamentals of Artifact Reuse in CPPS</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicole</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristofer</forename><surname>Hell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hannes</forename><surname>Röpke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacek</forename><surname>Zawisza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-56345-9_5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identification of Artifacts in Life Cycle Phases of CPPS</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicole</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristofer</forename><surname>Hell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hannes</forename><surname>Röpke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacek</forename><surname>Zawisza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-56345-9_6</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="167" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Les migrations et leur impact</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gudrun</forename><surname>Biffl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">El</forename><forename type="middle">Mouhoub</forename><surname>Mouhoud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Zalc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3917/idee.189.0046</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Idées économiques et sociales</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">2257-5111</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">N° 189</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="54" />
			<date type="published" when="2017-10-03" />
			<publisher>CAIRN</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Description Means for Information Artifacts Throughout the Life Cycle of CPPS</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicole</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristofer</forename><surname>Hell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hannes</forename><surname>Röpke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacek</forename><surname>Zawisza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-56345-9_7</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="183" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automatisierungstechnik</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Lunze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1515/9783110465624</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-05-10" />
			<publisher>De Gruyter</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cybersecurity for Industrial Control Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tyson</forename><surname>Macaulay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bryan</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1201/b11352</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-04-19" />
			<publisher>Auerbach Publications</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Software security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mcgraw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/msecp.2004.1281254</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Security &amp; Privacy Magazine</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Secur. Privacy Mag.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1540-7993</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2004-03" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Mcgraw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Software security: Building security in</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Cybersecurity Landscape in Industrial Control Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Mclaughlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charalambos</forename><surname>Konstantinou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xueyang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lucas</forename><surname>Davi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ahmad-Reza</forename><surname>Sadeghi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michail</forename><surname>Maniatakos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ramesh</forename><surname>Karri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/jproc.2015.2512235</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the IEEE</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Proc. IEEE</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0018-9219</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1558-2256</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1039" to="1057" />
			<date type="published" when="2016-05" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber-physical Production Systems: Roots, Expectations and R&amp;D Challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">László</forename><surname>Monostori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.procir.2014.03.115</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Procedia CIRP</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Procedia CIRP</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">2212-8271</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="13" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Art of Software Testing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781119202486</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-01-02" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">PDCA process application in the continuous improvement of software quality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computer, mechatronics, control and electronic engineering (CMCE), 2010 international conference</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-08" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="65" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taxonomy of Wireless Sensor Network Cyber Security Attacks in the Oil and Gas Industries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pedram</forename><surname>Radmand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Talevski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stig</forename><surname>Petersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Carlsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/aina.2010.175</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2010 24th IEEE International Conference on Advanced Information Networking and Applications</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="949" to="957" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>24th IEEE international conference</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Requirements and concept for Plug-and-Work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miriam</forename><surname>Schleipen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arndt</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Olaf</forename><surname>Sauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Holger</forename><surname>Flatt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jürgen</forename><surname>Jasperneite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1515/auto-2015-0015</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">at - Automatisierungstechnik</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0178-2312</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2196-677X</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="801" to="820" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-01-28" />
			<publisher>Walter de Gruyter GmbH</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combined safety and security development lifecylce</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Schmittner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhendong</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erwin</forename><surname>Schoitsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/indin.2015.7281940</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2015 IEEE 13th International Conference on Industrial Informatics (INDIN)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1408" to="1415" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methoden der Automatisierung</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eckehard</forename><surname>Schnieder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-322-90879-7</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Methoden der Automatisierung</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Braunschweig</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Vieweg+Teubner Verlag</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lessons Learned from the Maroochy Water Breach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jill</forename><surname>Slay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-0-387-75462-8_6</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IFIP International Federation for Information Processing</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer US</publisher>
			<date>2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quality improvement methodologies-PDCA cycle, RADAR matrix, DMAIC and DFSS</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Sokovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Pavletic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Pipan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Achievements in Materials and Manufacturing Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="476" to="483" />
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guide to Industrial Control Systems (ICS) Security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Stouffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Pillitteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Lightman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marshall</forename><surname>Abrams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.6028/nist.sp.800-82r2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NIST Special Publication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">82</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">800</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06" />
			<publisher>National Institute of Standards and Technology</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Guide to Industrial Control Systems (ICS) Security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Stouffer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Pillitteri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Lightman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marshall</forename><surname>Abrams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Hahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.6028/nist.sp.800-82r2</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.6028/NIST.SP.800-82r2" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-06" />
			<publisher>National Institute of Standards and Technology</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Engineering Workflow and Software Tool Chains of Automated Production Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anton</forename><surname>Strahilov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Holger</forename><surname>Hämmerle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-56345-9_9</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Multi-Disciplinary Engineering for Cyber-Physical Production Systems</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Biffl</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lüder</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">&amp;</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gerhard</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="234" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Engineering workflow and software tool chains of automated production systems</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Software Quality Engineering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Tian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/0471722324</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-01-27" />
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Secure cyber-physical production systems: Solid steps towards realization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johanna</forename><surname>Ullrich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Artemios</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Voyiatzis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edgar</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Weippl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/cpps.2016.7483921</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2016 1st International Workshop on Cyber-Physical Production Systems (CPPS)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-04" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1st international workshop</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Regelung von RLT-Anlagen – Richtlinie VDI 3525: Regelung und Steuerung Raumlufttechnischer Anlagen; Beispiele</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/bapi.200790022</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bauphysik</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Bauphysik</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0171-5445</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1437-0980</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="2007-04" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Richtlinie VDI 2537: „Obeflächenschutz mit Bahnen aus natürlichem und synthetischem Kautschuk”. Die VDI-Richtlinien erscheinen im VDI-Verlag GmbH., 4 Düsseldorf 1, Postfach 1139, und werden über den Beuth-Vertrieb GmbH.,1 Berlin 30, Burggrafenstraße 417, zum Preis von 5,20 DM ausgeliefert</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vereindeutscheringenieure</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/maco.19670181018</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Materials and Corrosion/Werkstoffe und Korrosion</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Materials and Corrosion</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0947-5117</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1521-4176</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="957" to="957" />
			<date type="published" when="1967-10" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cost-optimisation of analytical software quality assurance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
			<pubPlace>Munich</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Technical University Munich</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
