<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">A Digital Twins Approach to Smart Grid Security Testing and Standardization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright IEEE</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2020-06">2020-06</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Manolya</forename><surname>Atalay</surname></persName>
							<email>manolya@ceng.metu.edu.tr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Computer Engineering Middle East Technical University Ankara</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Pelin</forename><surname>Angin</surname></persName>
							<email>pangin@ceng.metu.edu.tr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Engineering Middle</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">East Technical University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ankara</settlement>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">A Digital Twins Approach to Smart Grid Security Testing and Standardization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">2020 IEEE International Workshop on Metrology for Industry 4.0 &amp; IoT</title>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
							<date type="published" when="2020-06" />
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1109/metroind4.0iot48571.2020.9138264</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:16+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Smart Grid</term>
					<term>IoT</term>
					<term>Cybersecurity</term>
					<term>Digital Twins</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The exponential growth of the Internet of Things in recent years has created an ever larger cyber attack surface, introducing new security vulnerabilities for all computerized systems. Among the most significant of those systems are industrial control systems (ICS) consisting of many cyber physical components, and smart grids are a prominent example of ICS, whose failures have potential to cause major disruptions in all aspects of our daily lives. In this paper, we provide an overview of smart grid cybersecurity standards, and review major threats to smart grid environments at the physical, network and application layers. In order to overcome the current lack of standards for security evaluation of smart grids, we propose a digital twins based approach for the complete lifecycle of a smart grid, which accurately models the functioning of the physical grid and avoids service disruptions caused by running security tests on the actual grid. A digital twins based approach is promising to provide a common ground for the development of standardized models for continuous and comprehensive penetration testing of smart grids.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>Cyber physical systems (CPS) have become completely integrated into our lives <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> with the rise of the Internet of Things (IoT) paradigm in the past decade. Energy distribution systems are a class of CPS, which are crucial parts of critical infrastructures. Current industry standards for energy distribution networks are moving towards the integration of smart meters and appliances under the smart grid concept, as traditional power grid technologies are not sufficient to meet energy demands. These systems require continuous monitoring, efficient usage of power, fewer power outages and fast recovery, among many other requirements.</p><p>Cyber attacks against smart energy grids are capable of causing major disruptions in energy transmission, as in the incidents of the US electrical grid being hacked by attackers in 2009 <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>, installing a backdoor to cut electricity at will, and the attack that took down Ukraine's power grid in 2015 <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, causing more than 200,000 consumers to lose power. It is difficult to measure/evaluate the security of a smart grid due to the number of interconnected devices supplied by different vendors, which communicate using a variety of protocols. Generic penetration testing tools are incompetent for this task, as they are generally designed for smaller and more homogeneous networks. This creates the need for a separate framework to evaluate the security of smart grids, which considers the nature of the interconnected devices.</p><p>Despite the global prevalence of smart grids in energy distribution networks, standards for their security testing are still not in place. In an effort to close this gap, this paper proposes a digital twins based security testing framework for smart grids, which is promising to both provide accurate modeling of a smart grid for realistic security evaluation and take a step forward in creating a common ground for security testing standardization for smart grids.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. SMART GRID SECURITY STANDARDS</head><p>A smart (power) grid is the deployment of an electricity transmission and distribution infrastructure that differs from traditional electrical grids with the use of smart meters and appliances, high-level monitoring tools, energy generators within a network, etc. In 2010, the US National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) released the 7628 <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> report to provide guidelines for smart grid cybersecurity. As of today, smart grid infrastructures have become exceedingly complex and advanced with the integration of IoT components. However, their security implementations still require more refined solutions based on the NIST 7628 report. Leszczyna <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> recently presented a survey of smart grid security standards over publications from various organizations including NIST, IEEE, NERC (North American Electric Reliability Corporation), NRG (US integrated power company), IEC (International Electrotechnical Commission) and ISO (International Organization for Standardization). The standards can be categorized as those that provide general non-technical guidance, those that provide general application security standards not specific to smart grids, but which can be utilized for risk assessment, and security standards more specific to smart grids and ICS. A summary of the existing security standards based on this categorization are given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">I</ref>.</p><p>Despite the presence of various standards for the implementation of security mechanisms in smart grids and ICS as listed above, Leszczyna concludes that standards for the security evaluation/measurement of smart grids do not yet exist.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. CYBERSECURITY OF SMART GRID INFRASTRUCTURES</head><p>Smart grid infrastructures are mainly composed of physical, communication, and application layers. The physical layer encompasses devices such as smart meters, smart appliances, electric vehicles, SCADAs, sensors, data generation components, etc. The communication layer deals with communication protocols, the interconnection of network components, network mediums, and data concentrators. The application layer manages the smart grid infrastructure, where the management system consists of servers regarding development, deployment, front-end, network management systems, business intelligence, routers, firewalls, etc.</p><p>Recent years have witnessed several cyber attacks directly on smart power systems, the most prominent ones being the Stuxnet worm between 2005 and 2010 <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and the Ukrainian power grid attack in 2015 <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Recent DDoS attacks have also been exploiting the vulnerabilities of power grid systems due to their heterogeneous nature.</p><p>Since smart grid systems are parts of critical infrastructures, they need to provide high degrees of reliability, availability and privacy. The highly heterogeneous nature of smart grid infrastructures make it important to comprehensively account for possible vulnerabilities against the system components and measure the criticality levels of these vulnerabilities. According to the nature and criticality of the vulnerabilities, appropriate countermeasures may be taken.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Common Smart Grid Vulnerabilities</head><p>Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> demonstrates categories of possible threats on a smart grid infrastructure. One of the most common threats is Denial of Service (DoS) attacks and its variants. A DoS attacker can simply send a flood of messages in order to impair the smart grid system and drain its resources. The adversaries may try to overload the memory, drain energy, and reduce the lifespan of the components. There is also the case where the adversaries deliberately send a flood of misleading messages. These types of attacks can bypass the anomaly detection systems by staying in the system for a period of time as a legitimate entity to gain reputation as in advanced persistent threats (APTs).</p><p>Heterogeneous systems are prone to have weaknesses that go unnoticed during deployment. However, a malicious attacker will most likely try exploiting this weakness at some point. There are cases when avoidance is not possible or practical. The countermeasure in such cases is either to make the attempt ineffective or recover from the failure.</p><p>Smart grid system components mainly sit in an unreliable channel and they communicate through a wireless network. Moreover, they will have access to the Internet. One of the worst-case scenarios is that the communicating components may not implement secure communication protocols when they work with different systems. This is mainly due to the fact that legacy systems do not implement well-structured and secure communication protocols. Many of the systems require outsourced operations, collections of data outside the network, send out temporal information, etc. The security must be orchestrated strictly in this case. Lastly, it is not sufficient to analyze each risk independently. There are many combinations of attacks, where an attacker may use one method to weaken the system and another to gain access to the system or to critical information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. DIGITAL TWINS</head><p>Digital Twins is a term coined in the early 1990s. However, with the recent Industry 4.0 standards, and the integration of IoT into our lives, digital twins has become a term more commonly used within the context of CPS, overriding its past connotations. At a high level, a digital twin can be defined as a virtual replica of an object from the physical world <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The environment that maintains a digital twin requires a standard structure, end-to-end connectivity, a communication protocol with backward compatibility, and a standardized data format with which the virtual replica can communicate with the real world object or system.</p><p>Grieves and Vickers define a digital twins system with the concepts of twin, prototype, instance, and environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Twin is the virtual construction of the actual subject that is aimed to fully represent the subject. The prototype is the description that contains sufficient information to reproduce the twin. The instance is the subject itself. The environment is what communicates with the twin. Overall, a digital twin exactly mimics the behavior of its related physical entity, as the physical entity experiences state changes in response to various inputs in the real world. While there are different models for digital twins, the most generic model includes data flows between the actual environment in which the physical object operates and the digital replica, where the digital replica may influence the behavior of the physical object through a feedback mechanism. A digital twin can both provide and undermine security based on its deployment. Hence, the definition of security in a digital twin is crucial <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. A typical CPS structure requires continuous monitoring of physical processes. It is a dynamic and selfconfiguring environment. In terms of security, it cannot depend on existing knowledge for long periods of time. The behaviorbased security analysis of a CPS is important <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>In Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> we demonstrate how to apply the concept of digital twins to the design of a smart grid environment based on CPS. Here, the Decision Making Control Center is a central unit that includes a human-machine interface. The digital twin here can also act as an operator as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. The Decision Making Control Center sends information and commands through automation devices to the Master Terminal. The Master Terminal unit communicates with the physical environment including sensors (e.g. smart meters) and actuators (e.g. display devices, breakers, etc) through network monitoring and gateway units, and relays inputs from the physical environment to the digital twin. Based on the processing of the data received from the physical environment and the behavior modelled in the digital twin, the decision-making center can take decisions that influence the actions of the corresponding objects, communicated back through the Master Terminal.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>V. IMPLEMENTATION OF DIGITAL TWINS FOR SMART GRIDS</head><p>In this section, we provide an overview of the implementation of our proposed digital twin structure for a smart grid. At a high level, an industrial IoT (IIoT) system requires resources capable of providing online storage units, operating interconnected networks, balancing the computational load on the system, and analysis tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. The digital twins concept separates a system into three tiers, namely the physical, virtual, and decision-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13]</ref> layers. The physical tier consists of computing, storage, terminal, perception, and networking resources. Here, the selection of appropriate hardware allows wide scaling through modularity, parallelization, adjustable processing and storage units, and secure communication. The virtual tier includes libraries for models, environment states, and optimization parameters. These libraries keep the physical and logical profiles of the system components, as well as information about the network state and optimization parameters that are tuned in the course of the simulation and evaluation phases of the network. Finally, the decision-making tier is composed of algorithms mapping the physical tiers to the virtual tiers, optimizing monitored data to improve the health of the system, and raising alarms during anomalous situations. Additionally, this tier manages the communication topology in a way to commence or terminate message exchanges and schedules the internal processes. In the following sections, we elaborate on each tier's roles in the implementation of a smart grid digital twin.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Physical Tier</head><p>Our system proposes a private cloud architecture for smart grids. A bi-directional communication platform for real-time continuous data management with high availability is essential. According to <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[14]</ref>, cloud platforms support demand and supply balancing through the integration of existing energy management systems (EMSs) such as home energy management (HEM), demand-side management (DSM), and building energy management (BEMS). Cloud computing is widely known for its provisioning of scalability, flexibility, dynamicity, measured nature, and stable Internet connectivity.</p><p>The proposed system includes micro-grid structures, which are called cloudlets <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[15]</ref>. Cloudlet is a term coined to standard-ize edge-computing systems for small-scale IoT environments with devices in close physical or logical proximity to process data more efficiently. There are mainly two advantages to this construction, including decentralization of edge device management and analysis of devices in their own microecosystem. In our smart grid digital twin, cloudlets allow us to scale-down some processes for specific locations. From the decision-making tier's point of view, the deployment of cloudlets provides a standard abstraction for outsourced services. Therefore, to preserve the modularity of each microecosystem, the cloudlets are required to be private. Despite the fact that a private cloud introduces additional complexity for the system, it provides enhanced control over the decisionmaking mechanism.</p><p>The cloudlets are composed of smart meter devices, controller units, storage units, and analytics applications for network management and monitoring. They are small-scale wireless sensor networks. The smart meters are commonly deployed in advanced metering infrastructure (AMI) systems. AMI systems are the gold standard in smart-grid technology for communication and data collection <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[16]</ref>. The smart meters supply data such as energy values, timestamps, and geolocation. One of the most commonly used communication protocols in IIoT systems is Message Queuing Telemetry Transport (MQTT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[17]</ref>. MQTT is based on a publishsubscribe model, which allows the information consumer to only accept information that is useful from the supplier. In the smart grid scenario, the publishers are smart metering devices and the subscribers can be controller units. MQTT brokers act as intermediate devices to collect information as subscribers, and propagate the required metered information to monitoring units <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. One of the main advantages of an MQTT-based implementation is the small size of data transferred. However, the conversion between TCP/IP communication and MQTT can result in an overhead when the cloudlets have many devices attached to the analytics unit.</p><p>Monitoring units supply the information our digital twin system requires for optimization to determine the regulatory information over the specific micro-ecosystems and devices. The decision-making control center consumes nodal and general cloudlet information. Nodal information creates digital twin profiles for all devices in the smart grid system. Overall, cloudlet information contributes to the knowledge models. The fluctuations for separate scenarios dependent on location and time can be used as optimization parameters.</p><p>Gateway units provide private networks for each cloudlet and implement additional privacy properties. The TCP communication can be secured using Efficient Large-Group Key Distribution (ELK) <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[17]</ref>. Finally, the master terminals are equipped with programmable logic controller (PLC) based automation units. There are efficient gateways for IIoT implementations with serial communication protocols such as Modbus and S7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Virtual Tier</head><p>The virtual tier is a fundamental feature of the digital twins concept. Here, the profiles and the system parameters of devices are organized in the form of libraries. The information about metering devices and gateways is static, since they require authorization for installation, update, and removal. Physical information regarding the devices such as identifiers, model, version, storage, input and output size, and location are kept as physical models. On the other hand, the devices have logical profiles in the system, such as their mapping in the virtual machine, the RAM size, the bandwidth, image size, processing power, etc.</p><p>A dynamic knowledge database is required in the system, which keeps the logs of monitoring data to model the behavior of a cloudlet. This knowledge database is frequently updated and represents the profile of the ecosystem the cloudlet resides in. The database can be organized to store the energy trend information for different times and tasks.</p><p>Finally, it is important to create a profile for the simulation and optimization environment. The simulation environment employs several algorithms in order to make decisions for the health of the running system. These algorithms have dynamic parameters for better assessment. The intrusion detection system includes several machine learning algorithms for the classification of abnormal behavior in the smart grid. Machine learning algorithms have parameters such as learning rates, weights, etc. These parameters are tuned during the lifecycle of the system. Moreover, continuous optimization for computation systems is required. These optimizations include load balancing, cloudlet power management, and task scheduling. These operations are carried out by separate algorithms with a variety of parameters.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Decision-Making Tier</head><p>The decision-making tier maps the physical tier to the virtual tier. In our framework, it is shown as the Decision-Making Control Center, which remotely operates other functional entities such as cloudlets, IoT gateways, PLC units, and tools for simulation and optimization. The authorization for installation, updates, and removal is commenced from this center. During installation, it identifies the new entities and creates instances of physical and logical models in the library. The logical models can also be viewed as behavioral models that are initialized with information from previous running instances in a similar environment. If the environment is new, the models are based on similar devices. However, if the device is a foreign system and implemented with legitimate authority, the logical model is initialized with manual input. Manual inputs can be taken with correct authorization at any time through a human-machine interface (HMI) that is established on the decision-making control center.</p><p>In the case of a new cloudlet introduced to the system, the decision-making tier defines an instance in the knowledge database dedicated to it. The initiation of a cloudlet starts when a monitoring and gateway controller unit is defined with its identifier. Then, it is necessary to define the details for the new environment such as required communication protocols, storage, properties of a dedicated file system, etc. Despite the fact that there will be multiple identical cloudlets at different locations, every cloudlet is defined as a separate network. This allows us to trace the root of failures and warnings and avoid a single point of failure. The system is built to scale and manage several cloudlets in parallel, yet local decisions are made according to contextual factors. Consequently, we can evaluate the devices in different environments at an equivalent level.</p><p>Every micro-grid system has its simulation, prediction, and decision policies and parameters. In the decision-making control center, many cloudlets might be required to run in parallel. However, the same algorithm is applied with different parameters acquired from the knowledge database. For instance, a change in energy consumption trend may raise an alarm in a cloudlet due to a routine task scheduled, which requires less deviation in the trend at that time. However, it may not raise an alarm on the next site with an identical cloudlet due to a large number of processes taking place.</p><p>Here, some of the main issues are the analysis of the temporal data, correlation of different components of the systems according to the tasks and location, real-time data acquisition, and asynchronous operations with high rates of transmitted data that are not affected by slower computation rates. The only issue regarding the computation rates is not decisionmaking systems. While the decision-making systems can have sufficient time tolerance, the data pre-processing operation is crucial. The data need to be structured, i.e. raw data are not suitable for processing. Unnecessary incoming data should be cleaned and the resulting data should be clustered.</p><p>During the monitoring analysis phase, despite having highlevel tools for monitoring, there are application-specific operations such as finding patterns in the incoming data, classification of the patterns, and defining the outliers. The patterns, hierarchies of patterns, and outliers specific to the cloudlets must be stored in the knowledge database. In the simulation and optimization phase, we can extract new features and continuously optimize the decision-making operations.</p><p>The digital twin concept aims to create a physical and logical profile of each entity that is running in the system. By keeping the presence of every actor in the system and mapping their behaviors during decision-making we will be able to have a fair and healthy framework.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VI. PROPOSED SECURITY EVALUATION APPROACH</head><p>Our proposed security evaluation framework for a smart grid builds a digital twin structure for the grid to be tested and follows standardized testing guidelines for potential vulnerabilities the grid might face, updated continuously with cyberthreat intelligence on smart grids. The framework consists of the following main elements:</p><p>• An extensible/modifiable digital twin representation for the smart grid</p><p>• A cyber-threat intelligence database for grid-specific attacks, as well as common attacks on the application and network layers</p><p>• Attack simulation toolset, which includes implementations of the attacks in the threat intelligence database</p><p>• A data analysis and reporting module that makes vulnerability inferences and risk assessment based on the results of attack simulations performed on the digital twin The security evaluation process in the proposed framework starts with the construction of the digital twin for the smart grid, either from scratch or through modification of a digital twin model for an existing grid structure. The digital twin can be built semi-automatically from the formal specification of the cyber physical system as proposed by Eckhart and Ekelhart <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, if such specification exists. In the case of missing a formal system specification, the framework should provide means for defining characteristics of common physical smart grid elements, which can be reused in multiple models, as well as an interface to define their runtime behavior.</p><p>Smart grids are very complex networks consisting of many cyber physical elements interconnected in various ways, which makes it costly to build an exact digital twin of the grid. As discussed by Bitton et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[18]</ref>, it is important to derive costeffective digital twins of industrial control systems (ICS) to facilitate comprehensive security evaluation both before and after real-world deployment. One property of smart grids is that they contain many repeating elements, such as smart meters of the same model, across the whole network. The fact that we expect to observe the same behavior in multiple instances of the same physical device facilitates the building of the digital twin for security testing by obviating the need to repeat digital models of these elements. Based on this observation, the evaluation framework separates the modeling process into two phases: (1) identification of major cyber physical elements in the grid and their interactions to build the digital twin model (2) building the complete network model in the virtual world through a network simulation. This separation will both facilitate the model-building process in terms of time costs and decrease the overall monetary cost of the digital twin model to be built. Note that while a partial digital twin model as suggested here will satisfy the needs of security evaluation, it may not be able to meet the requirements of providing smart grid security through intrusion detection systems that need to collect data from all physical devices in the network.</p><p>One requirement for the design of a digital twins based security evaluation/measurement framework that deserves particular attention is the ease of introducing changes into the model (1) to enable it to serve as a blueprint for other smart grid models (2) to swiftly integrate architecture/physical device changes in the grid as a result of technology upgrades and/or discovered security vulnerabilities. It is important to note that the security evaluation of the grid will be continuous due to new threats arising, and will not end with the deployment of the grid. Therefore, keeping the digital twin model up-to-date with the changes in the structure of the grid and the attack vectors up-to-date with the latest threats are vital.</p><p>The security evaluation lifecycle of the proposed framework can be summarized as follows:</p><p>1) A digital twin model of the main cyber physical elements in the smart grid are built from formal specifications, manually or by reusing elements from existing digital twin models.</p><p>2) The network model for the smart grid is built, where interactions between the main physical elements are encoded into the digital twin model and the broad network structure is simulated in software. 3) Attack vectors obtained from the central cyber threat intelligence database are implemented to simulate attacks on the smart grid model. 4) Results of the simulated attacks are analyzed and reported. 5) Vulnerabilities discovered during the attack simulation process introduce changes to the smart grid's design, which are reflected in the digital twin model. 6) The cyber threat intelligence database is kept up-to-date with the latest threats communicated through various resources. New attacks being added to the database generate alerts for customized implementation of the attacks for the smart grid being monitored and the attack simulation process is repeated. Utilizing a model-based approach, the framework takes a major step towards standardization of smart grid security evaluation by:</p><p>1) Introducing common cyber physical elements that could be shared across different smart grid platforms along with their digital behavioral representations.</p><p>2) Creating a central cyber threat intelligence database that includes smart grid specific attacks, which can serve as a checklist for the evaluation of different smart grids. 3) Achieving continuity of security evaluation with models updated with the latest attack vectors. The use of digital twins provides the advantage of accurate modeling of the cyber physical objects, whose behavior may not be captured with a purely simulation-based approach. It also provides the ability to run realistic attacks outside the real-world infrastructure, which could cause major service disruptions and infrastructure damage if run on the actual grid.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>VII. CONCLUSION</head><p>In this work, we reviewed existing standards for smart grid security and common attacks on the different layers of a smart grid infrastructure. A comprehensive analysis of existing standards demonstrates that while there are standards proposed by different organizations for the implementations of security mechanisms in smart grids and other ICSs, there is a lack of standards for comprehensive security assessment of smart grids, which is a critical shortcoming. We proposed a digital twins based approach for the security testing lifecycle of smart grids, which is promising to become an important tool for standardization. Our ongoing work includes the modeling and implementation of the proposed security evaluation framework for real-world smart grid infrastructures.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Fig. 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Fig. 1. Categories of Threats in a Smart Grid Environment</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. CPS-based Digital Twins Concepts Adapted to Smart Grid Systems</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>TABLE I SMART</head><label>I</label><figDesc>GRID SECURITY STANDARDS.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Domain General risk assessment NIST SP 800-53, ISO/IEC 15408 Standards ISO/IEC 18045, ISO/IEC 27005, NIST SP 800-39, NIST SP 800-64, NIST SP 800-115 Smart grid/ICS security IEC 62443, NRC RG 5.71, NERC CIP, IEEE 2030, IEEE C37.240, IEC 62351, ISO/IEC 27019, ISO 15118, RFC 6272, IEEE 1686 Non-technical guidance NISTIR 7628 (smart grid), NIST SP 800-82, DHS Catalog (ICS) IEEE 1402 (physical security)</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Authorized licensed use limited to: Uppsala Universitetsbibliotek. Downloaded on July 21,2020 at 03:37:00 UTC from IEEE Xplore. Restrictions apply.</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">New Edition of CSS&apos;s &quot;The Impact of Control Technology&quot; Report [Publication Activities]</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Baheti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Gill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/mcs.2012.2234933</idno>
		<ptr target="http://ieeecss.org/impact-control-technology-1st-edition" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Control Systems</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Control Syst.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1066-033X</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1941-000X</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-04" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep. The Impact of Control Technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Requirements for Smart Grid ICT-architectures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Rohjans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Danekas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mathias</forename><surname>Uslar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/isgteurope.2012.6465617</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.enisa.europa.eu/activities/Resilience-and-CIIP/critical-infrastructure-and-services/smart-grids-and-smart-metering/ict-inderdependencies-of-the-smart-grid/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2012 3rd IEEE PES Innovative Smart Grid Technologies Europe (ISGT Europe)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
	<note>ENISA</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of the cyber attack on the ukrainian power grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Assante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Conway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://ics.sans.org/media/E-ISACSANSUkraineDUC5.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SANS Inst</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-03" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guidelines for smart grid cyber security</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.6028/nist.ir.7628</idno>
		<ptr target="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/ir/2010/NIST.IR.7628.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Guidelines for smart grid cyber security</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>National Institute of Standards and Technology</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010-08" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>NIST</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Standards on cyber security assessment of smart grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rafał</forename><surname>Leszczyna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijcip.2018.05.006</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1874548216301421" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Critical Infrastructure Protection</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">International Journal of Critical Infrastructure Protection</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1874-5482</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="89" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-09" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stuxnet worm impact on industrial cyber-physical system security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stamatis</forename><surname>Karnouskos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/iecon.2011.6120048</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IECON 2011 - 37th Annual Conference of the IEEE Industrial Electronics Society</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011-11" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4490" to="4494" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Digital Twins for Cyber-Physical Systems Security: State of the Art and Outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ekelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">org/10.1007/978-3-030-25312-714</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Undesirable Emergent Behavior in Complex Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Grieves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Vickers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-38756-74</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-38756-74" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Digital Twin: Mitigating Unpredictable</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="113" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Security-Aware Virtual Environments for Digital Twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Ekelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3198458.3198464</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3198458.3198464" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical System Security</title>
				<meeting>the 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical System Security<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-05-22" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Analysis of Intrusion Detection Systems in Industrial Ecosystems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Juan</forename><forename type="middle">Enrique</forename><surname>Rubio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Alcaraz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><surname>Roman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Javier</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5220/0006426301160128</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 14th International Joint Conference on e-Business and Telecommunications</title>
				<meeting>the 14th International Joint Conference on e-Business and Telecommunications</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>SCITEPRESS - Science and Technology Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">National Aeronautics and Space Administration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Shafto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Conroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Doyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Glaessgen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Kemp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lemoigne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/springerreference_222298</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">National Aeronautics and Space Administration</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer-Verlag</publisher>
			<date>2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cloud connectivity for the factory floor: The necessary steps and considerations for implementation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Siemens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Tech. Rep.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">https://kujss.iraqjournals.com/pdf_166170_8dd024058ce4abb6c364bec514cecef8.html</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Available</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.32894/kujss.2019.15.2.1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://new.siemens.com/global/en/products/automation/industrial-communication/cloudconnect.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Kirkuk University Journal-Scientific Studies</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">KUJSS</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1992-0849</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2616-6801</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-06-30" />
			<publisher>Kirkuk University</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twin—The Simulation Aspect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Boschert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><surname>Rosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-32156-1_5</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Mechatronic Futures</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="74" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-32156-15</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cloud Computing Applications for Smart Grid: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samaresh</forename><surname>Bera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sudip</forename><surname>Misra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><forename type="middle">J P C</forename><surname>Rodrigues</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/tpds.2014.2321378</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Trans. Parallel Distrib. Syst.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1045-9219</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1477" to="1494" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-05-01" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Role of Cloudlets in Hostile Environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mahadev</forename><surname>Satyanarayanan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Grace</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edwin</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Soumya</forename><surname>Simanta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeff</forename><surname>Boleng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kiryong</forename><surname>Ha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/mprv.2013.77</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Pervasive Computing</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Pervasive Comput.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1536-1268</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="40" to="49" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-10" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey on advanced metering infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Mohassel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Mohammadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Raahemifar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0142061514003743" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Electrical Power Energy Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="484" />
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MQTT-S &amp;#x2014; A publish/subscribe protocol for Wireless Sensor Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Urs</forename><surname>Hunkeler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hong</forename><forename type="middle">Linh</forename><surname>Truong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andy</forename><surname>Stanford-Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/comswa.2008.4554519</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2008 3rd International Conference on Communication Systems Software and Middleware and Workshops (COMSWARE &apos;08)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="791" to="798" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deriving a Cost-Effective Digital Twin of an ICS to Facilitate Security Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Bitton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tomer</forename><surname>Gluck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Orly</forename><surname>Stan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Masaki</forename><surname>Inokuchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoshinobu</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoshiyuki</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tomohiko</forename><surname>Yagyu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuval</forename><surname>Elovici</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asaf</forename><surname>Shabtai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-99073-6_26</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computer Security</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Computer</forename><surname>Security</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Soriano</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="533" to="554" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
