<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">The Digital Twin Revolution in Healthcare</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright IEEE</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2020-10-22">2020-10-22</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Tolga</forename><surname>Erol</surname></persName>
							<email>terol@havelsan.com.tr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Training and Simulation Technologies</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">HAVELSAN A.Ş. Ankara</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Arif</forename><forename type="middle">Furkan</forename><surname>Mendi</surname></persName>
							<email>afmendi@havelsan.com.tr</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Training and Simulation Technologies HAVELSAN A.Ş. Ankara</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="TR">Turkey</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Dilara</forename><surname>Dogan</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">The Digital Twin Revolution in Healthcare</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">2020 4th International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies and Innovative Technologies (ISMSIT)</title>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
							<date type="published" when="2020-10-22" />
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ismsit50672.2020.9255249</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:35+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Digital Twin</term>
					<term>Digital Transformation</term>
					<term>Healthcare</term>
					<term>Industry 4.0</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Digital Twin technology entered our lives in the fields of production and engineering at the beginning with Industry 4.0, and it has also shown itself with studies that can be evaluated as revolutionary in the field of health. The Digital Twin is a digital replica that allows modeling the state of a physical asset or system. In the healthcare field, serious steps have been taken in creating Digital Twins of patients as well as Digital Twins of medical devices. The Digital Twin of the patient is created as a result of transferring the patient's physical characteristics and changes in the body to the digital environment. This technology offers innovative and definitive solutions for correct diagnosis and following the treatment processes suitable for the patient, which is one of the most important principles of medicine. At the same time, the use of technology is seen in studies in the personalized medicine and pharmaceutical industry. In this study, considering the impressive potential of the Digital Twin technology in the field of health, qualified studies that will guide future studies are emphasized.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>With the COVID-19 pandemic process, the importance of human health and health services has increased. In addition to this, it has come to the fore to ensure that working lives are sustainable from a distance and digitally. Governments and organizations have carried out various studies on digitalization and plans/arrangements continue. The health sector has been the most needed and demanding sector among the pandemic process. At the same time, in various fields, there have been situations such as digitalizing systems so that business processes can be managed remotely, and product/system development processes are accelerated. Meeting these demands is possible with Digital Twin technology. Studies are carried out for both the health sector and the digitalization field. In the "Hype Cycle for Healthcare Providers, 2020" report of Gartner, one of the leading research organizations in the world, it is stated that the subject of "Digital Twins in Healthcare" is on the rise and the interest in technology is gradually increasing <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Digital Twin technology, which is expected to increase in both the number and diversity of healthcare activities, offers promising revolutionary solutions.</p><p>The Digital Twin is a digital copy obtained by modeling the state of a physical system, collecting data through sensors placed on these systems, and reflecting this data into digital media. Digital Twins build a bridge between the physical and digital world by enabling us to understand the past and present processes and make predictions for the future. Known for its various studies in the field of engineering, this technology has many applications in various branches in the field of health. Similar to the engineering approach, it can also be applied to the healthcare field. Predictive maintenance services involved in engineering, early failure predictions; In the field of health, it refers to concepts such as predicting and early diagnosis of diseases that may occur by examining organs or symptoms in the body. In the case of atherosclerosis in the health field, performing a vascular bypass operation to restore blood flow, replacing the eye lens of cataract patients with a new lens, and organ transplantations can actually be defined as engineering activities in the health field <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>. An Example of Digital Human Body and Data <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> Errors that may occur in medical devices, incorrect detection of medical findings, and misinterpretation of the findings can lead to misdiagnosis, wrong diagnoses to wrong treatments, and wrong treatments that may result in negativity. For this reason, it is very important to anticipate and prevent errors. As a result of misdiagnosis and treatment, the patient's vital functions may deteriorate, leading to irreversible consequences in his life, and even the patient may lose his life. For example, if the leg muscle infarction is not diagnosed at the right time, or if it is misdiagnosed and treated, it can cause muscle death in the leg and cause irreversible damage to the leg, resulting in amputation or permanent disability. Digital Twin technology will also help in early and accurate diagnosis of cancer diseases. Cancer treatments are very difficult and risky processes for patients, patient relatives, and doctors. In critical diseases, a group of different patients with the same disease may respond positively to a certain treatment method, but not another group. With this situation, Hippocrates' "There is no disease, there is a patient." <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> when we consider the aphorism, the importance of personalized medicine is understood. When we examine personalized medicine, we can talk about personalization of treatment, especially personalized medicines based on data. Digital twins used for this purpose are built on computer-based, or in silico, models that are fed individual and population data <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. There are Digital Twin studies, such as the creating of Digital Twin of the whole human body and personalized medicine, whose foundation is laid but expected to be completed in the future. The studies will bring about revolutionary developments in the health sector and will lead to an increase in the progress in the field of health and the success rates in the treatment methods applied. In this study, we will examine the Digital Twin studies that have been and are planned to be carried out in the field of health, shedding light on the future, from the perspectives of digital patients, the pharmaceutical industry, hospital, and wearable technologies. Then we will make future suggestions and predictions for Digital Twin technology in healthcare.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. HEALTHCARE APPLICATIONS</head><p>With the development of technology day by day, developments are occurring in the field of healthcare.</p><p>According to Markets and Markets' IoT in Health Market report, the global IoT in healthcare market size is expected to grow from USD 72.5 billion in 2020 to USD 188.2 billion by 2025, at a Compound Annual Growth Rate (CAGR) of 21.0% during the forecast period <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>Digital Twin is used in the healthcare field for purposes such as improving, analyzing, and developing predictions for patients, hospitals, and the pharmaceutical industry. This technology gives very successful results for processes and machines. The development of the Digital Twin of the human body is similar to engineering products but consists of more advanced and complex processes. Sensors can efficiently provide data to the Digital Twin of the designed object but can be more expensive and time-consuming as data from individuals is often obtained through blood tests, imaging systems, and health scans. However, the developments that will be achieved as a result of the Digital Twin studies for the human body will accelerate the diagnosis and treatment processes and increase the accuracy rates. In this context, the concept of "Digital Patient" has come to the fore with the efforts to create the Digital Twin of the human body. The digital patient is patient-specific modeling to support medical decisions. This concept was introduced as part of an R&amp;D project funded by the European Commission. •</p><p>Silico medicine, also known as computational medicine, includes modeling and simulation technologies that directly contribute to the prevention, diagnosis, treatment planning, execution, and management of the disease. There is a difficult process to overcome in creating a digital patient. Integrated and interdisciplinary applied studies of biomedical, mathematics, bioengineering, and computer science branches are needed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>•</head><p>More data is needed for the digital patient. To date, only a few virtual patient projects have been completed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>•</head><p>Virtual patient technology has been defined as a fully autonomous process. However, there are two important points in the implementation of this vision in practice. The first of these is the need for experienced people in the field for the processes of creating the Digital Twin due to the complex nature of the human being. The second is that the collected data, which is important in terms of decision making, are complete and made suitable for analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>We will examine digital twin health practices in four main areas: digital patients, the pharmaceutical industry, hospitals, and wearable technologies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Digital Patient</head><p>An article was published by Chinese researchers in 2018 to understand how the connections between memory and neural networks are formed and to create a detailed threedimensional brain map of the human brain. They conducted various studies in the field of neuroscience and artificial intelligence to learn about the research problems in the article. At the same time, two projects named Brain Initiative and Human Brain Project were initiated in America to solve the structure and connections of the human brain and transfer it to the computer. The Blue Brain Project is one of the subprojects of the Human Brain Project <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. The project also referred to as the Blue Brain Cell Atlas, is the most comprehensive and accessible resource describing the number, types, and locations of cells in all areas of the mouse brain. He published the first three-dimensional atlas containing the entire mouse brain <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. Another work in the field of health is to create virtual twins of soldiers with the US Army and the University of Nevada. Digital twins of soldiers will be created using various imaging techniques such as MRI. Thus, it has been reported that organs can be produced by the 3D printing method by using models in Digital Twins in case of any injury.</p><p>Sim &amp; Cure is the first company to market a patient-based simulation model that allows predicting the placement of medical devices (flow guiding, intravascular device, laser-cut stent) for aneurysm treatment. Sim &amp; Size simulates each size and device type based on the patient's unique anatomy to provide the necessary information before implant sizing selection. In 25 countries, more than 250 hospitals and more than 2000 operations were simulated and aimed to minimize the margin of error <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>. The first of the two main visions of the company is personalized medicine and the second is to develop a treatment plan by securing the treatment applied to the patient <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>. In Sim &amp; Cure's new method, 3D rotational angiography is used to create a 3D model of the aneurysm and surrounding blood vessels after the patient is prepared for surgery. Sim &amp; Cure's software imports the model of the artery and presents it to the surgeon who chooses the points defining the ideal end position on the artery and the size of the implant placed. Using software developed by ANSYS, the physician can rotate and zoom the image to fully understand the relationship between implant and aneurysm. Color coding can be used to show the exact area where the implant touches the embolism (occlusion). A cross-sectional profile shows any gap between the implant and the artery. Each simulation takes only 10 to 25 seconds depending on the device selected. The surgeon can easily select and simulate additional devices and sizes for analysis to determine which will provide the best results. In less than five minutes, the surgeon can complete the simulation process, select the most suitable device, and initiate the operation <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13]</ref>.</p><p>Thanks to the Digital Twin technology, the times when physical parts in the machines need to be changed can be detected early. Similarly, Philips created the "HeartModel", a personalized Digital Twin of the heart, which is an important step towards the idea of the digital patient, starting with the question of whether it is possible to discover and treat ailments in the human body before they occur. Based on the unique images of the heart, HeartModel adapts the generic model to a personalized model. The Philips HeartNavigator tool, also developed by Philips, combines the Computed Tomography (CT) images obtained before the surgical procedure in a single image of a patient's heart anatomy with a layer of live X-ray information during surgery. The tool helps the surgeon select the right device by simplifying prior procedure planning. Provides real-time 3D insight to position the device during surgery. This device is a physical guide for the surgeon on how to proceed <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref>. Siemens Healthineers produces intelligent algorithms that can generate digital organ models based on large amounts of data. Cardiologists in a research project at Heidelberg University have tested these algorithms for cardiac resynchronization therapy. This used therapy is a treatment option for patients with chronic congestive heart failure. In the study, cardiologists simulated the heart's electrical signals with the help of electrodes in a computer environment and created the Digital Twin with an artificial intelligence infrastructure. Models created with MR images and ECG measurements simulated the first and fully simulated heart. Thanks to the created Digital Twin, it saves time in terms of making a definitive diagnosis as well as performing various treatment trials <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[16]</ref>.</p><p>Siemens Healthineers Turkey, about new technologies in health care and imaging solutions to digitalize international participation 40th National Congress of Radiology TURKRAD was introduced in 2019. Participating in the event with the slogan 'We are Shaping the Future in Health', Siemens Healthineers attracts great attention with the demos of the Digital Twin technology and various products and continues to work to offer the Digital Twin technology used in different industries to the service of the health sector. Following heart modeling, its first work in this area, the company is moving towards developing the Digital Twins of other organs, including the brain. Digital Twins, which are routinely used by cardiologists, provide better results thanks to pre-operative visualization and 3D imaging. This technology, which provides great convenience to cardiologists and cardiovascular surgeons, especially in correcting congenital heart defects in babies, was introduced with a demo at TURKRAD 2019. Siemens Turkey Healthineers has set up a display for attendees who want to see their simple Digital Twins. The application, which attracted attention, was presented as a visual demo of the digital future in the health sector, the route of sensitive and personalized medicine <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[17]</ref>.</p><p>When the studies in the field of digital patients are examined, most of the studies are aimed at developing the Digital Twin of a whole human body and focused on the creation of Digital Twins of some organs. It is not too far to carry out studies on integrated Digital Twins, where the number of studies in this field is increasing and the interactions between organs will be seen.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Pharmaceutical Industry</head><p>Companies and researchers focused on longevity are looking at body processes at the cellular level to see how aging progresses, and try to find the right medicines and treatments that can slow them down <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Some studies are also carried out on optimizing medicine production processes and personalized medicine issues. In addition to these subjects, the Computational Science Laboratory of the University of Amsterdam conducts studies in the fields of urban complex systems, computational finance, computational biology, complex systems theory, and computational bio-medicine. The European CompBioMed project, in which a research group in the laboratory participated, is concerned with the development of the virtual human, as each human life and physiology are different, the treatment method and medicines should be personal, changes in the performance of the human body can be seen with a virtual twin created by the genetic code in the DNA of the people. Information in this area was published in a short film. The film also includes information about the application of appropriate treatment to patients, as the effects of medicines on their bodies are first seen through this virtual twin <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[18]</ref>. A virtual twin is told about how medications can affect the right areas, what diet, exercise, and habits are necessary to improve quality of life, and even how bones can be strengthened <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[19]</ref>.</p><p>The SIMULIA Living Heart project, which Dassault Systèmes and the US Food and Drug Administration signed in 2014, signed a 5-year agreement, is the first study to use Digital Twin technology specifically to see the interaction of an organ with medicines. Thanks to this study, it is aimed to reduce the activities of testing medicine trials on animals <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[20]</ref>. SIMULIA Living Heart is a Digital Twin model that has been validated against a wide variety of clinical measurements and created by simulating a human heart. Educators, researchers in the field of cardiovascular, medical device developers, clinicians, and many institutions worked together to create the model. With computer simulation, doctors had the opportunity to see what they cannot see due to the mobility of the heart tissue and to study the complex structure in the heart by experimenting with the same organ model. It leads to personalized treatment by entering patient-specific vital signs and promising research in future medical treatments <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[21]</ref>.</p><p>IBM, together with the supercomputer Watson, aims to simulate biochemical processes in the body by using artificial intelligence techniques to detect cancerous cells in health data obtained from the past. However, the interaction of the 37 trillion cells that make up the human body is a process that is difficult to understand and almost impossible to follow. However, even if each cell has different characteristics, it carries the same genetic information. Damage to cells caused by various reasons can cause the cells to divide and multiply uncontrollably and tumor formation. The Alacris computer model can interpret the developing situations by understanding why the cell divides and the variables that cause its death with 800 genes and 45 biochemical methods. Thus, which medicines can stop dangerous cells from multiplying uncontrollably can be tested on the Digital Twins of patients. In a patient group with cancer, the mucous membrane tumor in the frontal sinus could not be killed as a result of chemotherapy, immunotherapy, and radiation received during normal treatment processes. However, 70% of the cells dividing uncontrollably, as a result of the administration of medicine developed only for breast and kidney cancer, which was designed in the Digital Twin, the data obtained from the biopsy of the tumor after a few months show that the rate of dividing cells decreased to 15% <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[22]</ref>. Semic Health's Digital Body Total has developed the Digital Twin of Artificial Intelligence-based human biological systems or organs or molecular systems, based on aggregated data and medical histories, to help diagnose current medical conditions and predict possible health problems. Realistic predictions can be made by testing scenarios such as adjusting medicines doses for the treatment of many diseases such as different types of cancer, liver sclerosis, Acute Myocardial Infarction, Alzheimer's Disease on Digital Body Total <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Takeda Pharmaceuticals, which has made various initiatives to offer transformative therapies to patients all over the world, has switched to Digital Twin technology in production to shorten pharmaceutical processes that take years to bring to market. By creating Digital Twins of all processes, it can make realistic input-output predictions about biochemical reactions that are difficult to model with machine learning techniques used in Digital Twins <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[23]</ref>.</p><p>Atos and Siemens are working with the pharmaceutical industry to improve manufacturing with an innovative solution based on a digital copy of the pharmaceutical manufacturing process. With "Process Digital Twin" for medicine production, currently tested in the pharmaceutical industry and supported by IoT, artificial intelligence, and advanced analysis, it aims to provide enhanced efficiency and flexibility for long processes in the production of pharmaceutical products. Digital Twins of physical processes were created in the study and it was aimed to overcome the difficulties in medicine production and efficiency by using real-time data <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[24]</ref>.</p><p>In order to benefit from the efficiency of the Digital Twin technology in the pharmaceutical industry, intensive studies have been carried out in areas that are expressed with parameters such as the medicine production process, human DNA, organs, cell behavior, etc. Developments in these areas are expected to assist in optimizing the personalized medicine and medicine launch processes planned for the pharmaceutical industry.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Hospital</head><p>A Digital Twin study was carried out with Siemens Healthineers to improve hospital processes due to high patient demand, increasing waiting times, etc. in the radiology department of Mater Private Hospitals in Ireland. Within the scope of the study, a Digital Twin of the radiology department fed with real data was created. With the Digital Twin, various predictions were obtained and various scenarios were tested on this twin. According to some data and recommendations of Digital Twin for MPH;</p><p>• If less time is spent 13 minutes for CT and 25 minutes for MRI(Magnetic Resonance Imaging), patients' waiting times may be shortened.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>•</head><p>If less time is spent 28 minutes for CT and 34 minutes for MRI, patients will be able to return faster.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>•</head><p>If MRI runs 32% and BT 26% more, the increased equipment usage will not be left.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>•</head><p>If 50 minutes more hours of work per day for MRI, personnel costs can be reduced and 9,500 Euros per year can be saved <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[25]</ref>.</p><p>Thus, in the light of the information provided by the Digital Twin, the changes to be made in the planning and organization for the radiology department of the hospital were determined.</p><p>Fig. <ref type="figure">5</ref>. Realistic 3D Animation of Hospital <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[26]</ref> The use of Digital Twins is expected for many hospital systems and resource management such as this study. In particular, it can be used in matters such as solving lack of the resource in health care during the COVID-19 pandemic process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D. Wearable Technologies</head><p>The startup acceleration center General Electric Health Innovation Village, which supports 26 local startups in the fields of health and medicine in Helenski, operates in partnership with USA-based Startup Health, the world's largest digital health hub. GE also offers an innovative approach by bringing health to the cloud. Engineers in Helsinki specifically observe patients and are working on wireless devices that will not exceed a bandwidth soon and transmit other information such as heart rate, blood pressure, respiration, etc. to the cloud continuously. With this information to be analyzed by software, Digital Twins of each of the people can be created and the system is working to develop software that can alert doctors in unexpected crises <ref type="bibr">[27]</ref>.</p><p>Sooma, one of the startups that creates solutions that change people's lives in the healthcare industry with wearable technology, develops devices that simulate the electrical signals of the brain to treat depression, other neurological and psychiatric disorders. Patients use these devices for 30 minutes in single-use and 5 days a week for 2 weeks. The patient places an electrode on each of his temples that sends an electronic signal to the brain. The positive electrode boosts immediate brain activity, which is very useful for dealing with depressive symptoms. Studies show that brain activity and metabolism in depressive patients is reduced or impaired. With the simulation of these areas, it is possible to restore normal brain functions and reduce symptoms of depression. With the Sooma Software Suite, patients can also be monitored at home. An application is installed on the phone of the patient where he can enter data about his daily mood and feelings. All these data are updated and uploaded to a cloud that the doctor can access on the internet. By examining these data and simulations, the doctor can monitor the treatment process and make changes in the treatment program. Although Sooma anticipates the use of this technology in hospitals very soon, it aims to create an alternative to depression drugs and to eliminate the side effects of drugs by reducing the use of drugs <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[28]</ref>.</p><p>Developing products that use muscle activation technology and electromyography (EMG) for a new dimension in understanding the behavior of muscles, Myontec analyzes the activity in the muscles and their responses to exercises according to the general health of the body and transfers them to a digital environment thanks to the technology placed between the threads, and makes more effective exercises in the light of these data. The company examines the user's activities through shorts they have developed, calculates the threshold at which the muscles perform best, increases training efficiency, and provides information about the warming and cooling times by reducing the risk of muscle injury <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29]</ref>. The technology integrated into the product called Myontec Mbody Pro measures the electrical activity of the muscles during training and provides an understanding of how they behave under what conditions. With the sensor technology in the product, it records and analyzes the EMG data in the muscles together with the heart rate, heart rhythm, and heart rate. Thanks to real-time data and post-exercise analysis, it allows users to make their working techniques healthy and efficient, and to detect and prevent problems such as imbalances and deviations in your muscular system <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[30]</ref>.</p><p>Expanding and combining wearable technologies that enable patients to be tracked physically and mentally will increase efforts to create and track innovative and wider Digital Twins. In the near future, wearable Digital Twin technologies will be applied to examine changes in the musculoskeletal system of patients with mobility impairments as well as paralysis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. FUTURE INSIGHTS</head><p>With the work done in the field of Digital Twin and the developments in IoT, sensors, big data, and artificial intelligence technologies, which have a large share in the formation of the Digital Twin, the number and variety of innovative studies in this field will increase. Before physical interventions such as medicine therapy, radiotherapy, or surgical operations are performed on the human body, various studies can be carried out to make sure that it is really necessary. Even if it is not preferred in case of difficulties in diagnosing diseases, a method that can be applied is to use exploratory surgery. With the creation of a holistic Digital Twin of the human body, the disease can be diagnosed by examining the necessary regions on the patient's Digital Twin, without using the exploratory surgery method, which can sometimes be painful for the patient and prolong the patient's treatment process. If the treatment method considered suitable for the disease is tested on the patient's Digital Twin and is expected to yield successful results with a high probability, the relevant treatment may be applied to the patient.</p><p>In the field of physiotherapy, the Digital Twin technology can be used to monitor the muscle development of patients, to monitor the changes in the cells in the spine and bone movement with physical therapy in conditions such as scoliosis. Following the treatment process with the personal data of the patient, predictions can be made for its improvement. With the creation of Digital Twins of these patients who receive physiotherapy as a result of in-vehicle and out-of-vehicle traffic accidents or paralyzed patients to be able to stand, walk and return to their former lives, information about what kind of treatment could be followed. In addition, thanks to real-time data transfer, various Digital Twin studies can be performed on changes in exercise and muscle activities, whether the strain or exercises show the right effect. It can be understood whether the patients respond to the treatment by following their condition and whether the treatment provides the desired effect. In addition, by testing various treatment methods on the patient's Digital Twin, which one is most suitable, time is saved and costly treatments that will not respond positively to the patient are avoided.</p><p>With the introduction of technologies in the field of personalized medicines, it is aimed to accelerate the medicine development processes and to decrease the use of test subject animals. In addition, studies are carried out to detect and reduce the side effects of drugs early. Some patients may experience allergic reactions to the active ingredients of certain drugs. For example, a patient who is allergic to Sulfonamide, which is included in some antibiotic drugs, may cause rash-like reactions as well as life-threatening situations due to the use of Sulfonamide-containing drugs <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[31]</ref>. Serious health problems can occur as a result of allergic reactions to many substances such as these. Many people do not know that they are allergic to such substances. For this reason, some chemical properties in the Digital Twins of patients can be examined before administering certain medications that may cause an allergic reaction. In allergies that cannot be detected by blood tests such as sulfonamide, it is possible to use medication on the real patient in a controlled manner and by examining real-time data feeding the patient's Digital Twin by doctors to detect and prevent complications that may occur early.</p><p>With the developments in 5G and infrastructure technologies, Digital Twin studies can be carried out to check the health of military teams that go to special operations, to be aware of the situation when they are injured, and how to intervene. Soldiers can transmit data to their Digital Twins in a distance, wearing clothing that is equipped with sensors but does not restrict mobility.</p><p>Digital Twin technology can also be used in organ transplantation, to resolve uncertainties about whether tissue adaptation will be achieved after transplantation or to predict probability.</p><p>While the demand for hospitals has intensified especially during the COVID-19 pandemic process, the problem of capacity and resources has come to the fore in many issues such as the number of respirators, intensive care units, and healthcare personnel in hospitals. With the creation of Digital Twins of hospitals or departments, resource management and planning can be viewed from a broad perspective in terms of more accurate management of resources in hospitals, so that needs-oriented activities can be better planned. As a result of machine learning and artificial intelligence techniques used in Digital Twins, various remedial predictions can be made to optimize process and resource use. New approaches gained in light of foresight can be tested on the hospital/department's Digital Twin. The situations obtained as a result of the scenarios run on the Digital Twin will be examined and the methods found right by the authorized experts can be applied in the hospital/department. Thus, more efficient processes can be created for resource management activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. CONCLUSION</head><p>Digital Twin studies in the field of health have mainly focused on the creation of twins of the organs in the human body, understanding the cell behavior in the body, and applying appropriate medicines and treatments. Furthermore, in parallel with the development of sensor, IoT, and machine learning technologies and the development of imaging systems, Digital Twin technology will also accelerate. With this rise in technology, great strides will be taken towards creating the Digital Twin of the entire human body that has long been desired. In addition, there will be widespread use of the Digital Twin to solve the problems in the management of hospital systems and medical resources, which have become more prominent with the COVID-19 pandemic. Similarly, it is expected that Digital Twin solutions will be used to accelerate the vaccine and medicine development processes that occur with COVID-19. In this study, we discussed the important Digital Twin studies conducted in different branches of health, which could lead to new studies, and talked about our predictions about what kind of developments these technologies may develop in the future. In the future, in addition to the health field mentioned in this study, detailed studies can be carried out on Digital Twin technology from different perspectives such as aerospace, military, education, security systems. Besides, studies can be conducted for more specific application areas that have not been done yet in the field of health. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Digital Patient Roadmap (Digital Patient Roadmap) report was prepared with the DISCIPULUS project, which is part of the Coordination and Support Action Plan financed by the European Commission. With the project carried out within the scope of the European Union 7th R&amp;D Framework Program (2007-2013), it is aimed to determine the roadmap for realizing the digital patient paradigm. Partners in the DISCIPULUS project were: University Col¬lege London, United Kingdom; empirica Communication and Technology Research, Germany; The University of Sheffield, United Kingdom; Istituto Ortopedico Rizzoli, Italy and Universitat Pompeu Fabra, Spain. Prominent recommendations according to the Digital Patient Roadmap report are as follows:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Fig. 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2. An Example Brain Image from the Blue Brain Project in Digital Environment [10]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig.3. An Example Heart Image from Philips HeartModel<ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15]</ref> </figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 4 .</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Fig.4. Semic Health's Digital Body Total Future Predictions<ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> </figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Hype Cycle for Healthcare Providers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Craft</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.gartner.com/en/documents/3988462" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-05" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Gartner</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twins in Health Care: Ethical Implications of an Emerging Engineering Paradigm</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Greenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lavazza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Beier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Bruynseels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Santoni De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Van Den Hoven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fgene.2018.00031</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Genet. | www.frontiersin.org</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SEMIC Health -Digital Body Total</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.13102/semic.v0i21</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.semic.de/en/ai/semic-health" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SEMIC RF Electronic GmbH</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2595-0339</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">21</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017-11-01" />
			<publisher>Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aydın</forename><surname>Erdem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Dünya ve Türk Tıp Tarihi. Ankara: Güneş Kitapevi</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Digital Health Hype Cycle 2020</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lloyd</forename><surname>Price</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.healthcare.digital/single-post/2020/01/29/Digital-Health-Hype-Cycle-2020" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-04-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Healthcare Digital</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Market Share and Appraisal Process</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781118878293.ch13</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Electricity Markets</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Ltd</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-11-22" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="131" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reflecting on DISCIPULUS and Remaining Challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vanessa</forename><surname>Díaz-Zuccarini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mona</forename><surname>Alimohammadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">César</forename><surname>Pichardo-Almarza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781118952788.ch2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Digital Patient</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-01-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="26" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">İnsan beyninin 3 boyutlu haritası: Hayal mi, gerçek mi?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Serap</forename><surname>Sinem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.bilimveutopya.com.tr/makale/insan-beyninin-3-boyutlu-haritasi-hayal-mi-gercek-mi" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-12-14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Bilim ve Ütopya</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Cell Atlas for the Mouse Brain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Erö</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M.-O</forename><surname>Gewaltig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Keller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Markram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fninf.2018.00084</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Front. Neuroinformatics | www.frontiersin.org</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">84</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Blue Brain Project -EPFL,&quot; EPFL</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">De-composing in bad faith: its cause and cure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-8705.1982.tb01899.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://sim-and-cure.com/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Critical Quarterly</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Critical Quarterly</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0011-1562</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1467-8705</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1982-12" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">De-composing in bad faith: its cause and cure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Sim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1467-8705.1982.tb01899.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://sim-and-cure.com/product" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Critical Quarterly</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Critical Quarterly</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0011-1562</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1467-8705</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1982-12" />
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using ANSYS workbench for structural analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mathieu</forename><surname>Sanchez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/b978-0-08-102164-4.10000-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.ansys.com/about-ansys/advantage-magazine/volume-xii-issue-2-2018/brain-trust-for-aneurysm-treatment" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Engineering Analysis with ANSYS Software</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="511" to="540" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How a virtual heart could save your real one -Blog | Philips</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Henk Van Houten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.philips.com/a-w/about/news/archive/blogs/innovation-matters/20181112-how-a-virtual-heart-could-save-your-real-one.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-12-17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Philips</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">10. Philips Oral Healthcare Symposium</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1055/s-0035-1559748</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=34&amp;v=Nx24-L6-K-4&amp;feature=emb_logo" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ZWR - Das Deutsche Zahnärzteblatt</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">ZWR</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0044-166X</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1439-9148</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">07/08</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="336" to="336" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-08-26" />
			<publisher>Georg Thieme Verlag KG</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Philips Healthcare</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agile Innovation – Ein Kernelement des Siemens Healthineers Performance System</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Walter</forename><surname>Märzendorfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3139/9783446458154.013</idno>
		<ptr target="Available:www.siemens-healthineers.com" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Agile Produktentwicklung</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Carl Hanser Verlag GmbH &amp; Co. KG</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-10-08" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="310" to="347" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Erlang</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Siemens Healthineers sağlıkta geleceğin teknolojilerini tanıttı</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Belgin Yakışan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.aa.com.tr/tr/sirkethaberleri/hizmet/siemens-healthineers-saglikta-gelecegin-teknolojilerini-tanitti-/654299" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-11-18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Anadolu Ajansı</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Instruction Sequences Expressing Multiplication Algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bergstra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Middelburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7561/sacs.2018.1.39</idno>
		<ptr target="https://ivi.uva.nl/content/news/2018/04/your-digital-twin.html?1556017299749" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Scientific Annals of Computer Science</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">SACS</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2248-2695</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2018</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-09-25" />
			<publisher>Scientific Annals of Computer Science</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Amsterdam</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">YouTube – YouLearn. Education via YouTube?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Michniuk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.15219/em56.1122</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1FvRSJ9W734" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">e-mentor</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">e-mentor</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1731-6758</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1731-7428</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2014</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">56 (4)</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2014-10-24" />
			<publisher>Foundation for the Promotion and Accreditation of Economic Education</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Stokoe, Maj. Gen. John Douglas, (born 30 Dec. 1947), Director, Dassault Systèmes EuroNorth, since 2015</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dassault</forename><surname>Systèmes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/ww/9780199540884.013.36379</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.3ds.com/press-releases/single/dassault-" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-12-01" />
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Living Heart Project Reaches Next Milestones in Mission to Improve Patient Care</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">{BLR 2376} FDA - Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D'souza</forename><surname>Karl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1089/blr.1997.16.206a</idno>
		<ptr target="Available:www.fda.gov/downloads/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/OfficeofMedicalProductsandToba" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biotechnology Law Report</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Biotechnology Law Report</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0730-031X</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1557-8704</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="206" to="207" />
			<date type="published" when="1997-03" />
			<publisher>Mary Ann Liebert Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Zeit Online</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rauner</forename><surname>Max</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.zeit.de/zeit-wissen/2017/05/medizin-genomanalyse-digital-zwilling-zukunft-arzt-dna/komplettansicht" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Medizin: Zum Arzt? Ihr Doppelgänger geht schon!</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-09-29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Digital Twins Bridging the physical and digital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Mussomeli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Parrot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Umbenhauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Warshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/focus/tech-trends/2020/digital-twin-applications-bridging-the-physical-and-digital.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Deloitte Insights</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">INCLUSIÓN COMO MÉTODO</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aldo</forename><surname>Ocampo González</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-6654-8269</idno>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7867/1809-0354.2020v15n2p330-365</idno>
		<ptr target="https://atos.net/en/2020/press-release/general-press-releases_2020_05_18/atos-and-siemens-introduce-digital-twin-solution-within-the-global-pharmaceutical-industry" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Atos de Pesquisa em Educação</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Atos Pesq. Educ.</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1809-0354</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">330</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-07-01" />
			<publisher>Fundacao Universidade Regional de Blumenau</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Photography Best Practices and Workflow</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Digital Workflow Optimization</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4324/9780080928227-6</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Digital Photographic Workflow Handbook</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Erlangen</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Routledge</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012-11-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Siemens Healthineers AG</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Schlienkamp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.9785/ag-2021-660127</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.siemens-healthineers.com/news/mso-digital-twin-mater.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Die Aktiengesellschaft</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0002-3752</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2366-097X</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="r13" to="r14" />
			<date type="published" when="2021-01-01" />
			<publisher>Verlag Dr. Otto Schmidt</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Siemens Healthineers</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TELEWORK: 21. YÜZYILIN YENİ ÇALIŞMA BİÇİMİ</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ferit</forename><surname>Ölçer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.14783/maruoneri.678614</idno>
		<ptr target="https://geturkiyeblog.com/21-yuzyilin-saglik-trendleri/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Öneri Dergisi</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1300-0845</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-01-23" />
			<publisher>Sosyal Bilimler Ensititusu Hakemli Dergisi Oneri</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Earth Station Antenna using Reflecting Beam-Waveguide Feed</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shooji</forename><surname>Sooma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ikuro</forename><surname>Sato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susumu</forename><surname>Tamagawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isao</forename><surname>Mori</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kiyotsugu</forename><surname>Ishii</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/euma.1975.332190</idno>
		<ptr target="https://soomamedical.com/sooma-treatment-outcomes-2018/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">1975 5th European Microwave Conference</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1975-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Sooma</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LAS VEGAS SANDS CORP., a Nevada corporation, Plaintiff, v. UKNOWN REGISTRANTS OF www.wn0000.com, www.wn1111.com, www.wn2222.com, www.wn3333.com, www.wn4444.com, www.wn5555.com, www.wn6666.com, www.wn7777.com, www.wn8888.com, www.wn9999.com, www.112211.com, www.4456888.com, www.4489888.com, www.001148.com, and www.2289888.com, Defendants.</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1089/glre.2016.201011</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.myontec.com/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Gaming Law Review and Economics</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Gaming Law Review and Economics</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1097-5349</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1941-5494</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="859" to="868" />
			<date type="published" when="2016-12" />
			<publisher>Mary Ann Liebert Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">mBody health: Digitizing disabilities in Sierra Leone</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emma</forename><surname>Hebert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Spencer</forename><surname>Mccullough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><surname>Chan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arsen</forename><surname>Drobakha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Ritter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Khanjan</forename><surname>Mehta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ghtc.2016.7857357</idno>
		<ptr target="https://performbetter.co.uk/product/myontec-mbody-pro-portable-emg/#detail" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2016 IEEE Global Humanitarian Technology Conference (GHTC)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sulfonamide Allergies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amber</forename><surname>Giles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Foushee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Lantz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Gumina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/pharmacy7030132</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pharmacy</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Pharmacy</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2226-4787</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">132</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09-11" />
			<publisher>MDPI AG</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
