<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Blockchain, Internet of Things and Digital Twins in Trustless Security of Critical National Infrastructure</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>ACM</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright ACM</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2020-11-26">2020-11-26</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Hammoudeh</surname></persName>
							<email>m.hammoudeh@mmu.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Manchester Metropolitan University Manchester</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="GB">United Kingdom</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Blockchain, Internet of Things and Digital Twins in Trustless Security of Critical National Infrastructure</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">The 4th International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems (ICFNDS)</title>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>ACM</publisher>
							<date type="published" when="2020-11-26" />
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3440749.3442650</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:38+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The advent of communication technologies and smart storage gave rise to the concept of smart cities. One of the key enabling technologies of smart living is the Internet of Things (IoT). In recent years, IoT has developed into many areas of application including critical national infrastructure (CNI) such as transport, hospitals and power distribution grid. The proliferation in IoT applications raised many serious security and privacy concerns to citizens, businesses and governments. CNI systems depend heavily on IoT devices and Cyber Physical Systems (CPS) to perform autonomous actions or inform human decision makers through the exchange and processing of data.</p><p>Recently, blockchain has been advocated as a solution for secure data storage and sharing. Blockchain cryptographically offers a</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>secure platform for maintaining a decentralised, "append-only", publicly verifiable and immutable data structure, which is timestamped and sequentially ordered by its reference to previous block hashes. The immutability and security of blockchain can improve the CNI protection. Two specific smart CNI enabling technologies that would highly benefit from blockchain are IoT and CPS.</p><p>Digital twins are virtual replica of the network and logic layer of physical system. A digital twin provides a platform to solve major IoT related CNI cybersecurity challenges in tomorrow's secure infrastructure, energy distribution, smart cities, smart manufacturing (Industrial IoT and Industry4.0) and autonomous transit systems. This key note discussion outlines how to implement blockchain as a fundamental theory for trustless security for connected CNI. It will investigate technologies which can be utilised to achieve a trustless matrix such as blockchain and peer-distributed security systems, for instance onion-routing, with the wider aim of defining trustless security further. The research also considers the feasibility of trustless IoT security systems and their application in CNI. It investigate the present state-of-the-art in cybersecurity as it relates to trustless security technologies and blockchain and what is the present state of the art of cybersecurity in IoT-enabled CNI systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Security and privacy → Distributed systems security; • Networks → Security protocols.</p><p>Permission to make digital or hard copies of part or all of this work for personal or classroom use is granted without fee provided that copies are not made or distributed for profit or commercial advantage and that copies bear this notice and the full citation on the first page. Copyrights for third-party components of this work must be honored. For all other uses, contact the owner/author(s). Professor Hammoudeh advised the UK's Government on law reform related to national cybersecurity security through a number of committees and hearings. He is the co-developed a state of the art unprivileged and trustless computing zero trust security theory. He currently investigates ways of improving industry practice to allow for guaranteed security and distributed computing applications which work effectively every time. This theory of zero trust is rooted in his research on smart cities and critical infrastructure such as smart grid and intelligent transport. Throughout his 15 years research career, Mohammad developed significant insight and expertise into a number of computer science disciplines (such as blockchain and Artificial Intelligence) adjacent to his area of specialism (distributed systems).</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>ICFNDS '20, November 26-27, 2020, St.Petersburg, Russian Federation © 2020 Copyright held by the owner/author(s). ACM ISBN 978-1-4503-8886-3/20/11. https://doi.org/10.1145/3440749.3442650 KEYWORDS blockchain, digital twin, zero trust security, internet of things ACM Reference Format: Mohammad Hammoudeh. 2020. Blockchain, Internet of Things and Digital Twins in Trustless Security of Critical National Infrastructure. In The 4th International Conference on Future Networks and Distributed Systems (ICFNDS) (ICFNDS '20), November 26-27, 2020, St.Petersburg, Russian Federation. ACM, New York, NY, USA, 1 page. https://doi.org/10.1145/3440749.3442650 1 BIOGRAPHY Mohammad Hammoudeh is a Professor (Chair) of Cyber Security in the Department of Computing and Mathematics at the Manchester Metropolitan University. Mohammad heads the CfACS Internet of Things Lab he founded in 2016 where he leads a multidisciplinary group of research associates and PhD students. From this he established the Lab as a leading research hub with a broad portfolio of successful, industry-sponsored projects. Mohammad has been awarded above £1.5M in competitive research funding as Principal/Co-Investigator for 13 research projects. He published over 75 refereed conference papers, over 55 peer reviewed journal articles, and is a successful editor of 3 books and many journal special issues. Mohammad supervised 7 PhD candidates to completion is currently co-supervising 6 PhD students. He is a Senior Member of IEEE and Fellow of the Higher Education Academy UK.</figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internet of Things: Evolution and technologies from a security perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Ande</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-1632-8484</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bamidele</forename><surname>Adebisi</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0001-9071-9120</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Hammoudeh</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-1058-0996</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jibran</forename><surname>Saleem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.scs.2019.101728</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sustainable Cities and Society</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Sustainable Cities and Society</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">2210-6707</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">101728</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-03" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Threats on the horizon: understanding security threats in the era of cyber-physical systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Walker-Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohammad</forename><surname>Hammoudeh</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-1058-0996</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Omar</forename><surname>Aldabbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mehmet</forename><surname>Aydin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Dehghantanha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11227-019-03028-9</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Supercomputing</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">J Supercomput</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0920-8542</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1573-0484</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">76</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2643" to="2664" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-10-24" />
			<publisher>Springer Science and Business Media LLC</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
