<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the Space Domain 48</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Salvador</forename><surname>Llopis Sanchez</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Mazzolin</surname></persName>
							<email>r.mazzolin@rheagroup.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ioannis</forename><surname>Kechaoglou</surname></persName>
							<email>i.kechaoglou@rheagroup.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Wiemer</surname></persName>
							<email>d.wiemer@rheagroup.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Wim</forename><surname>Mees</surname></persName>
							<email>wim.mees@rma.ac.be</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jean</forename><surname>Muylaert</surname></persName>
							<email>j.muylaert@rheagroup.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">European Defence Agency (EDA)</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brussels</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">RHEA Group</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Wavre</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Royal Military Academy</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Brussels</settlement>
									<country key="BE">Belgium</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the Space Domain 48</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-23210-8_108</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:43+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The focus of this article is to describe the rapid changing nature of space systems where the electromagnetic spectrum and cybersecurity aspects coexist, leading to a "change of course" to ensure secure space communications. Space systems must be designed to achieve cyber resilience. Existing vulnerabilities must be mitigated as resulted from a risk management methodology. To avoid compromises of security, a security monitoring mechanism and incident response for space systems have to be implemented. The authors provide an analysis of the functional capabilities and services of a "cybersecurity space operations center." System monitoring is essential in view of obtaining a cyber situational awareness and decision-making for space missions. Security operation center-related services could be built up in a permanent or in an ad hoc mobile infrastructure. An integrated cyber range capability to test, train, and exercise over modeled and simulated space systems will improve space operators' skills when confronted with time-critical interventions.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introduction</head><p>National security is not restricted to securing the land, air, and maritime boundaries and pursuing strategic interests but encompasses all aspects that have a bearing on the nation's well-being. Outer space and cyberspace have emerged as the new enablers for nations, enhancing the speed and efficiency of national security and socioeconomic efforts and also providing novel applications in these areas. In an information-dominated world, they are instrumental in providing the competitive edge among the global community, strategic and tactical superiority in conflict situations, and projection of national power and influence. In addition to capability enhancement towards national aspirations, investments are also necessary for securing these capabilities against deliberate or unintentional intrusions or attacks and in ensuring safe and sustainable operations. Assured access to cyberspace is a key enabler of national security. Two of the defining characteristics of a strong, modern, industrial nation are economic prosperity and a credible defense. The ability to use cyberspace has become indispensable to achieving both of these objectives. Business and finance executives, as well as senior defense leaders, rely on cyberspace for exactly the same thingto get information, move information, and use information to make better decisions faster than the competition. The data-and information-rich environment of the modern battlespace presents a key area of both strategic opportunities and, equally, vulnerability. Both cyber and space technologies, in particular, are the new battleground for competing great powers who seek to limit opponents' access to information, analytics, and complex surveillance and reconnaissance information with which to inform decision-making.</p><p>With growing participation, commercialization has become an integral part of space operations and is receiving active governmental support. The peaceful use of space and the military significance of outer space continues to increase with some 60 countries currently utilizing it for peaceful purposes, for communications, banking, monitoring environmental and climate change, disaster management, e-health, elearning and communications, and surveillance and guidance systems for military purposes. Regarding vulnerabilities, while space operations have always been vulnerable to natural forms of interference, progressive developments in the domain have also resulted in the emergence of unique novel challenges to space security and the sustainability of the environment. Greater participation in the domain and commercial prospects has more players vying for prime orbital slots, the radio frequency spectrum, and a larger share of the market. Overcrowding and increasing space debris are adversely affecting the survivability of satellites. The environment is therefore becoming more contested, congested, and competitive with the consequent increase in potential for disruption of operations. Space is being used extensively by advanced spacefaring nations for supporting military operations, and most new entrants would also leverage their access for these purposes. A corollary to this is that all assets in space providing a strategic or military advantage can be designated as valid targets in case of hostilities. Consequently, advanced nations are making efforts to dominate and control the environment to protect their interests and assured access to the realm, and the less capable ones would do the same to gain an asymmetric advantage through degradation and destruction of systems. Both these strategies demand development of counter-space threats and counter-cyber threats capabilities that would include risk mitigation actions. Such capabilities in the hands of rogue nations or non-state actors, who have limited interests in the space domain, could be extremely dangerous, even up to the catastrophic level of cascading satellite collisions. In recent years, national security challenges have necessitated a tacit acceptance of the use of the space domain for meeting national security objectives.</p><p>The discussion about the creation of space forces in some countriesas a new service branch within the armed forcesto have control over military space operations is one example of the growing importance of the use of outer space.</p><p>Cyberspace is a man-made domain consisting of the interconnected networks of computing and communication devices and the information contained on these networks. Satellites and other space assets, just like other parts of the digitized critical infrastructure, are vulnerable to cyberattacks. When considering our daily lives, there is not an operation or activity conducted anywhere at any level that is not somehow dependent on space and cyberspace. This interdependency could be used to attack space assets from cyberspace. From a cyberspace perspective, it's irrelevant how high above the ground a computer is positioned. Cyber vulnerabilities associated with space-related assets therefore pose serious risks for ground-based critical infrastructure, and insecurities in the space environment will hinder economic development and increase the risks to society. Advancements in the cyber domain have not required a protracted thrust by governments towards its development as the transformational nature of the technology, its commercial potential and cheaper access, has caused a self-sustaining expansion of capabilities and capacities. Societies' increasing dependence on networks, however, has resulted in a surge in the number and sophistication of cyberattacks that exploit the hardware or software vulnerabilities of the networks with diverse motivations and consequences. Cyber intrusions could target government agencies and departments and private corporations or individuals, with diverse impacts on national security. These could be undertaken for espionage, to commit cybercrime or for denying or disrupting critical national infrastructure systems like power grids, telecommunication networks, transportation systems, water services, or financial and banking operations. They could be used for social engineeringspreading disinformation and molding public opinion with the intention to destabilize the internal security environment of the country, as is currently being seen as part of the current western electoral dialogue, and supporting evolving hybrid warfare techniques that see aggressive state-based actors conduct provocative activities that fall slightly below the threshold to provoke political sanctions or military response. As network centricity becomes integral to military operations, military equipment and operations could be attacked to gain strategic or tactical advantage. These attacks could even be used to cause kinetic effects and acts of sabotage or to hamper national response mechanisms, all of which would endanger lives, thereby impacting the credibility of governments and the underlying societal security frameworks. More widespread and systematic attacks could escalate tensions among states. The perpetrators of these attacks currently range from an individual to hacking syndicates that work independently or are covertly supported by governments and corporations. States as well as non-state actors could seek an asymmetric advantage by employing such attacks to undermine an adversary's security and stability. With greater technological capability, the nature and scale of cyberattacks have continued to evolve. They are now more targeted and decisive, with clear political, economic, or military motivations and intentions. The traditional lines that would have earlier helped distinguish between the types of attacks and the motivation of their perpetrators have blurred. While the state actor could resort to an attack to undermine security or stability, a similar attack could now be undertaken by non-state actors for extortion or for obtaining information that could be sold to third parties. In that sense, a cyber threat intelligence capability is paramount to prevention and preparedness.</p><p>Networks continue to expand and become more complex, and their interdependencies continue to grow, further enhancing the vulnerabilities and increasing the difficulty in providing comprehensive protection. The environment is highly dynamic, and preventive and defensive countermeasures and reactive strategies, even with continuous efforts, are finding it difficult to keep pace with the rapidly evolving threats. Cyber situational awareness and the ability to monitor the domain, identify the vulnerabilities, and detect intrusions are still not sufficiently developed. Attempts at enhancement are hampered by concerns for privacy, freedom of speech, and the free flow of information. Even as detection rates have gone up through concerted efforts, cyber forensics need to be developed for attribution, as the attacker can easily hide his tracks in this intricate, borderless cyberspace domain. International legal regimes have failed to keep pace with the rapid technological advancements in this discipline. Advanced nations, whose critical dependence on space and cyberspace exposes them to asymmetric risks of disruption, are responding to these limitations by developing effective deterrence against misadventures, including counterthreat capabilities. Growing economies are investing heavily in computer networks and communication facilities to meet their aspirations and have received a further boost with the smartphone revolution, increasing the density and diversity of appliances used for access to the Internet. The diversity of machines makes it difficult to put in place comprehensive protection measures. Computers and networks rely mostly on foreign software and hardware, exposing them to risks associated with the global information technology supply chain. Most of the data generated in any country is exported and stored in foreign data banks using cloud computing infrastructure. Digital and smart city initiatives and the increasing involvement of the private sector in nation-building endeavors are progressive steps that are also increasing the scope and complexities of cybersecurity efforts and are further complicated by the Internet of Things (IoT). All these makes securing the domain an arduous task.</p><p>Clearly, it can be seen that most earth-based activities are touched in some manner by space when one considers the wide array of applications associated with satellite communications, precision navigation and timing, and earth and space observation. The contemporary nature of international strategic competition has reached an inflection point where national strategic security interests embrace a wide range of activities and communities ranging from traditional military to daily commercial interests. The integrity of the underlying technology base will be a central consideration to ensuring societal security and stability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description of the Cyber Threat Landscape Affecting Space-Based Information Systems</head><p>Space activities have obtained an increased focus in recent years. Within the space domain, space-based information systems (for the purpose of this publication, spacebased information systemsreferred as space systems in the further textcan be understood as the collection of devices and networks which permit the reception, processing, exploitation, and transmission of the information having their origin or destination in any type of space mission, e.g., navigation, telecommunication, earth observation, weather monitoring, etc.) use a digital infrastructure which connects primarily ground control stations with satellites. The architecture of satellite communications is composed of a ground segment or control segment, a space segment, and a user segment. Each segment has its own information exchange requirements and protection measures. Satellites can retransmit information to other satellites using relays without the intervention of ground assets. Ground control stations are connected with other ground tracking stations to exchange information. Ground stations can deliver commands through the uplink channel to the spacecraft and can receive data via the spacecraft downlink channel.</p><p>In cyberspacebeyond the computer networks, their connections through physical cables or fiber opticsthere are other communication means which are often forgotten when a threat assessment is performed: the signals. Electromagnetic spectrum forms the invisible propagation medium through which the signals and their information flow. Electromagnetic spectrum has a remarkable influence in the space domain given the long distance between space assets and end users. The convergence between cyber defense and electromagnetic activities for space systems is even more significant. Reasons for that convergence reside in the need to keep control over space assets at any time as well as to ensure confidentiality, integrity, and availability of space operations. In the past, satellites were launched with an estimated life span of decades. Recognizing that satellites cannot be fixed easily when they are in orbit, the design of such satellitesexpected to be fully operational for many yearsforesaw minor and major software configuration updates to accommodate future enhancements. This contingency design might extend their estimated life cycle. In case of performing technical corrections to a satellite, stringent procedures must be put in place to prevent any disruption. The architectural design and engineering discipline of space systems are of the utmost importance. System engineering precepts for verification and validation testing <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(Byrne et al. 2014</ref>) expose security flaws which may not be previously identified by information security standard practices. The adopted cyber defense posture of space assets is a trade-off between a technological simplicity to permit defendable systemswhich means fewer entry points known as attack vectorsand robust system architectures. Simplicity and robustness must go hand in hand, but it is not always feasible.</p><p>In this section, some cybersecurity topics relevant for space systems will be described with an expression of cyber threats and associated risks. The results will shed some light on challenges and recommended actions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Electronic Warfare and Cyber Defense Convergence</head><p>It would be difficult to understand the digital battlefield as we know it today without the information services provided by space assets, e.g., geolocation. Thanks to a global coverage, space systems enable armed forces to operate in different scenarios across the globe. Space domain is more and more a contested and congested environment where armed forces aim to preserve freedom of operation. What is at stake is the ability of a military commander to plan and conduct military operations supported by a multi-domain command and control system (multi-domain command and control system refers to an emerging doctrinal concept which proposes the use of capabilities in concert across domains, e.g.. air, space, and cyber) which benefits from an integration with space systems. The global defense C4ISR (C4ISR stands for command, control, communications, computers, intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance) architecture leverages on space, especially because military operations are expeditionary. The armed forces are experiencing a digital transformation leading to a drastic modernization of command and control systems in all the traditional operational domains at land, sea, and air. Space systems contribute to a better integration and jointness of military operations. The underlying physics of space communications could be altered by an adversary causing undesired events into a space mission. Space assets are equipped with thousands of sensors transmitting signals of a different nature and informing about parameters to a monitoring center. Signals may interfere with each other if they use close radio frequencies of which harmful effects dependamong other featureson the transmission power. To achieve a high level of cybersecurity in space, efforts must be pursued in promoting cyber resilience by hardening electromagnetic features of onboard space assets. Effects in cyberspace can be achieved by exploiting vulnerabilities in the electromagnetic spectrum and vice versa. Sophisticated electromagnetic techniques could make satellites vulnerable including ground equipment. Space systems must be protected against jamming or spoofing (electromagnetic jamming (United States Department of the Army 2017) is the deliberate radiation, reradiation, or reflection of electromagnetic energy, and spoofing (United States Defense Intelligence Agency 2019) is a technique that deceives a receiver by introducing a fake signal with erroneous information) and must have a capability to operate under degraded circumstanceswhich means to cope with limited communication capabilities.</p><p>Electronic warfare (EW) (electronic warfare (United States, Joint Publication 2012) refers to a military action involving the use of electromagnetic energy and direct energy to control the electromagnetic spectrum or to attack the enemy. EW consists of three divisions: electronic attack, electronic protection, and electronic warfare support) and cyber defense technologies need to keep pace with a fast technological development in space. Today the challenge is not to establish longrange communications that are almost taken for granted. The challenge is to secure such communications that the protocols that were born to ensure the information distribution are also valid to ensure confidentiality and resilience. Experience in this field is far from understood since the consequences of adversarial use are not publicly known. Cyber defense and EW operations are closely intertwined in a dynamic continuum like "two sides of the same coin." Ground-based EW systems considered as counter-space capabilities must be well taken into account when assuring the survivability of space-based tactical communications. Engineering design of space systems could advocate for a redundancy of key equipment in order to maintain service continuity, notably when a cyber-electromagnetic attack occurs or could enforce the use of radio waveforms less susceptible to external interferences. An increase of cybersecurity capabilities in space will allow governments to ensure their freedom of use, despite asymmetric capabilities possessed by an adversary. The duality cyber and EW and their effects cannot be neglected when approaching security solutions for space systems.</p><p>Space is a pivotal element of defensive capabilities for the military. Intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance (ISR) depend largely on space as well as positioning, navigation and timing (PNT). Situational awareness in space (SSA) helps to track and collect data related to space debris which is an important matter of concern for space operations. Reported cyberattacks on space systems including their lessons learned could work backwards to structure a cyber defense posture. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Managed Cybersecurity of Space Systems Is Key</head><p>It is impossible to fix a security vulnerability if neither monitoring nor detection capabilities are implemented into corporate networks of a given organization. This is a principle that should be obvious but pushes cybersecurity in space to become mainstream throughout all phases of space operations from the initial design, to launching and entry into service up to the final disposal phases. Like any other critical infrastructures do, space systems need to be monitored to detect malfunctioning or to correct deficiencies as they appear. But how big is this endeavor in the face of growing cyber threats affecting space systems? Can we extract some common ground to articulate a better readiness? The answers to these questions are not simple. Some ideas will follow to illustrate the complexity of the space security issues.</p><p>A few space-based cyberattacks can be found in the literature. A summary of cases grouped by the categories of the space missions affected is as follows <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">(Zatti 2017</ref>):</p><p>• Missions on observation and exploration experienced incidents such as targeted interference and control take over. • Missions on navigation experienced incidents such as a denial of service and spoofing. • Missions on telecommunications experienced incidents such as deliberate jamming and unauthorized access.</p><p>Although, there are differences in the cyber threats affecting each category of space missions, a general classification can establish two main groups: (a) those focused on the information, e.g., infiltration in command and control networks, and (b) those targeting the space infrastructure, e.g., onboard components, payload, etc. The availability of cheap jamming devices has demonstrated the threat to global positioning system (GPS) applications <ref type="bibr">(Cuntz et al. 2012</ref>). These threats may fall under the information category. GPS provides geolocation and timing information to a plethora of ground satellite receivers. GPS devices assist naval ships and drones to transit through international waters or to operate planned routes in the air, respectively. GPS spoofing <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Falco 2018)</ref> has been revealed as a serious threat that could manipulate the GPS signal by injecting false data in the GPS receiver causing a miscalculation of the positiononce again a clear example of the interrelated dependencies between electromagnetic signals and cyber defense. To reduce the impact of such attacks and minimize the risks, e.g., collisions at sea and deception, a backup to "classical" navigation systems could be an option besides demanding regulators to establish urgent measures, e.g., anti-jamming or anti-spoofing components or add-ons.</p><p>The commercial space sector is experiencing an explosion. The rapid emergence of low-cost microsatellites is characterized by a wide spreading of commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) products <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">(Falco 2018)</ref>. New "CubeSat constellations" could increase the satellite's attack surface to potential hackers. Attention must be paid to ensure the adoption of minimum cybersecurity requirements before receiving an authorization to deploy in space. Policy recommendations would be focused on holding the owner of the satellite network liable for any damage that occurred and imposing a culture of "duty of care" for the space assets that private companies own, manage, operate, or develop. Another aspect of common concern which may fall under the infrastructure category is the complex supply chains when developing a satellite. Different suppliers may participate at various stages of the satellite's lifecycle. This situation introduces difficulties to manage accountability of the cybersecurity measures needed to be put in place. Therefore, system integrators must be empowered to certify a cybersecurity compliancebased on security standardsof every piece of hardware and software ever installed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Challenges and Recommended Actions</head><p>To meet and outpace cyber threats in the space domain, it is recommended to create a cybersecurity space operations center (CySOC) as the focal point to handle cybersecurity incidents for space missions forming part of a wide area network with other security operation centers (SOC), computer emergency response teams (CERT), and security monitoring centers (SMC). CySOC is a threat-driven response with responsibilities to detect and support the mitigation of cybersecurity incidents, train space operators, and provide expertise about the convergence of cyber defense and electromagnetic activities to counter-cyber threats. An integral part of the CySOC would be a full-fledged cyber range for space systems. A cyber range would provide training, education, exercise, and testing functionalities including the promotion of a system engineering discipline aiming to build cyber resilient architectural designs of space systems avoiding architectural points of failure. Security certification and accreditation of space systems shall be governed by and construed in accordance with an overall cybersecurity certification framework. A cyber range could simulate space scenarios including the environmental conditions present in space. Combining intelligence with cyber operations as part of the operational activity at CySOC could prevent the materialization of future attacks. An information sharing network (ISN) would allow the exchange of information of cyber threats to other space security centers. The CySOC must provide a cyber situational awareness capability for space systems contributing to a SSA. A digital forensic capability as part of an incident handling would permit to conduct forensic investigations appropriate to support attribution. An interesting concept would be the development of a mobile deployable CySOC which could complement the work of a permanent center in situations where it is necessary to conduct on-site activities, e.g., spaceports and military operations overseas. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Functional Capabilities for Implementing a Space Operation Center</head><p>Baseline Functions of a Cybersecurity Space Operations Center (CySOC)</p><p>The need for a cyber defense situation awareness capability (CDSA) is well documented in cybersecurity-related literature and results from extensive studies in the domain. CDSA itself is rooted in the application of foundational situation awareness (SA) concepts as applied to the cyber domain. Although there may be variants, the work of Mica Endsley <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">(Endsley 1995a</ref>) and her decision-making model is still widely accepted as the foundation, including three levels of situation awareness (SA): perception, comprehension, and projection. Fundamental to development of any level of cyber operator SA is implementation of an appropriate means to monitor the cyber environment through collection of cybersecurity-relevant data and transforming this into information useful for the operator understanding. A CySOC provides a focal point for this essential capability of data collection and information transformation.</p><p>The CySOC focuses on the early detection of an event that may reveal an incident. It provides the necessary tools to help the analyst not only to timely classify the event but also to identify effective mitigation measures. In an effort to enhance its proactive capabilities, it will utilize any available input including a direct user input, through a call center. In addition, various threat intelligence feeds are a valuable asset to identify threats and develop mitigation measures.</p><p>Since the security analysts are not normally in control of the operational systems, the CySOC team works closely with the monitored system's administrators who implement the resulting mitigation measures. This close collaboration is also essential for continuous security protection optimization and sensor tuning to enhance the cybersecurity resilience.</p><p>As a baseline, the functional role of the CySOC is a derivation of cyber situation awareness, providing: Finally, the CySOC can produce meaningful reports containing situational awareness data, system statistics, and regulatory compliance status as deemed necessary per network/mission.</p><p>As already introduced above, the application of resulting mitigation measures is out of the scope of the cybersecurity operations. The role of the CySOC is strictly advisory to the monitored system's administrators who are responsible for the final decision and application of a mitigation strategy.</p><p>Commonly, cybersecurity operations center services are divided into the following three service packages to cover different needs of the monitored entities based on their internal cybersecurity capabilities and risk assessment:</p><p>1. Managed Threat Detection: The service is limited to detection and report of probable incidents, 2. Managed Detection and Response Support: Building upon detection and report, the service expands to incident response support in collaboration with the monitored entity. 3. Specialized Services: It contains additional supporting services that may be utilized on demand based on specific needs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Managed Threat Detection (MTD)</head><p>Managed threat detection service is limited to monitoring and triage of events informing the monitored entity for probable incidents that require attention. Normally it includes the following functions:</p><p>• Call center: In the form of a call center, utilizing telephone, email, and ticketing system, the CySOC is receiving input from the users of the monitored system as an extension to the deployed sensor. The user reports aim to enhance the capability of early incident detection covering advanced threats able to evade the monitoring infrastructure. • Proactive real-time monitoring and prioritization: Aggregating and analyzing all security events from IT and operation technology (OT) systems, as well as any necessary preprocessing and visualization to provide an overview of the current situation. This encompasses immediate analysis of real-time events and data feeds such as alerts from various intrusion detection systems or other system logs. The objective is to spot probable immediate threats or incidents that require the attention of the monitored entity. • Reporting: Production of meaningful reports containing system statistics and regulatory compliances status as deemed necessary per network/mission.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Managed Detection and Response Support (MDRS)</head><p>The service aims to support the monitored system's incident investigation and response capabilities. The involvement of the CySOC does not stop on the reporting of a probable incident (like in MTD service) but continues with the comprehensive investigation of the event, in collaboration with the monitored entity providing mitigation strategy advices monitoring the effectiveness of the applied measures. Managed detection and response support will normally include the following functions:</p><p>• Incident and threat analysis: Involving the in-depth analysis of events that are categorized as an alert indicating a probable incident. This capability usually involves detailed analysis of various data artifacts from different sensors and systems. • Situational awareness: Providing knowledge and understanding of the current state of the IT/OT systems, which can provide timely and accurate assessment of the effectiveness of the mitigation strategy. • Incident response support and collaboration: A key capability providing the tools (both technical and administrative) to support an effective response by the monitored entity to a successful cyberattack. The CySOC will collaborate with the monitored entity in order to identify in a timely manner the most effective mitigation measures to contain and minimize the impact of a cyberattack. This involves working with affected system owners to gather further information about an incident, understand its significance, and assess the potential mission impact. • Reporting: Expands on the MTD service reports to include development of targeted threat intelligence data for the space sector.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Specialized Services</head><p>The specialized services utilize the advanced capabilities of the CySOC to support specific needs of the monitored entity. Those services can be provided on demand and may be totally independent from the other services or build upon those:</p><p>• Forensic investigation/analysis: Providing tools, means, and forensic investigation capabilities to analyze cybersecurity incidents in detail and to provide intelligence on cyberattacks in support of MDRS service or as part of postincident analysis investigation. This encompasses analysis of digital artifacts (including various storage media, network traffic, memory analysis, etc.) to determine affected assets, identify the attack vector, produce IOCs, and establish a timeline of events. • Threat intelligence: Ingesting institutional, governmental, or commercial threat indicators to provide timely intelligence to use against cyberattacks relevant to the monitored entity in the form of security feeds. • Security protection optimization recommendations and system tuning: Including analysis of the monitored system's capabilities to identify required improvements, updates, upgrades, or tuning in support of the monitoring operation. This applies only to security-related devices utilized by the CySOC including, but not limited to, intrusion detection and prevention systems (IDS/IPS), firewalls, log servers, and endpoint protection solutions. The security operation team passes recommendations to the systems' owners leaving to them the implementation responsibility. The service does not provide system vulnerability assessment. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Concept of Operations</head><p>The cybersecurity operations team is organized into three teams, called Tiers, Tier-1, Tier-2, and Tier-3, organized under a technical leader and managed by a service manager.</p><p>Tier-1 and Tier-2 analysts compose the proactive detection and analysis team. The team is responsible for identifying threats having the Tier-1 analyst to perform continuous monitoring of the alert queue (system generated or by the call center) and triaging security alerts escalating them to Tier-2 analyst for further investigation and deep-dive incident analysis. The team is also responsible for identifying mitigation measures under the supervision of the technical leader supported, when required, by the advisory team. They coordinate with the asset owners under threat for a timely and effective response providing recommendations only (no actions upon the monitored system) and situational awareness reports. In the case of MTD service, the team is limited to triage of alerts leaving the further investigation and response to the asset owners.</p><p>Real-time monitoring is dependent on the necessary presence of cybersecurityrelated sensors, log collection and aggregation, event correlation, and operation of security information and event management (SIEM) tools.</p><p>Tier-3 analysts form the security advisory team. The team is composed by specialists that possess in-depth knowledge in one or more of the following fields, network security, endpoint security, threat intelligence, forensics, and malware reverse engineering, as well as the functioning of specific applications or underlying IT/OT infrastructure, acting as an incident "hunter," not waiting for escalated incidents and closely involved in developing, tuning, and implementing threat detection analytics. Their functions include:</p><p>• Forensic investigation/analysis: In support to the forensic investigation/analysis service. • Space threat intelligence feed production: Leveraging commercial and open threat intelligence feeds, as well as internal findings, the team produces space-specific threat intelligence. The threat intelligence results are used to improve CySOC operations (e.g., feeding the system with IOCs) and are reported to the monitored entity as part of the reporting function of MDRS service. • Reporting: In addition to the required reports for the monitored entity, the team produces reports related to the CySOC itself. The reports include metrics on the effectiveness and efficiency of the operations, mean response time, etc. • Monitoring system optimization: In support of the security protection, optimization recommendations, and system tuning service including also the CySOC system itself. The identified improvements for the CySOC system are implemented directly in contrast to the monitored systems in which the implementation falls under the responsibility of the system owners. • Tool improvement and engineering (to improve effectiveness and efficiency):</p><p>Encompassing improvements of existing supporting tools and engineering of new to improve the effectiveness and efficiency of the CySOC operations. • Proactive detection and analysis team support: As subject matter experts, they support in incident response operations.</p><p>The above functions of Tier-3 analysts are aided by cyber simulation technologies. A fully functioning cyber range provides the means to analyze current and potential threats evaluating security feeds and hunting potential threats. The cyber range having the capacity to represent the monitored systems at high fidelity offers the optimal means to conduct the Tier-3 functions.</p><p>The service manager has a complete view and responsibility for the state of the service leading the daily operations. The technical leader is the senior security analyst of the proactive detection and analysis team. He has the full view of the service and the service operations status and is responsible for the coordination of CySOC operations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional Capabilities of a Cybersecurity Space Operation Center (CySOC)</head><p>The previous section described the baseline functions of a cybersecurity operation center. However, as previously described in this article, the realities of threats to space missions go beyond the traditional monitoring and analysis of IT/OT systems and comprise other threats including (a) those focused on the information, e.g., infiltration in command and control networks, and (b) those targeting the space infrastructure, e.g., onboard components, payload, etc. As has been described, threats against the command and control networks may include specialized threats in the electromagnetic spectrum, while threats against the onboard components may take the form of kinetic threats from other space objects.</p><p>Therefore, it is recommended that the concept of CySOC should encompass not only traditional cybersecurity operations capacity but be augmented as an all-hazards threat assessment and mitigation service as a supplemental capacity to existing space operations. While the existing roles for space operations, including signal interference detection and response or SSA, should remain as the primary operational capacity for ensuring space operations against natural or random occurrences, these operations are not designed nor equipped to assess the potential of these effects being part of a larger, intentional, threat campaign. Meanwhile, a properly equipped CySOC, having access also to signal interference analysis capabilities and SSA information, could develop a larger threat and risk-based view of SA also involving indicators of compromise (IOC) from terrestrial networks, social engineering attacks, and others.</p><p>As an added perspective, to augment the role of the CySOC towards a more complete space mission assurance capability, it is recommended that the CySOC should also analyze information from ground-based physical security surveillance systems, enabling a more complete all-hazards risk assessment capability. Certainly, in all cases, CySOC operations would remain limited to the role of analysis and response assessment, offering advisory services to space operations, network and system operations or physical security operations, with each having their respective roles as final decision authority for implementation of the recommended mitigation response.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Importance of Collaborative Information Sharing and Incident Management</head><p>It is already understood that effective cybersecurity operations have a high dependency on collaborative information sharing of cyber-relevant information. Advisory services providing reference information related to vulnerability of systems, availability of malware exploits and resulting IOCs, and threat awareness information are essential aspects of cybersecurity analysis and response assessment. However, creation of effective information sharing communities for the purpose of coordinating cyber incident response remains an elusive goal. While communities of cyber adversaries will actively collaborate to develop comprehensive attack campaigns through coordination of social engineering attack specialists, information reconnaissance and data collection, and the development of target-specific malware to penetrate systems, defenders are hampered by ineffective collaboration tools to allow secure information sharing of cyber incident information across organizational boundaries. Fortunately, changing regulations regarding responsible disclosure, improved attitudes towards information sharing, and improved technologies to support secure and selective information sharing of cyber incident information are increasing the potential for developing a coordinated incident response capability. For example, within Europe, four pilot projects, sponsored by the European Commission, have been established to develop an EU network of cybersecurity competence centers. This initiative represents the largest ever investment into creation of a collaborative cybersecurity information sharing capacity. The current initiative includes various studies and system development activities to create secure means for partners to share information among a wide scope of trusted relationships. Instances of the proposed CySOC services should participate and collaborate among such a network of cybersecurity competence both to leverage on the derived knowledge and to contribute to improvements in cybersecurity competence. In this way, the CySOC can take advantage of knowledge coming from dependent sectors and thereby improve the effectiveness of mitigation response to threats posed to space systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Role of Education and Training for Developing a Skilled Space Workforce Introduction</head><p>Space agencies are facing the challenge to educate and train a workforce that will be required to operate in an increasingly contested and complex space environment that may be affected by deliberate adversary cyber operations (Martin and Inspector General 2012). Space operations are moreover increasingly reliant on information system technology, and even though increasingly efforts are being dedicated to better securing networks and systems, no system of systems will ever be entirely cybersecure. Therefore, a paradigm shift is needed from information assurance to mission assurance, which has to be considered in the context of complex systems that comprise not only physical and information assets but also cognitive and social domains. Subsequently solutions need to be designed for cyber resilience with the human operator as an integral part of the solution to ensure mission control in a degraded information environment. At this time few opportunities exist for space operators to develop a clear understanding of how cyberattacks impact the systems they manage or a space mission as a whole. When cyber events are considered in a training exercise, they are typically developed in an isolated storyline out of fear that the potential cascading effects might interfere with the other training objectives. Given the principle that you "fight like you train," it is however essential to incorporate realistic cyber scenarios into a significant part of the education and training exercises, in order to produce a workforce that is capable of mitigating the effect of cyber incidents in an operational space system environment.</p><p>The design of cyber injects for training non-cyber operators can be performed in two possible ways <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">(McArdle 2019)</ref>. The "systems engineering approach" consists in first identifying an attack vector (weaponized file, social engineering, hardware of software supply chain, etc.) and subsequently the target of the attack <ref type="bibr">(organization, mission, network, system, etc.)</ref>. Next the specific effects of the identified attack opportunity are estimated, such as induced system failures, denial of service, and data exfiltration, and this effect is then simulated to the trainees.</p><p>The second approach is an "information assurance approach," which is based on the confidentiality, integrity, and assurance (CIA) triad. By applying the loss of one or more of the CIA attributes to a specific system, the result on the broader encompassing systems of systems, on the mission or on the organization, is estimated and presented to the trainee during the training. Certain observable effects of cyberattacks may be difficult to be distinguished from more innocent technical failures; however, both situations require a different response. Therefore, it is important that trainees learn to recognize a cyberattack in order to trigger the appropriate response and recovery. This is therefore also a training objective.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Training Environments</head><p>When training a space workforce, the option of training cyber incidents with live systems is not an option. This can be circumvented through the use of a high-fidelity synthetic training environment, where the operators interact with a virtual environment that runs as much as possible the real software systems combined with models and simulations of the physical phenomena the systems normally interact with. Synthetic systems exist for specific simulations or trainings. However, they are often tailored to a specific task and siloed, which makes it hard to integrate them It is essential to be able to run multi-domain simulations, covering all ground segment systems and radio links, as well as all aspects of the space segment ranging from the power management subsystem, attitude determination and control, communications, computing and data handling, to all possible payloads <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(Cayirci et al. 2017</ref>). This will make it possible to design realistic scenarios that confront the trainees with their day-to-day user interfaces and with a realistic baseline system behavior.</p><p>The goal of the non-cyber workforce is not just to train them for identifying cyber incidents but also for training the interaction with the cyber workforce, so they know the procedures, the contact points, the information to provide, how not to destroy valuable forensic information, etc. Finally, the ultimate goal is to create a digital twin of the systems that the trainees are being trained for. A digital twin is a virtual representation of a system that has been loaded with the real-world inputs and environmental parameters that were acquired on the real-world system so that it can be used to accurately simulate the real-world system's behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Designing Training Scenarios</head><p>Attackers have an interest in being unpredictable. Indeed, high-threat potential actors will deliberately misrepresent their capabilities, having a stockpile of zero-day exploits at hand. They are typically capable of deploying varying tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs), for instance, by relying on different hacker groups. Finally, any up-to-date detailed threat intelligence covering adversaries' capabilities will likely be classified and therefore difficult to include in training scenarios. Therefore, it is impossible to design training scenarios that cover the exact incidents the trainees will face during normal operation. Nevertheless, using the available doctrinal documents from potential adversaries and drawing inspiration from documented past attacks, it will still be possible to develop relevant scenarios.</p><p>As a baseline reference for designing adversarial cyber operations, the following aspects should be considered. Adversaries will be especially interested in high-value targets, such as ground stations, communication satellites, etc. They will furthermore try to undermine trust in the information that is produced, for instance, by manipulating sensor data that is acquired by a payload or telecontrol information from the satellite itself in order to mislead the operators. Finally, they can also resort to blended strategies, where they combine kinetic attacks, like jamming or sabotage, with nonkinetic cyberattacks that reinforce and prolong the effect of the physical attack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Evaluating Training Results</head><p>The education and training processes will have to be periodically evaluated and improved in order to ensure that they achieve the objective of a cyber-skilled workforce. Alongside the typical evaluation approaches for more scholarly education as well as for operational training activities, it will be necessary to ensure that the cyber-related objectives for the training have been achieved. More in particular the question that needs to be answered is whether the staff members, both in cyber and in non-cyber positions, are able to take the appropriate decisions with respect to cyber incidents and events.</p><p>A valuable approach for measuring in an objective way whether the trainees have observed and appropriately processed the necessary information to support their decisions is the situation awareness global assessment technique (SAGAT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">(Endsley 1995b</ref>) that was developed by Mica Endsley and is based on her decision-making model with three levels of situation awareness (SA): perception, comprehension, and projection. SAGAT is an on-line approach for real-time, human-in-the-loop trainings that freeze the simulation at specific moments during the training and query the subjects on specific information elements situated at the three levels of SA. Unfortunately, the fact of freezing a complex training scenario does have an effect on trainee performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(Matthews et al. 2000)</ref>; therefore, it may be more appropriate to use real-time probing by sending SA questions to the trainees as a part of the normal exercise communication <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(Jones and Endsley 2000)</ref>. Since the probing should not disturb the normal operation of the trainee too much and therefore the sampling rate and size shall be limited, it may be useful to complement it with nonintrusive expert behavior observations, for instance, based on the situation awareness behaviorally anchored rating scale (SABARS) approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">(Strater et al. 2001)</ref>.</p><p>It must finally also be noted that cyber range-based trainings could be used for selecting operators or for verifying the required skills for candidate operators before they start a long and expensive training, in a similar way as Liu et al. did to select astronauts to be trained into qualified robotic operators <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">(Liu et al. 2013</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusions</head><p>Space is changing from a selective preserve of wealthy states or well-resourced academia, into one in which market forces dominate. Current technologies bring space capability into the reach of states, international organizations, corporations, and individuals that a decade ago had no realistic ambition in this regard; and capabilities possessed a few years ago only by government security agencies are now in the commercial domain.</p><p>Space and cyber, both technologically intensive domains, need to be harnessed optimally for national security. Formulation and articulation of an all-encompassing national security policy would help define domain-specific strategies and roadmaps. There is a global trend towards increased instability in these domains as nations develop counter-space threats and counter-cyber threat capabilities. Consequently, space has been labeled as the fourth, and cyber the fifth, dimension of warfare.</p><p>The threat manifests itself in a variety of forms on a daily basis. Lacking a coherent way forward, the collective accumulation of the variety of impacts from the myriad of cyberattacks across the breadth of critical systems could serve to drain western innovation, economy, and commerce without reaching the threshold of triggering meaningful government and military and commercial engagement and response. There has never been a more important time or imperative for us to act upon this issue given the increasing potential existential threats posed to our societies and make this a more central element of our public agenda. The potential exists for a revolution to drive space-based security.</p><p>Disclaimer This article is a product of the authors. It does not represent the opinions or policies of the European Defence Agency or the European Union and is designed to provide an independent position. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the. . .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the. . .</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>(a) Knowledge and understanding of the current state of the monitored systems (b) Timely and accurate assessment of potential threats Moreover, the CySOC provides incident management support and post-incident analysis capabilities to support forensic investigation of incidents. The scope of the investigation will focus on the: (a) Circumstances (how and why) that allowed this incident to occur (b) Identification of affected assets (c) Evaluation of the extend of the compromise (d) Identification of indicators of compromise (IOC)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_12"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>synthetic training environment. It is therefore necessary to encourage simulation system developers to open up their systems and to develop federation technologies to interconnect them.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_16"><head>48</head><label></label><figDesc>Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the.</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">t r a c k ers of t w a r e . c o m</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber defense of space-based assets: verifying and validating defensive designs and implementations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Byrne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Dorros</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877050914001276" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc Comput Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jamming and spoofing in GPS/GNSS based applications and services -threats and countermeasures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cayirci</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Karapinar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L ;</forename><surname>Ozcakir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Konovaltsev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Dreher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 winter simulation conference. IEEE Press Cuntz M</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Aschenbruck</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Martini</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Meier</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tölle</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the 2017 winter simulation conference. IEEE Press Cuntz M<address><addrLine>Berlin/Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">318</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Joint military space operations simulation as a service</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a theory of situation awareness in dynamic systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Endsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hum Factors: J Hum Factors Ergon Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="32" to="64" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measurement of situation awareness in dynamic systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Endsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hum Factors</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="84" />
			<date type="published" when="1995" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">one for space force: space asset cyber security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Falco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Job</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.belfercenter.org/publication/job-one-space-force-space-asset-cybersecurity" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>cyber security project</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proceedings of the human performance, situation awareness and automation: user-centered design for the new millennium</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Endsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
			<pubPlace>Savannah, GA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Can real-time probes provide a valid measure of situation awareness</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Predicting space telerobotic operator training performance from human spatial ability assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acta Astronaut</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">92</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="38" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inspector General Nasa cybersecurity: an examination of the agency&apos;s information security. US House of Representatives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Martin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-02" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measures of infantry situation awareness for a virtual MOUT environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the human performance, situation awareness and automation: user centred design for the new millennium conference</title>
				<meeting>the human performance, situation awareness and automation: user centred design for the new millennium conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Rethinking cyber training for the non-cyber warrior, conference summary and conclusions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Mcardle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://pellcenter.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/McArdle-Rethinking-Cyber-Training-Final.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Measures of platoon leader situation awareness in virtual decision-making exercises. No. SATECH-00-17. TRW INC Fairfax VA Systems and Information Technology Group United States Defence Intelligence Agency, Challenges to Security in Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Strater</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001-01" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>United States Department of the Army, FM 3-12 Cyberspace and electronic warfare operations</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Joint Publication 3-13.1 electronic warfare</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012-02-08" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>United States</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The protection of space missions: threats and cyber threats; information and systems security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Zatti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings 48 Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the. . . 939</title>
				<meeting>48 Cybersecurity Space Operation Center: Countering Cyber Threats in the. . . 939<address><addrLine>Mumbai, India</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-12-20" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3th international conference</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
