<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twins for Intelligent Authorization in the B5G-Enabled Smart Grid</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Javier</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Malaga</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Juan</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rubio</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Malaga</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Alcaraz</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Malaga</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twins for Intelligent Authorization in the B5G-Enabled Smart Grid</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MWC.001.2000336</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:43+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EnAblIng tEchnologIEs</head><p>Due to the increasing complexity of power grid architectures, access control is essential to manage the permissions of all users, processes, and heterogeneous devices involved. This obliges us to continuously study the full range of requirements of this scenario, and redesign new ways</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Beyond fifth generation (B5G) communication networks and computation paradigms in the edge are expected to be integrated into power grid infrastructures over the coming years. In this sense, AI technologies will play a fundamental role to efficiently manage dynamic information flows of future applications, which impacts the authorization policies applied in such a complex scenario. This article studies how digital twins can evolve their context awareness capabilities and simulation technologies to anticipate faults or to detect cyber-security issues in real time, and update access control policies accordingly. Our study analyzes the evolution of monitoring platforms and architecture decentralization, including the application of machine learning and blockchain technologies in the smart grid, toward the goal of implementing autonomous and self-learning agents in the medium and long term. We conclude this study with future challenges on applying digital twins to B5G-based smart grid deployments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IntroductIon</head><p>The smart grid (SG) came in the last decade to change the way electricity is consumed in homes and demand is managed in the utilities. As the digitalization of critical infrastructures continues, advancements in telecommunications do not stop either, and the industry is not unaware of this progress. New communication technologies such as 5G and innovative computing paradigms at the edge of the network are on the horizon. Together with them, other disruptive technologies such as the Internet of Things (IoT) and blockchain are already being integrated into various industrial sectors (including the smart grid) in what is already known as Industry 4.0.</p><p>Besides adding more complexity to the SG infrastructure, these technologies can solve several of the problems it currently faces. This ranges from increased process automation to secure data handling at all levels, accompanied by almost instantaneous transmission and analysis. Only in this way can we understand future industrial scenarios where data ubiquity is achieved, as well as optimal interaction between all participants in the production chain.</p><p>However, these upgrades can only be adopted if fine-grained control over the data is introduced, along with continuous assessment of all assets in terms of cyber-security, in order to anticipate risks, generate evidence transparently, and ensure the democratization of the available resources. This is attained by advanced authorization policies capable of adapting to lively environments with ever changing technology and actors. For this mission, virtualization technology is the turning point for the simulation and visualization of changes in the infrastructure while also predicting consequences derived from potential actions, approaching the concept of digital twin (DT). This can be defined as a representation of a physical asset in virtual space, enabled by synchronized data acquisition about its structure, functionality, and behavior. By analyzing and simulating virtual states of such an entity, it is possible to undertake real-time monitoring and predictions, optimize processes, and improve decision making <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. All in all, they emerge as a forthcoming solution to guide access control by coordinating all security services within the SG network in a holistic and autonomous manner.</p><p>In this work, we carry out an introspection of the future SG architectures to accommodate the upcoming communication and computation technologies by looking into the evolution of DTs for the ultimate goal of implementing intelligent authorization policies. More specifically, we provide a mid-term and long-term analysis and a concise study on the pending challenges of DTs concerning artificial intelligence (AI). These are consistent with recent industrial views which suggest that the landscape of DT evolution will fulfill a three-stage process: from mere monitoring systems with limited analysis capabilities nowadays, going through semantic platforms featuring prediction and optimization over the next few years, to the future implementation of fully semantic, self-learning, socio-technical platforms <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>The remainder of the article is organized as follows. To begin with, the enabling technologies for the upcoming power grids are highlighted. Then we present the proposed SG architecture and the analysis of DT advancements in the medium and long terms. Based on this, the main challenges regarding AI and intelligent authorization policies are identified later. Finally, conclusions are drawn.</p><p>to intelligently update authorization policies over time. In this section, we review the emerging technologies that offer significant innovations to the SG in the medium and long terms.</p><p>Beginning with the timeline of forthcoming communications technologies, beyond fifth generation (B5G) networks emerge as the first solution to meet the performance demands and extreme capacity of present-day applications. Following the principle of "no latency, gigabit experience," it will allow to instantaneously and reliably connect millions of users in dense areas and trillions of IoT devices, thereby enabling the smart cities and autonomous cars, among other applications. As for industrial environments, 5G enables realtime business decisions driven by data, paving the way for cost savings and long-term growth. In the particular case of the SG, 5G networks can provide significant advancements to four application scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>Intelligent Distributed Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Automation: Nowadays, fault isolation and control procedures are conducted by centralized automation, which causes more traffic from the terminals to utilities and high latency. However, B5G enables effective P2P communication between terminals, aggregators, and substations to take the processing logic from primary sites to those distributed devices in an autonomous way.</p><p>Millisecond-Level Load Control: This circumvents the issue of traditional distribution networks, which are not deployed with sufficient communication infrastructure to support precise load control. At this point, 5G offers ultra-low-latency and high-reliability communications with high isolation from actual management assets.</p><p>Low Voltage Information Retrieval: Electricity usage data is periodically retrieved in intervals of ~1 5 minutes. However, upcoming services impose quasi-real-time reporting and the coverage of a greater number of terminals in households and high-end premises. In this sense, B5G copes with such massive access to ensure high-frequency transmission of data.</p><p>Distributed Power Supplies: Over the present and coming years, new types of micro-grids and distributed power supplies are being integrated at the user end, which now becomes a user and generator of electricity. These introduce new challenges to deal with massive power and information flows in an efficient manner. Again, 5G emerges as a key technology to enable seamless communication with millions of accesses and low latency.</p><p>At present, the standardization bodies behind 5G, the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) and the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI), already started its commercial deployment early in 2020. Long after that, 6G technologies, despite still being in the design phase, are expected to roll out from the 2030s. This process first requires a deep effort to physically integrate new equipment into the radio access networks and then implement virtualization technologies that enable the programmability of B5G networks. This is the case of software defined networking (SDN) and network functions virtualization (NFV), which permit the flexible migration of components of the network core to the cloud so that network resources are optimized for particular services.</p><p>As part of this offloading of functions to the cloud, mobile edge computing (MEC) appears to address further performance requirements by bringing the cloud closer to the edge of the network, and consequently to the users. For this reason, it is considered as a key technology toward B5G networks to drive demand for its services. It provides a highly distributed environment that can be used to integrate computing, storage, and networking resources with the base station, thereby enabling compute-and latency-sensitive services in proximity to mobile users. With this computation model, applications are split into small tasks that are executed at the local or regional clouds to achieve ultra-low latency and high bandwidth.</p><p>SG will also benefit from MEC technologies: • Smart meters can send energy readings, and trigger alarms or fire events that can be transmitted to the MEC nodes for data analytics and billing purposes. • Measuring sensors and actuators from a local region can collect control information that is handled by MEC to perform fine-grained management of energy supply. Despite the contributions of MEC, some challenges arise when distributing sub-tasks of one of these services across different edge computing nodes. The reason is that we need to coordinate individual edge service providers and allocate shared data between different domains, which is essential in applications with stringent requirements on mobility <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Therefore, MEC needs a versatile deployment that allows the optimal management of virtual resources while in operation. Fog computing can also be integrated and leveraged as an alternative in this matter, by orchestrating scalable services between devices that reside at the edge <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>In the area of authorization enforcement, the security of data at rest is likewise of paramount importance, as well as the accounting of every single action performed across all devices within the grid. Blockchain solutions barge in at this point to offer synchronization of immutable but linkable information between all partners within a federated SG, vouching for the data ownership and provenance. This way, access registers can be securely analyzed by external auditors to submit potential policy updates to devices and components involved, favoring the creation of access control schemes governed by smart contracts <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Beyond authorization applications, blockchain can be applied to other scenarios, generally to conduct energy trading processes or to establish trusted networks for the operation of intelligent electric vehicles <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>Altogether, these technologies set the dynamic and mutable application context, where it is fundamental to introduce access control mechanisms that are steadily supported by intelligent monitoring platforms and context awareness solutions. These pave the way for the development of DTs in the future SG. In the next sections, we take these constraints into account to analyze the evolution of these systems in the medium and long terms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IntEllIgEnt MonItorIng PlAtforMs for b5g-bAsEd sMArt grIds In thE MEdIuM tErM</head><p>According to the heterogeneity of not only technologies but also stakeholders involved in a SG system (i.e., prosumers, governments, utilities, reg-Despite the contributions of MEC, some challenges arise when distributing sub-tasks of one of these services across different edge computing nodes. The reason is that we need to coordinate individual edge service providers and allocate shared data between different domains, which is essential in applications with stringent requirements on mobility.</p><p>ulators), it becomes mandatory to apply hybrid access control mechanisms. They can be based on role-based access control (RBAC) or attribute-based access control (ABAC), which permit fine-grained policies to be defined that are easy to maintain. These must subsequently meet the real-time needs of all entities, respond in a timely manner, and be subject to dynamic cyber-security rules.</p><p>As a consequence, the traditional authorization model in an SG scenario should be redesigned to comply with these requirements. The aforementioned model is commonly based on the introduction of policy enforcement points (PEPs), which emit requests to policy decision points (PDPs), where they are assessed and access decisions are made depending on the policy and permissions. Whereas the former points are allocated in households or substations near the consumption areas, the latter are endorsed by aggregators, utilities, or data centers in a hierarchical fashion within the grid infrastructure, where analysis and management endpoints are placed. However, despite their location, all of them serve as policy information points (PIPs) to collect contextual information from resources and processes involved in any interaction to enrich the evaluation of access requests, conducted by PDPs. This is where context awareness mechanisms and intelligent monitoring platforms come into play.</p><p>By introducing ubiquitous processes that permanently conduct context awareness analysis over the entire infrastructure, the authorization components can improve decision making and enhance the established policies <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. More specifically, these processes act as PIPs that are assigned different tasks: first, they retrieve contextual information from a layer of devices to be monitored, which includes low-level operational inputs (e.g., energy readings, pricing data) and host-based or network-related information (e.g., protocol used, commands issued, bandwidth). Together with cyber-security analysis executed ad hoc or leveraging external mechanisms (e.g., intrusion detection systems), this information helps to create a virtual representation of the assets in a certain region: a DT.</p><p>Consequently, DTs must be implemented and live in the vicinity of the devices, if not embedded in them, to achieve total interoperability between virtual and actual assets without delays. MEC nodes are a solution to introduce intermediate computational nodes alongside regular energy management procedures near the consumption areas. In particular, these can transparently implement the PDP components in charge of autonomously applying authorization at a regional level and the context awareness processes described before. Both services are deployed on different edge applications that are coordinated by the respective utility, which ultimately behaves as a global PDP when exchanging data between different regional domains.</p><p>The new infrastructure would also allow the utilities to store aggregated transactions that belong to a local business network in the blockchain. Thus, there would be a distributed ledger across a set of peers involved in an SG consortium, which guarantees consistent updates to a chronologically sorted database. It can contain tamper-proof access and context awareness registers from all participants using a consortium-based platform with an efficient consensus algorithm. This information is regularly accessed and validated by external auditors and regulators (e.g., federal commissions, energy market operators) to assess the policy enforcement and detect possible tamperings. As a result, they may also contribute to the new authorization life-cycle by proposing potential updates to the different utility PDPs.</p><p>The resulting B5G-enabled architecture is depicted in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The current network infrastructure may converge on this model in the coming years, taking into account the direction of the new communication and computing paradigms. How- MEC nodes are a solution to introduce intermediate computational nodes, alongside regular energy management procedures, near the consumption areas. In particular, these can transparently implement the PDP components in charge of autonomously applying authorization at a regional level, and the context awareness processes described before.</p><p>ever, this vision still has some drawbacks: on one hand, there is still a dependence on centralized entities for the staggered governance of resources, which can lead to bottlenecks and latency problems. By the same token, non-federated environments could simply benefi t from domain-focused monitoring, without trusted and third-party auditing procedures based on blockchain. For these reasons, there is no distributed intelligence that allows for autonomous and holistic decision making; nor do DTs control the productive process. In this case, the use of AI is reduced to threat analysis in localized areas, and policy redesign is mostly a manual procedure in the hands of auditors. Consequently, these aspects are expected to be tackled with a highly decentralized architecture, where DTs play a key role in adapting authorization to the dynamic environment instantly. This is addressed in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AutonoMous And rElIAnt dIgItAl twIns for long-tErM grId dEPloYMEnts</head><p>As the electric sector is embracing the digital age, the SG infrastructures are more infl uenced by value-added technologies to analyze data, carry out simulations, and ultimately optimize the energy management systems. This evolution will lead to a full hybridization of grids at an international/ regional level with local substation micro-grids focusing on consumer empowerment, which demands a more resilient, reliable, and efficient architecture. For this goal, while intelligent monitoring systems provide a fi rst semantic representation of the grid assets, DTs are needed to convey a more holistic socio-technical and process-oriented characterization of the environment by means of total synchronicity of the cyber-physical bi-directional data fl ows.</p><p>In order to present the characterization of DTs in the upcoming SG model, we first present its architecture, shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. This hyper-connected and totally decentralized model assumes that the barrier between energy generation, transmission, and distribution assets are blurred, and all processes coexist with micro-grids and electric vehicle (EV) infrastructures. Based on any application scenario, these resources are collaboratively used, and the information is compartmentalized and securely accessed by the corresponding stakeholders, who have flexible control over the legislation, energy management, and data acquisition. This is achieved with NFV-and SDN-based techniques, with little or no change to the physical infrastructure.</p><p>In a higher layer of abstraction over these physical devices, a blockchain-based authorization system handles the access to information and resource trading in communities, thereby avoiding the need for additional and coupled PDP computation nodes. The provisioning of the DLT nodes can be done by stakeholders on premises (e.g., microgrid owners, resident operators, utility administrators) or leveraging blockchain-as-a-service (BaaS) providers, hence cutting costs and increasing the scalability of resources.</p><p>Transversely to the end devices and the blockchain infrastructure deployed over the future grid, the presence of DTs must be holistic to achieve a symbiosis between physical assets and their virtualized entities. This means that the authorization and energy management processes must be integrated around the DT agents to implement fully distributed automation. This way, they play the proactive role of controlling resources over the grid, compared to the passive behavior (i.e., monitoring) presented earlier. This functionality is enabled by orchestrating MEC, fog, and cloud services at multiple architecture layers, which enables sensing of the physical, and having full interaction with the blockchain and the production line. The functionality loop between both worlds is provided by the data that connects them, so the DT agents act as transparent but operational proxies in this duality, as represented in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. It comprises four phases As the electric sector is embracing the digital age, the SG infrastructures are more infl uenced by value-added technologies to analyze data, carry out simulations, and ultimately optimize the energy management systems. Th is evolution will lead to full hybridization of grids at an international/regional level with local substation microgrids focusing on consumer empowerment, which demands a more resilient, reliable, and effi cient architecture.</p><p>that are executed permanently at high-frequency intervals.</p><p>Data Collection: Energy usage data and control information is retrieved in the proximity of IoT and end devices, leveraging the B5G infrastructure to carry out context awareness procedures.</p><p>Data Processing and Adjustment: As data is aggregated, further analysis and detection is performed to subsequently store such information in the ledger and execute additional maintenance tasks to inform potentially affected stakeholders.</p><p>Information Discovery: The DT subscribes to events on the blockchain that are related to its monitoring area (e.g., pricing information, demand response) in order to accelerate decision making and anticipate potential security issues that may render changes in the access to resources.</p><p>Control and Management: As aforementioned, the DT agents that are hierarchically spread over the SG infrastructure have full autonomy to manage its corresponding assets, without the need for vertical and centralized control.</p><p>Aside from sensors' information and control commands, authorization requests and responses pass through intermediate DT agents located in the edge, as depicted in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. These submit transactions to the ledger and relay the outputs back to the field devices using B5G communication, based on the existing policy and the cyber-security state assessed by the agents. Likewise, they can propose amendments to the access control scheme based on repetitive behaviors and past perceptions, as explained in the next section.</p><p>So far, we have presented the architectural side of the B5G-based SG for the future accommodation of DTs as the enabling factor of the distributed automation of processes. However, despite the emergent interest around this concept, the research within this field is still immature: many simulation applications have been used and re-branded as DTs, while some others lack precision for tailored environments or cannot escalate to potential nationwide agents <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Moreover, the core AI algorithms have a long road ahead until the com-pletion of self-reliant and self-learning agents. In the following, we review these challenges and provide useful insights for future R&amp;D milestones in this area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>chAllEngEs And oPtIMIzAtIons usIng AI tEchnologIEs: sElf-uPdAtE-tAblE AuthorIzAtIon PolIcIEs</head><p>Numerous challenges remain to drive the sophistication of DTs and enable application scenarios where the AI will play the leading role <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. Particularly, in the context of this article, we stress challenges belonging to four categories: technology integration, modeling, usability, and security and safety. These are summarized in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. We close this analysis by discussing the intelligent authorization policies.</p><p>Beginning with the commissioning of modern technologies, the main concerns revolve around the coordinated deployment of applications in the edge or fog to ensure data sharing between geographically dispersed environments (and incidentally avoid handover), and the need to speed up transaction processing in distributed ledger technology (DLT) structures to reduce the impact on control performance. The latter depends on upcoming advancements such as the concept of lightning networks (i.e., an extra layer to process private transactions between parties in a P2P fashion) or sidechains (i.e., secondary blockchains to offload bulky processing from the main one), besides lightweight consensus algorithms. Another issue consists of the privacy of customer data, which has also been addressed by using blockchain approaches, including private channels between peers <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. Also, as a consequence of the deep transition from legacy tools, this integration process must be supported by a gradual standardization effort. Telecommunication bodies, industrial committees, government entities, e-mobility investors, and cyber-security institutions are expected to join forces toward the sustainable development and harmonization of these technologies in society at an international level. In brief, Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> summarizes the advantages and constraints of every discussed technology in the scenario considered. With respect to implementation, modeling DTs imposes several improvements over well established simulation procedures in the industry. Despite the many approaches investigated in other fields, the SG requires an increased degree of precision in its business logic, ranging from small measurement and control elements to buildings, aggregators, and power plants at the national level. The main challenges to maintain synchronization between the physical resources and the DT representation are twofold: first, the variety, volume, and velocity of data to be processed online from multiple sources in order to create an accurate model; and second, the maintenance of virtual models as the actual equipment evolves over time. Enabling technologies to address these issues include data compression in B5G networks, hybrid techniques that combine physics-based modeling approaches (experimental and numerical), and data-driven approaches (by using readily available open resources) into reduced order models that can be efficiently handled at a greater computational speed <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. In these environments, the use of open, cross-platform communication protocols (e.g., OPC UA) is crucial for the acquisition of observations from heterogeneous devices and hence estimate the state of the physical system given a predefined model (i.e., data assimilation). This process can be accomplished by means of big data analytics and machine learning solutions allocated in the cloud or fog (e.g., compressed sensing and symbolic regression).</p><p>As for usability requirements, the interaction of the twin with the physical infrastructure can imply autonomous decisions made by the agent that must be interpretable by humans in a transparent way. This is ensured by means of explainable AI, providing users with timely and actionable information to manage the SG resources efficiently, and complying with legal and regulatory requirements. Fast interaction with augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR) is also key to support decision making, which can be aided by enhanced probabilistic and predictive recommender systems. Besides top-notch human-machine interfaces, voice communication and web apps are needed to provide the operators with holistic access and detailed visualization of assets.</p><p>The solutions outlined above assume that information security and safety are guaranteed in all scenarios. This requirement is met by various conditions. First, all grid operations are supervised by context awareness agents in the proximity of the affected devices (e.g., by leveraging apps deployed in the edge). Various distributed detection techniques can evaluate the security state of resources and accurately trace persistent attacks throughout the infrastructure. One of the most promising approaches is Opinion Dynamics <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>, a multi-agent algorithm that holistically correlates anomalies to report different alert indicators in real time. Second is the privacy of users and the security of data in transit and at rest. As mentioned above, this must be addressed by means of privacy-preserving techniques to collect and aggregate consumption information, coupled with cryptographic measures when this data is accessed and exchanged in the blockchain of a federated environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. Third, the grid is envisaged to effectively manage demand response to hold the power supply and anticipate high peaks to avoid potential blackouts. For this goal, the adoption of time series forecasting models or deep neural networks has been successful in forecasting residential load demand <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>.</p><p>Lastly, and returning to the starting point, the access control and authorization systems will acquire a greater influence from AI in the new DT prototypes for the SG. The provisioning of traditional policy schemes in industrial sectors require an initial static procedure to analyze the regulations applied, engineer the roles involved, establish permissions, and define rules for accessing resources or performing actions, considering precise constraints and relationships between assets. At the same time, these rules should be consistently declared to avoid conflicts, using an interoperable policy language such as XACML. However, such mechanisms will have to face an unsteady environment where a huge set of actors fluctuate and the information flow is massive. Consequently, policies will have to be continuously assessed for the entire set of domains in order to readjust them in real time depending on a wide range of social, economic, and security conditions to guarantee the continuity of the network <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Additionally, although decentralized authorization systems are more flexible than centralized decision points in terms of efficiency, they are harder to manage. Therefore, the administration of complex authorization systems is expected to progress toward more automated processes with scarce manual intervention. This fact is visible in our analysis of the transition from the medium-to long-term DTs regarding the authorization workflow, as Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> shows. Whereas the auditor has the last decision to manage the policies in the earlier approach, the latter does not need any human interaction. In this trend, we can classify the use of AI for intelligent authorization into two research lines.</p><p>Automatic Policy Alteration: The aim is to gain insight from previous access requests and the overall behavior of the system in order to refine existing rules. Data mining and classifi cation algorithms are useful to identify discrepancies in policy specifi cations and infer new properties. Also, such evaluation can be combined with time-constrained delegation models and domain-specific rules to derive authorizations in unforeseen scenarios <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. Altogether, they can help to automate confl ict resolution and role assignment, as well as to support implicit authorizations (i.e., accesses that are not explicitly specifi ed or granted) <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. Simultaneously, the complexity of the explicit authorization set is reduced.</p><p>The logic behind the analysis and improvement of security policies could ideally be implemented through smart contracts in the architecture proposed in the long-term analysis. This way, the DT agents distributed over the architecture would be in charge of auditing the policy correctness, so they would be able to submit transactions to propose upgrades to certain access control functions, which would then be approved by the consortium after being contrasted with other concerned peer agents.</p><p>Rule Learning: In this case, algorithms are trained to learn from data and infer policies rules from scratch. The most significant solutions here involve reinforcement learning. The traffic and events generated during the standard operation of the grid are studied to identify target resourc-es and infer trust relationships between users and assets, based on the anomalies encountered <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. The counter-side is that the system is exposed to potential security threats, as the learning process takes place progressively while accesses are made and optimal policy rules are barely applied. As such, these solutions are more appropriate in later stages of the authorization life cycle, when a base authorization model is enforced. Other alternatives to guide reinforcement learning consist of probabilistic policy reuse, which balances among the application of the dynamically learned policy, the exploration of random actions, and the use of past policies.</p><p>Due to the differences between automatic alteration and rule learning, a dynamic authorization system that is collaboratively maintained and upgraded by a decentralized architecture of DTs must fi nd a balance between these two approaches. Generally, the most common rationale will be to apply rule learning over a minimal set of policy regulations defi ned in the organization and to subsequently polish them with automatic alteration methods. Therefore, this process must be coupled with context awareness and auditing procedures to feed back the learning mechanisms and be fully integrated with the DT functionality loop of the previous section.</p><p>conclusIons <ref type="bibr">And</ref> </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>futurE chAllEngEs</head><p>In this article, we have carried out a prospective analysis of the future smart grid through the evolution of digital twins, and we have pointed out the most relevant challenges they face. Due to the aspirations of artificial intelligence and the role of recent computer and B5G communication technologies in this sector, these mechanisms are postulated as the guiding thread to drive the progress of the electricity grid toward a fully decentralized and autonomous model, governed by intelligent authorization systems. Ahead lies an arduous path that involves various efforts in terms of standardization and information security, in conjunction with deep research into machine The most common rationale will be to apply rule learning over a minimal set of policy regulations defined in the organization, to subsequently polish them with automatic alteration methods. Therefore, this process must be coupled with context awareness and auditing procedures to feed back the learning mechanisms and be fully integrated with the DT functionality loop of the previous section.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>FIGURE 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>FIGURE 1. B5G-enabled smart grid architecture for accommodating DTs in the medium term.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>FIGURE 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>FIGURE 2. B5G-enabled smart grid architecture for accommodating DTs in the long term.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>FIGURE 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>FIGURE 3. DT authorization workfl ow: a) medium term; b) long term.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>TABLE 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>AI-related challenges for the future digital twins in the smart grid.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Category</cell><cell>Challenge</cell><cell>Enabling technologies and solutions</cell></row><row><cell>Technology integration</cell><cell>Coordination of edge-distributed DT agents</cell><cell>Multi-cloud application delivery using fog/cloud services, handover prediction</cell></row><row><cell>and real-time performance</cell><cell>Low transaction processing rate in blockchain</cell><cell>Lightweight consensus algorithms, lightning networks, sidechains</cell></row><row><cell>Modeling and physical/</cell><cell>Real-time modeling and data processing</cell><cell>Hybrid analysis and modeling, reduced order modeling, multivariate data-driven models</cell></row><row><cell>virtual synchronization</cell><cell>Consistent and continuous model updates</cell><cell>Data assimilation, big data analytics, compressed sensing, symbolic regression</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Transparency and interpretability</cell><cell>Hybrid analysis and modeling, explainable artificial intelligence, DLT accounting</cell></row><row><cell>Usability</cell><cell></cell><cell>Aided decision making with Bayesian recommender systems, natural language processing,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Interaction with physical asset</cell><cell>enhanced human-machine interfaces (augmented reality and virtual reality), holistic web-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>based integration</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Global intrusion detection</cell><cell>Distributed detection frameworks, opinion dynamics</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Data privacy</cell><cell>Cryptography and blockchain private channels, group signatures, zero-knowledge protocols</cell></row><row><cell>Security and safety</cell><cell>Demand forecasting and fault prediction</cell><cell>Time series forecasting models like autoregressive integrated moving average (ARIMA) or deep learning architectures such as deep neural networks (DNNs), deep belief networks</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(DBNs), and recurrent neural networks (RNNs)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Authorization policy readjustment</cell><cell>Automatic alteration (classification, time-contrained delegation models, implicit authorization) and rule learning (reinforcement learning, probabilistic policy reuse)</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>TABLE 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Advantages and constraints of the future DT enabling technologies in the smart grid.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Technology</cell><cell>Medium term</cell><cell>Long term</cell><cell>Advantages</cell><cell>Drawbacks</cell></row><row><cell>B5G communication</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>Distributed and intelligent P2P automation, ultra-low latency, high-frequency data retrieval</cell><cell>Slow international rollout and integration in the industry</cell></row><row><cell>Mobile edge computing</cell><cell>∼</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>Accelerated context awareness services by means of computation offloading in the proximity to end users</cell><cell>Service allocation for multiple computing nodes, coordination of distributed DT agents</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Orchestration of scalable services at a regional or national</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Fog computing</cell><cell>∼</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>level, synchronization of physical/virtual entities across multiple</cell><cell>Complex data management and maintenance</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>domains, privacy control</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Cloud computing</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>Advanced data processing and policy readjustment, provisioning of blockchain nodes</cell><cell>Privacy implications due to ineffective data governance, availability and high-latency issues</cell></row><row><cell>Blockchain</cell><cell>∼</cell><cell>ü</cell><cell>Tamper-proof database across SG domains to store context awareness and access registers, decentralized authorization schemes, P2P energy trading</cell><cell>Low transaction speed rates, computation overhead</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">Authorized licensed use limited to: Oulu University. Downloaded on June 01,2021 at 09:02:12 UTC from IEEE Xplore. Restrictions apply.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AcknowlEdgMEnts</head><p>This work has been partially supported by the EU H2020-SU-ICT-03-2018 Project No. 830929 CyberSec4Europe (cybersec4europe.eu), the EU H2020-MSCA-RISE-2017 Project No. 777996 (SealedGRID), and a 2019 Leonardo Grant for Researchers and Cultural Creators of the BBVA Foundation. The second author has been partially financed by the Spanish Ministry of Education under the FPU program (FPU15/03213).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twin: Values, Challenges and Enablers From a Modeling Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rasheed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>San</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Kvamsdal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Access</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a Semantic Construction Digital Twin: Directions for Future Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Boje</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Automation in Construction</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">114</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">179</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">5G Networkbased Internet of Things for Demand Response in Smart Grid: A Survey on Application Potential</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied Energy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">257</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">972</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A P2P Network Based Edge Computing Smart Grid Model for Efficient Resources Coordination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Peer-to-Peer Networking and Applications</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fog Computing for Smart Grid Systems in the 5G Environment: Challenges and Solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kumari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Wireless Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blockchain-Assisted Access for Federated Smart Grid Domains: Coupling and Features</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Alcaraz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rubio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Lopez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Parallel and Distributed Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">144</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="135" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-06" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blockchain-Powered Value Creation in the 5G and Smart Grid Use Cases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Valtanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Backman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yrjölä</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Access</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">707</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intelligent Power Equipment Management Based on Distributed Context-Aware Inference in Smart Cities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Commun. Mag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">56</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212" to="217" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-07" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Applications of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning in Smart Cities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ullah</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Permissioned Blockchain and Edge Computing Empowered Privacy-Preserving Smart Grid Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Gai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Internet of Things J</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7992" to="8004" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tracking Apts in Industrial Ecosystems: A Proof of Concept</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Rubio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Computer Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="546" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-09" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Neural Ordinary Differential Equations Based Approach for Demand Forecasting within Power Grid Digital Twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Parlikad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Puri</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2019 IEEE Int&apos;l. Conf. Commun., Control, and Computing Technologies for Smart Grids</title>
				<meeting>2019 IEEE Int&apos;l. Conf. Commun., Control, and Computing Technologies for Smart Grids</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dynamic Access Control Policy Based on Blockchain and Machine Learning for the Internet of Things</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Outchakoucht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Hamza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Leroy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int&apos;l. J. Adv. Comp. Sci. Appl</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="424" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Data Classification Method for Inconsistency and Incompleteness Detection in Access Control Policy Sets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Shaikh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Adi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Logrippo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int&apos;l. J. Info. Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="113" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic Fine-Grained Access Control in Scada by Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Future Generation Computer Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="548" to="559" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">uma.es) is a full professor and head of the Network, Information and Computer Security (NICS) Lab at the University of Malaga, Spain. His research activities are mainly focused on network security, security protocols, and critical information infrastructures</title>
		<editor>Javier Lopez [SM] (jlm@lcc.</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>international research projects in those areas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">es) is a Ph.D. student at the University of Malaga, receiving funds from the Spanish Ministry of Education under the FPU program. He obtained his Bachelor&apos;s degree in computer science in 2014 and his Master&apos;s degree in computer science in 2016, both with distinction, from the same university. He has been a collaborator in the Department of Computer Science since 2013, and his research activities are focused on the protection of critical infrastructures and the analysis of cybersecurity threats</title>
		<editor>Juan e. rubio [StM] (rubio@lcc.uma</editor>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in the paradigm of Industry 4.0 and the Industrial Internet of Things</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Her main research interests include critical infrastructure protection, more specifically, the security of SCADA systems, cyber-physical systems, the Industrial Internet of Things, and digital twins, all of them applied in Industry 4.0, manufacturing and supply chain systems</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">uma.es) received her M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees in computer science from the University of Malaga in 2011 and 2006, respectively. She is an associate professor with the</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><surname>Cristina Alcaraz [m] (alcaraz@lcc</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Department of Computer Science, University of Malaga</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>and smart grids</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
