<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Systems Engineering Grand Challenges in Security and Safety</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
							<email>mcdermott@gatech.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Larry</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Strawser</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Daryl</forename><surname>Farber</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Yokell</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Walker</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia Institute of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Atlanta</settlement>
									<region>GA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Baltimore</settlement>
									<region>MD</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Pennsylvania State University</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>State College</addrLine>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country>USA M</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="laboratory">M. Walker BCT LLC, Annapolis Junction</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Yokell Lockheed Martin Corporation</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Fort Worth</addrLine>
									<region>TX, MD</region>
									<country>USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Systems Engineering Grand Challenges in Security and Safety</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-00114-8_14</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:45+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper describes the methodology and outcomes from a series of three workshops organized by the International Council of Systems Engineering (INCOSE) Academic Council. Distinguished systems engineering (SE) researchers and professionals from across the United States were invited to explore the global Grand Challenges from the SE perspective as related to security and safety, identify research gaps, and provide recommendations on closing those gaps. The paper begins by describing the concept of global Grand Challenges and the resultant workshop series. The paper goes on to describe how Workshop I defined the problem, how Workshop II defined the research gaps, and then how Workshop III developed the necessary research directions. The paper concludes by describing the recommended research threads to meet the Grand Challenges in systems engineering research relating to security and safety.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="14.1.1">Grand Challenges in Systems Engineering</head><p>The concept of global Grand Challenges can be used to focus technical, educational, and humanitarian efforts <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. In 2014, INCOSE developed a systems engineering vision for 2025 <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, which coupled societal needs to systems challenges and then to gaps in SE capabilities. Subsequently, the "INCOSE Systems Engineering Research Future" project <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> was initiated by the Academic Council of INCOSE, which used the framework of the SE Vision 2025. This project aimed to achieve the following objectives:</p><p>• Build communities among academia, industry, and government from numerous domains, dedicated to tackling the major global systems challenges confronting humankind for societal good. • Excite, inspire, and guide systems engineering research in these communities.</p><p>• Achieve consensus among these communities to establish the priorities of systems engineering research. • Provide the means by which to create synergy in these systems engineering research efforts such that progress can be measured against these objectives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="14.1.2">INCOSE Grand Challenge Workshop Series</head><p>This project produced a series of three workshops (October 2016, March 2017, and October 2017) with participants comprised of SE researchers and professionals from academia, industry, and government. The participants in the first workshop used the list of societal needs in the INCOSE SE Vision 2025 to select the following four Grand Challenges to be explored by the project: (1) access to education, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> access to healthcare, (3) access to clean water, and (4) security and safety. The first workshop also adopted the five desired characteristics of societal needs Grand Challenges first proposed by the National Council of Teachers of Mathematics and added a sixth as follows:</p><p>1. Represent complex and extremely difficult questions that are solvable (potentially within 10-20 years). 2. Improve quality of life through positive educational, social, and economic outcomes potentially affecting millions of people. 3. Involve multiple research projects across many subdisciplines to be satisfactorily addressed. 4. Require measurable outcomes so that progress and completion can be identified. 5. Compel popular support by encouraging the public to relate to, understand, and appreciate the outcomes of the effort. 6. Is systemic in nature. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="14.2">Problem Definition: Workshop I</head><p>The first workshop in the series set the stage for the four focus areas by selecting Grand Challenges from the SE Vision 2025 based on participant interest and identifying obstacles and relevant research questions. Security and safety was one of the four challenges selected, along with access to education, food, and clean water and access to healthcare. The full results of this workshop were previously documented <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, and the security and safety challenge is summarized here. The security and safety group identified two Grand Challenges, which were both derived from the National Association of Engineering (NAE) Grand Challenges "Prevent Nuclear Terror" and "Secure Cyberspace." These were generalized as two themes: "resilience to catastrophic events" and "systemic security." Resilience to catastrophic events represents the need for SE methods, processes, and tools that adequately capture both the system and its external context, in order to address systemic effects. Because such events are necessarily addressed by combined policy, economic, and technical strategies, future systems engineering tools must capture both technical and nontechnical solution sets. For systemic security, there is recognition that the traditional methods of hierarchical decomposition of structure and associated perimeter defense strategies must be supplemented by new/future perspectives, process-and scenario-driven approaches, and more emphasis on failure modes (cyber warfare, catastrophic events, unintended events, etc.). Future systems engineering tools and design techniques need to emphasize the implementation to consider the heterarchical nature of cyber systems and their context.</p><p>The workshop participants developed a set of short vision statements reflecting a future state of systems engineering in which we capture system security and safety value and risk metrics into all types of systems and all levels and phases of decision analysis:</p><p>• Future systems engineering will engineer system solutions at the speed of the threats we see today. • Systems will be designed to adapt to internal and external threats instead of reacting to them. • System models will underlie all design practices, capture all system behaviors, be adaptive, and be able to evaluate systemic effects both within the system and out to external use contexts. • Continuous experimentation with system vulnerabilities and threat scenarios (red and blue teams) will become a standard part of systems engineering at all phases of design, integration, test, and deployment. • Model-based systems knowledge of both the system and current context will always reflect the current states of the system and its history. • In order to make effective decisions, future systems engineering methods, processes, and tools will span the engineering, economics, human, and policy domains. • Best practices from systems engineering (technology and data driven) and engineering design (user experience driven) will be merged so that all systems balance solutions and external context drivers.</p><p>The following research questions were captured as an output of Workshop I:</p><p>1. How will SE categorize security and safety-related challenges if structural decomposition methods no longer work? 2. How will SE characterize capabilities and gaps in this domain? 3. What methods and tools will SE need to address simultaneously the human, physical, and informational aspects of the system? 4. Can SE address uncertainty in the system analysis process, particularly uncertainty of external system drivers? 5. How does one model real-time, realistic operational environments of changing systems and changing contexts? 6. How does one design governance methods for ensuring system security when the individual components are not secure, effectively emphasizing heterarchical system structures? 7. How does one "reverse engineer" the architecture of an existing system in order to learn its interfaces and potential vulnerabilities? Particularly brownfield systems (power grid, etc.)? 8. How does one measure what you don't know and plan to evolve as the system scales? 9. How does a system expose the necessary information to monitor system security in a private way? 10. How does one design a system to self-analyze failures and heal itself? 11. How can SE education engage the different domains at this level of design?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="14.3">Research Gaps: Workshop II</head><p>At the second workshop, the group derived a number of gaps in current SE processes, which need to be addressed to meet the envisioned future state:</p><p>1. Current SE processes often assume static life cycle models and do not address the rapid emergence cycles now being seen in both the cyber threat environment and in commercial system development processes. As a result safety and security analyses are not regularly updated, particularly in response to emergent threats. 2. The "VEE" model paradigm does not represent the use of or the need for continuous engineering and test strategies. There is not a current SE process that balances continuous development, integration, and test with incremental safety and security analyses. 3. Most systems don't have or consider self-healing capabilities that correct externally driven failure modes. There is not currently an effective process to value such capabilities as a trade study factor in system architecture decisions. 4. System abstractions as one moves up and down component tiers tend to become ingrained into static structural boundaries in the system design process. As a result dynamic threat exploitation across these boundaries is not considered after the design is frozen. Current SE processes do not support "dynamic" abstractions such as new system boundaries or behaviors that emerge as the result of unplanned external system exploitation. 5. SE methods and tools lack language commonality and support for combining multidisciplinary expertise when considering internal system boundaries and the changing external context as a common system definition. 6. SE does not explicitly consider methods and tools to address rapid emergence and scaling in information domains. System behaviors are increasingly determined by information that is provided or collected external to the system. This data is also subject to rapid changes and shifts in context. 7. Current SE safety and security methods do not represent "bad actors" within the system boundary as a general source of system failure. As protection or resilience to such failures could rapidly become unaffordable, holistic approaches to value protection or resilience functions based on system level criticality must be developed. 8. There are many ontological barriers that limit design team interaction and design methods in the physical system versus cybersecurity domain, and there are limited methods and tools to manage their interaction. The effects of cyberattacks have had minimal consideration to date in the design of cyber physical systems, and the value or utility of functions that provide resilience to cyberattacks is not well understood. 9. SE does not explicitly consider methods and tools to encode ethical decisionmaking into the system operational capabilities. Systems these days are often faced with ethical choices, and the design community does not have the methods to support system trades associated with these attributes (often resulting in agnostic response to ethical dilemmas). 10. There is a need for rapid synthesis of data/information from both physical components and all data (IT) sources to information needed for decision-makers at all levels of the organization(s). This included data from the lowest level sensors on up and all data/IT sources. Rapid information development and dissemination are critical. 11. System design must include physical protections for catastrophic events that can cause catastrophic failures over wide areas of the earth. These include solar, nuclear, and cyber.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="14.4">Research Directions: Workshop III</head><p>Workshops I and II produced a consistent view of SE challenges and needs in a world where the external context of safety and security is subject to much more rapid changes, and a much larger set of threats than previous SE processes, methods, and tools were designed to support. As with many other SE attributes, there is a need to shift from more efficient to more flexible, resilient practices, designs, and decisions, as well as to more fully consider the sociotechnical implications of systems and their context. Workshop III used the identified research questions and gaps to discuss potential research directions. These are not exhaustive but intended to serve future discussions. The following six research threads were identified as important to security and safety of future systems.</p><p>1. Increasingly dynamic context. Methods and processes that bring more agility to development and certification of critical systems should be a focus of future SE research. In the systems development process, agile "build-measure-learn" processes must have an accompanying agile "build-audit-control" model that goes beyond user stories and considers safety and security oversight of the development and modification processes. MIT's System-Theoretic Accident Model and Processes (STAMP) is an example of such research <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. In addition, the emphasis of initial safety and security scenarios development prior to design is essential to work with customers and establish the basis for system design initiatives. SE life cycle models need to be adaptive to emerging threats from outside the system, such as cyberattacks, climate changes, economic shifts, political shifts, etc. One mental model for future systems is the "pipeline to platform approach"systems that are built to endure (platforms)/built to change (apps) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. The community needs to address more generalized architectures and specialized functions, systems that are designed to be invulnerable but can be rapidly fixed. This includes methods and tools in the system-of-systems domain that address platform-to-platform interactions.</p><p>Future SE processes need to support "dynamic abstractions" that can adequately deal with changing system boundaries. As today's systems mature, boundary relationships shift, but the abstractions used to design and measure system performance remain static. We need system models and simulations that reflect emergence between boundaries, changes in data flows, performance, and system languages/mathematical constructs that combine disciplines and methodologies.</p><p>2. Human-machine interaction, bad actors, and trust. Methods are needed to formally address human-machine interaction, not as static use cases but as "human-machine conversations." SE focuses on the human as the purposeful user of the machine, and ignores in the development process all other human interactions-including threats. Formal models of trust need to be developed within both intended and non-intended interactions, which require an integration of human activity models with system models. SE assurance methods must consider malicious actors within the system boundary-the insider threat. SE must consider countering modes and effects that emerge from these actors. This means that systems must be aware of their human actors (both good and bad) and monitor combined human and machine behaviors as part of their assurance design <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. These are interactions between physical and data/informational processes. As these will be complex relationships, graph theoretic methods might be explored in addition to continuous monitoring of these interfaces for threat-related activities/changes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3.</head><p>Modeling societal and organizational context. Modeling and simulation must encode the societal context and impacts of solutions as tradespace alternatives.</p><p>Architectures that can simulate post-conditions of a deployed system and feed that back into the model are needed. This will change how we instrument systems, shifting collection of data toward measures that are critical constructs of the system model (often called the digital twin). Models and simulations that interact with larger models and simulations of social context are also needed. Future SE tools that model "noise" from signals and erroneous information versus encoded truth may become useful when modeled at the system and system-ofsystems level. All of these needs imply a shift from modeling "the system" toward modeling the system and the external context it resides in, in both environment and timeframe <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13]</ref>.</p><p>The need for organizations and management to fund and support the continuous evolution of system models throughout their life cycle is essential for these changes to be captured and understood. Rapid and agile system evolution requires the equivalent rapid updating of the system models. This is needed in a SoS with many operational and in development systems, otherwise chaos results along with wasted time and funds. Note that the threats to systems will continue to evolve rapidly; the models, design changes, and implementations must be evolving in an equal or more rapid manner.</p><p>In the future it will be useful to integrate system models with narrative scenarios as a bridge between the system and its sociotechnical context. Future tools should extract meaning from text and formal representations of situations or concepts of operations (CONOPs)-using key constructs and concepts-that capture both the structure and meaning that result. This will require advances in machine learning methods and tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. Future SE tools need to partially or fully automate model building by observing system behaviors and combining these observations with linked knowledge.</p><p>CONOPs and their related scenarios, requirements, system models, designs, processes, etc. need to be continuously updated and available to developers, maintainers, management, etc. to assure that all personnel that manage, develop, and support the system(s) have access to current information for their decision needs. CONOPs (Operational Concept Documents) should be computer based to allow rapid updating of the scenarios, etc. and changes that reflect the need for design updates, etc.; this is essential for cyber security/software in addition to other failure mode impacts, process changes, physical changes, and other future safety and security challenges. 4. Heterarchy, adaptive learning, and emergence. System-of-systems research must advance, and research is needed particularly in the domain of human and autonomous systems, where machines will soon join the ranks with humans as drivers of complex adaptive behaviors. These systems must assure security and safety, as well as other attributes like ethics and social responsibility. There is a general need for the SE community to embrace heterarchical models of complex systems and create methods and tools that allow heterarchical processes to be addressed in system requirements, architectures, design, and process evolution. New modeling and simulation frameworks should be designed to evaluate effective design principles that address trust and scalability in both the system-system and human-system dimensions, thereby increasing their operational utility. Most existing SE methods/processes assume hierarchical decomposition strategies, which are not incorrect but are insufficient for future systems. Even systems-ofsystems research lacks a framework to address systems that learn and adapt themselves. SE methods that explicitly consider adaptive learning and emergence must be developed to manage the complexity of future cyber-enabled systems and automated human-machine systems. Both human-machine and independent machinemachine adaptation are important. Current approaches to mitigate these challenges have been isolated within traditional simulation formulations and environments and associated siloed scientific disciplines; most typically pure engineering fields are insufficient to address the nature of the problem space. The community needs to develop the foundations for an integrated "social" systems science. This will lead to a more relevant fundamental study and characterization of the "social behavior of complex and autonomous systems" and unintended consequences of these behaviors (whether constructive or in conflict). This needs to lead to the development of new scenarios development concepts and content to drive the future systems designs. 5. Self-healing systems and condition-based adaptation. Research is needed on methods that automate the healing process of a compromised system <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. Breakthroughs may come from biological-inspired processes for sensing, classifying, and recovering health, related research on "effectors" of these recoveries, methods to encode these change effectors into system components, methods and means to create system self-learning by immersing the system in different environments, multi-stage models, and simulation methods for such systems. Future systems should be able to define and then sense preconditions of abnormal operations at any level. Research is needed on how to model this information, particularly for nonphysical processes. Research is also needed on how to capture the information on external conditions and use it to train adaptive models. These preconditions need to be updated throughout the system's life cycle and also be reflected in the CONOP scenarios, use cases, models, data flows, etc. automatically along with identifying system design/development needed changes. 6. Libraries, patterns, and model sharing. Like software, system models are abstractions of physical phenomena. SE methods and tools should capture these abstractions as basic functions supporting standard system models that are created from shared libraries that reflect normally used functions and communications <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17]</ref>. This would help increase both the efficiency of the design activities and the resilience of new systems, drawing from the history of other successful systems. Due to the complexity of systems today and with even greater complexity expected in the future, the SE community must develop and share both functional and formal design patterns that can be used to compose new system models and designs. Functional patterns are necessary early in the design process when architectural decisions are being made, to reduce errors in requirements. Formal methods are needed to assure the as-designed system is free from errors of construction. The SE community should lead the development of complex system modeling federations for sharing data and associated research and design processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Metamodeling needs to become a natural SE research and design skill.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="14.5">Common Directions Across Grand Challenge Areas</head><p>As was discussed in Sect. 14.1, in addition to the security and safety Grand Challenge, three other Grand Challenges were explored by the Academic Council: clean water, healthcare, and education. In similar fashion to the security and safety Grand Challenge, the key problems and research threads for each of these were identified, followed by identification of current gaps in SE research and suggested topics for future SE research. Although each of these Grand Challenges identified specific topics for SE research relevant to their specific challenge, there were three major necessary SE research areas common to all four Grand Challenges:</p><p>• SE research is needed to understand the human element in developing the system and the deployed system. • With the increasing dynamic context, research is needed on the role of SE in developing self-adaptive, evolving, and self-sustaining systems. • Study is needed to determine the role of SE in human factors by researching models of long-term sociotechnical systems to address culture-and value-based decisions.</p><p>Each of these research areas should be addressed from the perspective of engineering systems, which according to Kossiakoff et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> is:</p><p>A broader and robust perspective to systems approaches to solve very extensive complex engineering problems by integrating engineering, management, and social science approaches using advanced modeling methodologies . . . . The intent is to tackle some of society's grandest challenges with significant global impact by investigating ways in which engineering systems behave and interact with one another including social, economic, and environmental factors. This approach encompasses engineering, social science, and management processes without the implied rigidity of systems engineering.</p><p>Acknowledgments The authors would like to acknowledge the contributions and support from the INCOSE Academic Forum and from the other participants in the three Grand Challenges in systems engineering workshops. </p></div>		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grand challenges and opportunities in mathematics education research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Stephan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Fish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Chval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Herbel-Eisenmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wanko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Konold</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal for Research in Mathematics Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grand challenges in global health</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Varmus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Klausner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Zerhouni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Acharya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Daar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Singer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">302</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5644</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="398" to="399" />
			<date type="published" when="2003" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Grand challenges for engineering</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.engineeringchallenges.org" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008-01" />
			<biblScope unit="page">18</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>National Academy of Engineering.</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Internet</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grand challenges for social work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Uehara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Flynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Fong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brekke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Barth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Coulton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Society for Social Work and Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="165" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Agency for International Development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.usaid.gov" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Grand challenges for development</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Global grand challenges</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.raeng.org.uk/publications/other/ggcs-report" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Institution of Engineering and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A world in motion: Systems engineering vision 2025</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Friedenthal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Beihoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Oster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Paredis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Stoewer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014" />
			<pubPlace>San Diego, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Council on Systems Engineering</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Future systems engineering research directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Wade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Adcock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Strawser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Disciplinary convergence in systems engineering research</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Madni</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Boehm</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Ghanem</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Erwin</surname></persName>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wheaton</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1165" to="1179" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://psas.scripts.mit.edu/home/" />
		<title level="m">MIT Partnership for a Systems Approach to Safety</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pipelines, platforms, and the new rules of strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Van Alstyne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Choudery</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Business Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2016-04" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">System-aware cyber security: A systems engineering approach for enhancing cyber security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Horowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Lucero</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">INCOSE INSIGHT</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Considerations for an extended framework for interactive Epoch-Era analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Systems Engineering Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>13th Conference on</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward next generation social analytics: A platform for analysis of quantitative, qualitative, geospatial, and temporal factors of community resilience</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Folds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hutto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal on Advances in Internet Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1-2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="70" to="86" />
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computational narrative intelligence: Past, present, and future. Medium</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://medium.com/@mark_riedl/computational-narrative-intelligence-past-present-and-future-99e58cf25ffa/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-10-24" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-healing systems-Survey and synthesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ghosh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Sharman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Upadhyaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Decision Support Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2164" to="2185" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Basis set exchange: A community database for computational sciences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Schuchardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Didier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Elsethagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Gurumoorthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1021/ci600510j</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1021/ci600510j" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Chemical Information and Modeling</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1045" to="1052" />
			<date type="published" when="2007" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A functional basis for engineering design: Reconciling and evolving previous efforts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hirtz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Stone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mcadams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Szykman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Research in Engineering Design</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kossiakoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sweet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Biemer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Systems engineering principles and practice</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Hoboken, NJ</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="34" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
