<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Towards Cybersecurity of the Smart Grid using Digital Twins</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Juan</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Olivares-Rojas</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Enrique</forename><surname>Reyes-Archundia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">José</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Gutiérrez-Gnecchi</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ismael</forename><surname>Molina-Moreno</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Cerda-Jacobo</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Arturo</forename><surname>Méndez</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Patiño</forename><surname>Tecnológico</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Nacional</forename><surname>De México</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Morelia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Tecnológico Nacional de México / I. T. Morelia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Tecnológico Nacional de México / I. T. Morelia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Tecnológico Nacional de México / I. T. Morelia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Tecnológico Nacional de México / I. T. Morelia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">Tecnológico Nacional de México / I. T. Morelia</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Towards Cybersecurity of the Smart Grid using Digital Twins</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MIC.2021.3063674</idno>
					<note type="submission">This article has been accepted for publication in a future issue of this journal, but has not been fully edited. Content may change prior to final publication. Citation information: DOI 10.1109/MIC.2021.3063674, IEEE Internet Computing This article has been accepted for publication in a future issue of this journal, but has not been fully edited. Content may change prior to final publication. Citation information: DOI 10.1109/MIC.2021.3063674, IEEE Internet Computing</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:47+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The proliferation of cyber-physical systems is bringing with it the growing need to link these systems with virtual environments. Particularly in the smart grid, the high costs of some devices and especially the imminent need to not be able to manipulate these devices in production environments make necessary mechanisms that allow the manipulation of these physical objects in virtual environments; this has been called a digital twin. On the other hand, cyberattacks are growing in all cyber-physical systems, and in the smart grid, cybersecurity is essential due to the smart grid is a critical infrastructure. This work shows a small implementation of a digital twin system for smart metering systems in a smart home environment for testing cybersecurity issues. The results show that the use of digital twins is feasible in various contexts of the smart grid in particularly in cybersecurity testing.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>¢ INTRODUCTION Due to the increasing digitization of human activities derived from Industry 4.0 Technologies, various areas have been revolutionized; one of them it is the Power Sector generating what is called Energy 4.0 or Smart Grid (SG). The SG is characterized by the use of technologies in the areas of information, consumption, and operation, which allows better management in the processes of utilities, which translates into improvements in the use of end-users, among other things <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>The SG allows utilities to generate, transmit, distribute, consume and commercialize electrical energy in a reliable, environmentally friendly, and economically sustainable manner; it also allows them to automate operations such as outages and reconnections, as well as to monitor the state of the electrical network. For end-users, it will enable them to visualize their patterns of consumption/production of electrical energy, allowing them to make better decisions regarding the use of electrical power and its costs <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>.</p><p>A fundamental part of the SG is the Smart Metering System (SMS), which transversally involves almost all the SG processes. The cornerstone of SMI is the Smart Meter (SM), which is considered an Special Issue on Digital Twins Editor: Patrick Henz, Roberto Saracco, ic3-2021@computer.org</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Internet Computing</head><p>Internet of Things (IoT) device for its data communication and processing capabilities. SM can interact with Smart Appliances (SA) in homes by using the same electrical cable in what is called Power Line Telecommunications (PLT) or through wireless sensor technologies. The combination of these technologies gives rise to the concept of Smart Home (SH) <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>One of the main concerns in SH and SMS is the cybersecurity. The proliferation of IoT devices in SH carries out a lot of threats and cyber-attacks, and if these IoT devices are not well-protected must compromise their information due to their vulnerabilities <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>Being able to interact for testing cybersecurity with SA, SM, and other devices in SH becomes difficult in many cases due to the cost of physical devices and not being able to stop the current environment for testing <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. In the past, simulations were performed with specialized software to recreate general working conditions. Unfortunately, simulations in many cases did not represent the virtual world in the right way. To improve these simulations so that they present a closer environment to the real one, various simulators have been created in real-time, which are integrated into physical devices through a Power Hardware-In-the-Loop (PHIL) interface <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, allowing simulate physical objects with virtual elements through simulation software.</p><p>Recently, the concept of Digital Twins (DT) has emerged that allows the interaction between physical and virtual objects, considering a virtual object as a replica of the physical object allowing both to interact as if it were one. DT brings enormous advantages since the physical world interacts in the same way with the virtual world, altering any change in the reality of the two worlds <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>.</p><p>With the modeling of systems through DT, significant benefits can be obtained in all areas and particularly in the SG, and the SMS is no exception, allowing saving costs and improving decision-making processes.</p><p>This work presents the design and implementation of a DT applied to the SG. Since the SG is pervasive, the work is limited to the SMS and its interrelation with devices in the home.</p><p>The paper is organized as follows. Section 2 shows a review of the literature regarding the topic of DT applied to SG. Section 3 shows the design and implementation of a DT for SMS in the SH area.</p><p>Section 4 shows the results obtained, while section 5 shows the conclusions and future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STATE OF THE ART</head><p>The use of DT has been around for a few years as a concept and derived from the so-called fourthgeneration industrial systems. Its use has been extended to various areas of engineering, mainly in manufacturing systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p><p>At SG, the DT have mainly focused on various areas such as security, data analytics, and machine learning, simulation of intelligent electronic devices, among others <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>.</p><p>The development of DT involves the modeling of each physical object with its virtual object so that they can share common characteristics, in turn, it is necessary to have data communication systems between physical objects, as well as a concentrating interface that allows visualization and control virtual and physical environment operations <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>The most extensive use of DT in SG has been within the cybersecurity area. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> shows an intelligent implementation of a DT in microgrids, which are autonomous electrical networks that operate in small communities and that include power generation systems generally distributed through photovoltaic panels or wind turbines.</p><p>The aspect of cybersecurity modeling in cyberphysical systems like SG is of vital importance since modeling attacks under test conditions is extremely difficult in operational environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. For this reason, in <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, a review of the state of the art of cybersecurity of cyber-physical systems in Industry 4.0 systems is shown.</p><p>Finally, the area of most significant application today of DT is the area of machine learning and information processing. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> shows the use of DT in the SG demand forecast. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>, the use of DT to understand human behavior using deep learning techniques is shown. <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> shows the use of machine learning to improve processes within the chemical industry.</p><p>As can be seen in the literature, the use of DT within SMS, particularly within the SH area, is still limited.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DESIGN AND IMPLEMENTATION OF A DT FOR SMS</head><p>We develop a DT Framework mainly composed of a DT Controller. The DT Framework Controller (DTFC) is responsible for mapping real objects with its virtual representation, exchange values between DT, notify events and alarms between all the objects, and simulate cyber threats and attacks. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref> shows the uses cases describe above of the DTFC.</p><p>In general terms, an SMS is mainly composed of SM in the premises of the end-users, Data Concentrator (DC) that concentrates the SM consumption/production data, and Metering Database Management System (MDMS) Server which concentrates all the information recollected by DC. These components are connected used wired and wireless telecommunications means.</p><p>This work is focused on the Home Area Network (HAN) which is similar to a Local Area Network (LAN) restricted geographically into a household and it is composed of SM, appliances, and SA. Designing an SMS DT requires physical mapping objects such as appliances with the SM. The SM used is made up of a Raspberry Pi Model 3B + board with the use of a SmartPi power data acquisition card. The SM uses a Linux Raspbian distribution, so its mapping is direct with the DT driver. In the case of household appliances, a WiFi communication module, and processing of electrical variables has been added through an Arduino microcontroller and current and voltage sensors. Additionally, a temperature sensor and a potentiometer have been added to control an appliance to switch on or change speeds. For the implementation of the system, SM DT, a 6-type iron, and a 4-speed blender were modeled.</p><p>DT architecture is shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref>. It can be seen that there are six objects. Three of the physical worlds represented by the initial letter P and that are iron, blender, and SM. Each physical object has its identical virtual component represented by the initial letter V. Home appliances in the physical world have a Processing and Communications Module (PCM), which allows mapping with its tangible counterpart through the DT controller. The core of the architecture is the DT controller, which concentrates information from physical objects with virtual objects to map any changes. Communication is made both ways, and with all objects, both physical and virtual. We can note that there are particular identification data and values that represent each of the data. In the case of SM, position 0 of the potentiometer indicates the device is turned off, while the other positions indicate variables of electrical energy that it is wanting to monitor. In the case of the blender, the states of the potentiometer indicate the different speeds, while on the iron, they indicate types of clothes for ironing. The heat of the iron is monitored with the temperature sensor.</p><p>For each physical object, it is necessary a mapping process to obtain a virtual object. The JSON object represents a virtual object and can be added manual or discovered by the DT controller.</p><p>The implementation of the DT is made in python due to its simplicity and high portability with other platforms. Each physical object has an IP address configured and is registered in the controller through data mapping. Once changes have occurred, they are displayed on the DT interface and reflected on both the physical and virtual objects.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Internet Computing</head><p>The readers can note that communication between physical objects is directed. It is no necessary modification in the physical system. In this case, SMS works as normal and interact with another SA. The communication between virtual objects is directly through the DT platform. The DT controller is responsible of communicate the changes of virtual objects to the physical and vice versa. Also, the DT controller is always monitoring the interaction between physical and virtual objects and reflects the changes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>TESTING CYBERSECURITY OF SMS USING DIGITAL TWINS</head><p>Cybersecurity threats are vast <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> and have diverse countermeasures to mitigate risks. The DT platform can detect some cyber threats such as sensor attack, spoof-node attack, hardware manipulation attack, energy manipulation attack, sniffing, Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS), sensitive data leakage, and fault tolerance. Each type of threat is described below and how the DT platform can help test SH cybersecurity.</p><p>Sensor attack Each registered device in the platform must register each sensor. The DT platform records the sensor data of each device in a historical database. The DT platform monitors this historical data and sends an alarm if the sensor has a probable anomalous behavior that can be considered as a possible attack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Spoof attack</head><p>Each registered device in the platform register and unique ID take of hardware feature. The DT platform monitors this unique ID continuously and avoids a possible spoof device.</p><p>Hardware manipulation attack Each registered device in the platform must verify in their PCM a security process responsible for checking all hardware components if they are connected or disconnected.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Energy manipulation attack</head><p>Similar to sensor attack, the DT platform monitors the historical consumption of each registered device. If the consumption varies in an outlier value, a notification is sent to the user.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sniffing attack</head><p>The DT platform always monitors the network connection of all registered devices, both physical and virtual. When a new connection is detected, the DT platform records the new connection and notify the users. The communication between physical and virtual objects are ciphered using RSA signatures.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack</head><p>The DT platform has an embedded firewall responsible for verifying network connections. Only the registered devices both, physical and virtual, can connect each one. The DT platform records the frequency of communication of each device and notifies the users of abnormal use.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sensitive and data leakage (SDL) attack</head><p>The DT platform only permits registered and authorized devices to see and export the information. The DT platform required to grant permission to access sensitive data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Fault tolerance</head><p>The bottleneck in centralized systems is the server process, in our case, the DT controller. The DT platform can connect with other DT controllers as a backup. When the DT platform detects a failure, if exists an auxiliary DT controller, the auxiliary controller is switched as a new DT controller. The auxiliary DT controllers check the database with the whole information updated.</p><p>We developed a cybersecurity scenario for testing cybersecurity aspects in SH. The testing scenario is related to tampering with data in a physical and logical way. The testing scenario takes into account the diverse attacks and threats mentioned above in this section.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref> shows the different attacks used in the tampering testing scenario. The readers can observe that both and physical and virtual objects are tested. We run the scenario of tampering data100 times, obtaining the results described in Table <ref type="table">I</ref>.</p><p>Table <ref type="table">I</ref>  The readers can observe that most of the cases are 100% secure. Only the sensor and energy manipulation attacks have a percentage distinct of 100%. These attacks have a non-linear behavior due to that components are based on their historical records of the use of each sensor/energy and it is difficult to detect if an abnormal could be considered as an attack.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSIONS AND FUTURE WORK</head><p>DT development is a necessity today in any cyberphysical system. Particularly in the SG, its use is necessary for all its areas, particularly in the SMS, it would allow better modeling and development of SH. This work shows that the implementation of a DT system for use in SG is feasible and it can aim to protect physical devices through virtual devices interactions.</p><p>The cybersecurity is a vital aspect in any DT implementation, and for SG is crucial to protect SMS, SH, and another IoT devices. For this reason, the cybersecurity heuristics of this work must be improved.</p><p>As future works, it is intended to build a DT display and controller system with a Graphical User Interface (GUI) as well as expand the catalog of physical objects within SH.</p><p>Other important aspects of cybersecurity in DT must be checked such as avoid points of failure, data confidentiality issues, troubleshooting and speed recovery, orchestration issues, and policy definition issues, among others.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Use case diagram of a DT Framework Controller.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Architecture of the DT prototype for SMS in SH.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3. Tampering testing Scenario.</figDesc></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">This article has been accepted for publication in a future issue of this journal, but has not been fully edited. Content may change prior to final publication.Citation information: DOI 10.1109/MIC.2021.3063674, IEEE Internet Computing</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENT</head><p>This work is partial supported by Tecnológico Nacional de México under grants 7948.20-P and 8000. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20</ref> </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Energy 4.0: Towards IoT Applications in Kazakhstan</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Satuyeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.procs.2019.04.126</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Procedia Computer Science</title>
				<meeting>edia Computer Science</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">151</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="909" to="915" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A survey on smart grid technologies and applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Dileep</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.renene.2019.08.092</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2589" to="2625" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in Renewable Energy, 146</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Survey on Home Energy Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Leitão</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ACCESS.2019.2963502</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Access</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5699" to="5722" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Security in Cyber-Enabled Design and Manufacturing: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Chaduvula</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1115/1.4040341</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ASME Journal pf Computing and Information Science in Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smart Residential Load Simulator for Energy Management in Smart Grids</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>López</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/TIE.2018.2818666</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Transactions on Industrial Electronics</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1443" to="1452" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Real-time test-bed system development using power hardware-in-the-loop (PHIL) simulation technique for reliability test of DC nano grid</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Heo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s43236-020-00075-x</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Power Electronics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="784" to="793" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twin: Enabling Technologies, Challenges and Open Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Fuller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.2998358</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Access, 2020</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twin for Variation Management: A General Framework and Identification of Industrial Challenges Related to the Implementation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wärmefjord</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/app10103342</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Applied Sciences</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2020</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cyber Twins Approach for Smart Grids</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Senrhilnatan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annapoorani</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://smartgrid.ieee.org/newsletters/november-2019/cyber-twin-approach-for-smart-grids" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">#:~:text=The%20cyber%20twin%20model%20is,netwo rk%20under%20various%20operating%20conditions</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IEEE Smart Grid Newsletter</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Digital Twins Approach to Smart Grid Security Testing and Standardization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Atalay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Angin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MetroInd4.0IoT48571.2020.9138264</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2020 IEEE International Workshop on Metrology for Industry 4.0 &amp; IoT</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Roma, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="435" to="440" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ANGEL: An Intelligent Digital Twin Framework for Microgrid Security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Danilczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/NAPS46351.2019.9000371</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2019 North American Power Symposium (NAPS)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Wichita, KS, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Digital Twin for Cyber-Physical Energy Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Pileggi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MSCPES.2019.8738792</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2019 7th Workshop on Modeling and Simulation of Cyber-Physical Energy Systems (MSCPES)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Montreal, QC, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twins and Cyber-Physical Systems toward Smart Manufacturing and Industry 4.0: Correlation and Comparison</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>|tao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.eng.2019.01.014</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">in Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="653" to="661" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Digital Twins for Cyber-Physical Systems Security: State of the Art and Outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ekelhart</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-25312-7_14</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Security and Quality in Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chapter Ten -Impact of cloud security in digital twin</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Susila</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/bs.adcom.2019.09.005</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Advances in Computers</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">117</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="247" to="273" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Neural Ordinary Differential Equations Based Approach for Demand Forecasting within Power Grid Digital Twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Xie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/SmartGridComm.2019.8909789</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2019 IEEE International Conference on Communications, Control, and Computing Technologies for Smart Grids (SmartGridComm)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Beijing, China</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital twins in human understanding: a deep learning-based method to recognize personality traits</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/0951192X.2020.1757155</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Computer Integrated Manufacturing</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine Learning based Digital Twin Framework for Production Optimization in Petrochemical Industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><surname>Min</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2019.05.020</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Information Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="502" to="519" />
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smart Meter Data Privacy: A Survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Asghar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/COMST.2017.2720195</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Communications Surveys &amp; Tutorials</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2820" to="2835" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrusion Detection for Cybersecurity of Smart Meters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/TSG.2020.3010230</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE Transactions on Smart Grid</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
