<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Trustworthy Digital Twins in the Industrial Internet of Things with Blockchain</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2021-05-19">19 May 2021</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sabah</forename><surname>Suhail</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Rasheed</forename><surname>Hussain</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Raja</forename><surname>Jurdak</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Choong</forename><forename type="middle">Seon</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Trustworthy Digital Twins in the Industrial Internet of Things with Blockchain</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="j" type="main">IEEE Internet Computing</title>
						<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Internet Comput.</title>
						<idno type="ISSN">1089-7801</idno>
						<idno type="eISSN">1941-0131</idno>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="1"/>
							<date type="published" when="2021-05-19">19 May 2021</date>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1109/mic.2021.3059320</idno>
					<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:2105.08886v1[cs.CR]</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T12:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The proliferation of digitization and complexity of connectivity in Cyber-Physical Systems (CPSs) calls for a mechanism that can evaluate the functionality and security of critical infrastructures. In this regard, Digital Twins (DTs) are revolutionizing the CPSs. Driven by asset-centric data, DTs are virtual replicas of physical systems that mirror every facet of a product or process and can provide actionable insights through monitoring, optimization, and prediction. Furthermore, replication and simulation modes in DTs can prevent and detect security flaws in the CPS without obstructing the ongoing operations of the live system. However, such benefits of DTs are based on an assumption about data trust, integrity, and security. Data trustworthiness is considered to be more critical when it comes to the integration and interoperability of multiple components or sub-components among different DTs owned by multiple stakeholders to provide an aggregated view of the complex physical system. Moreover, analyzing the huge volume of data for creating actionable insights in real-time is another critical requirement that demands automation. This article focuses on securing CPSs by integrating Artificial Intelligence (AI) and blockchain for intelligent and trusted DTs. We envision an AIaided blockchain-based DT framework that can ensure anomaly prevention and detection in addition to responding against novel attack vectors in parallel with the normal ongoing operations of the live systems. We discuss the applicability of the proposed framework for the automotive industry as a CPS use case. Finally, we identify challenges that impede the implementation of intelligence-driven architectures in CPS.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I. INTRODUCTION</head><p>In the paradigm of Industry 4.0, the traditional Industrial Control Systems (ICS) that include operational technology (OT) is increasingly integrated with general-purpose Information Technology (IT) systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Whereas integrating IT and OT systems in Cyber-Physical Systems (CPSs) provides promising solutions in a plethora of ubiquitous industrial ecosystems, it introduces novel attack vectors <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Usually, operational functionality outweighs security. Furthermore, if addressed at all, security is often added retrospectively during the operation phase of the asset rather than at the initial design phase. Thus, loopholes in the system infrastructure enable the attackers to launch a multitude of complex cyber-attacks. Such attacks not only highly degrade the overall system performance but have catastrophic consequences on human safety and life.</p><p>Considering the proliferation of digitization and complexity of connectivity, essential measures to fortify CPS involve S. Suhail and C. S. Hong are with Kyung Hee University, Korea. R. Matulevičius is with University of Tartu, Estonia. R. Jurdak is with Queensland University of Technology, Australia.</p><p>(1) evaluating the functionality of critical infrastructures, <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> assessing the security level by identifying vulnerabilities, and (3) conducting security attacks. Therefore, online solutions that accurately reflect the actual CPS in operation must be deployed while avoiding any interference or implications of testing on live systems. In this regard, Intrusion Detection System (IDS) (signature-or anomaly-based) is a promising approach to uncover malicious activities by identifying deviations or patterns from a defined benign behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. However, false alarms may raise safety concerns, and attack scenarios are hard to reproduce. Another potential solution involves deploying testbeds as a controllable cyber prototype for testing functional requirements and operational behavior of the system; nevertheless, a testbed setup and maintenance can be time-and cost-intensive <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. Most importantly, attackers may harm system infrastructure due to delayed countermeasures as mere detection of attacks by these solutions is of limited use. Moreover, such solutions may not cover the entire lifecycle of the product.</p><p>Considering the involvement of multiple participating entities throughout the lifecycle of physical resources, the key question is how to ensure the trustworthiness of data collated from disparate data sources <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>? To establish a trustworthy framework for the CPSs throughout the product lifecycle phases (including design and development; operation and maintenance; and decommissioning), blockchain-based Digital Twins (DTs) are one of the promising candidates. During industrial processes, DTs collect and integrate data from multiple sources, such as sensor and actuator data from the factory floor, historical production data derived from product lifecycle data, and domain knowledge to generate comprehensive data in the form of models, simulations, replications, or behavioral analytics. Following a closed-loop, the simulation data are fed back to the physical object to adopt better calibration and testing strategies that further evolve DT models and physical counterparts to support optimized processes. Additionally, utilizing blockchain allows lifecycle stakeholders (i.e., owner, manufacturers, distributors, and maintainers) to manage data on a shared distributed ledger to solve important challenges in traceability such as procuring complete lineage of DTs ranging from their origin to the present state. Thus, combining DTs and blockchain can reshape the industry where blockchain ensures secure data management and DTs use trustworthy data as input to extract actionable insights for predictive maintenance <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>Considering the complexity of cyber-physical data (including logging and resource monitoring events), the overarching question is how to automate cyber situational awareness while providing online threat intelligence (TI)? To ensure sustainable protection against attacks, it is necessary to automate the process of extracting TI and evidence-based insights from data sources. While keeping up with the complexity and adaptability of current cybersecurity threats, Artificial Intelligence (AI)driven security solutions provide autonomic security solutions to detect zero-day threats <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. In this regard, we orchestrate intelligence-driven solutions (such as data analytics and TI) along with blockchain-based DTs that can help to identify existing vulnerabilities, faulty models, malicious actors, and potential attack vectors, thereby minimizing the threat landscape and improving the CPS.</p><p>In this article, we propose an AI-aided blockchain-based DT framework (shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>) to secure CPSs. Our main contributions are as follows:</p><p>• To secure CPSs, in addition to DTs, we leverage TI that can analyze the huge volume of data for creating actionable insights in real-time, detect the presence of malicious or inadvertent disruptions in the system, and can invoke the appropriate defense mechanisms autonomously. • We discuss the feasibility of the proposed framework for the automotive industry as a CPS use case. In the following section, we envision a blockchain-based DTs framework for securing CPSs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>II. SECURING CYBER-PHYSICAL SYSTEMS THROUGH DIGITAL TWINS: A SECURITY BY DESIGN APPROACH</head><p>Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> represents the detailed working of the main components of the proposed framework presented in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>. The framework comprises four key components including (i) physical asset and its replica, (ii) data integration and interoperability, (iii) blockchain ledger, and (iv) threat intelligence (TI). The physical asset and its clone counterpart must be constantly connected through the data sync method to continuously perform the digital-physical mapping between the pre-defined system performance parameters retrieved from the storage, and real-time sensor data from the manufacturing unit, to verify data consistency. The modes of DTs (simulation and replication) that support monitoring and replaying of CPS events are part of this component. The data integration and interoperability is responsible for cleaning invalid, duplicate, or missing data, converting heterogeneous data formats into a unified data structure, and aggregates data to generate a consistent interpretation of a certain object before inputting data into the physical space. The blockchain ledger enforces secure data management by storing data and recalling events. TI identifies vulnerabilities, threat actors, existing and potential attack vectors to minimize the threat landscape. We divide the data flow throughout the system into three types of processes: (1) the initial input is provided to the data wrangler and data fusion methods; (2) to stay consistent with the requirement of the underlying application, the continuous process updates the data or state based on a defined time period; and (3) the system-specific process is scheduled based on the underlying events or triggered depending on cyber situational awareness of the CPSs.</p><p>The steps shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> can be summarized as follows:</p><p>The participating entities (such as sensors, machines, and humans) register as authorized entities at the blockchain (step 1). The multimodal and heterogeneous sensors or actuator data from physical assets (step 2a) and system-specific input knowledge such as engineering and domain knowledge (step 2b) are cleaned and converted to a unified format at the data wrangler. The data from multiple sources, for instance, auxiliary data (step 3a), multiple DTs data (step 3b), and unified sensory data (step 3c) is aggregated by data fusion and is inputted to the physical asset to support consistent and comprehensive representation of data. (step 3d). To facilitate track and trace solutions, the provenance data is recorded on the ledger (step 4). During the process, any essential data (such as Safety &amp; Security (S&amp;S) rules) can be accessed by the blockchain (step 5). Based on the continuous digitalphysical mapping (step 6a and 6b) through data sync, the replication mode records and replays the states or events (step 6c) from the physical environment for tracking data consistencies. To secure the CPS from attacks, TI accesses data from data sync (through replication mode steps 7a) and DT (through simulation mode (steps 7b) to observe the data patterns. Depending on the data anomalies or uncertain data inconsistencies, alerts are generated (steps 7a) and the corresponding scheduling services (in the physical space) or model calibration services (in the virtual space) carry out the necessary measures such as configuring the machine settings based on tool wear data or energy consumption, or tuning model parameters to simulate the physical counterpart with high fidelity. The simulation mode operates independently of the physical space and can be used to monitor and update the twin (step 8). The updated models upon calibration (step 9a) and S&amp;S rules must be stored and retrieved from the ledger to ensure their reliability (step 9b) and thus strengthen the rationale for integrating blockchain with DTs.</p><p>In the following, we discuss each component of the TI-aided blockchain-based DT framework in detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A. Data Integration and Interoperability</head><p>The integration and interoperability of data from multimodal and heterogeneous sensors are significant prerequisites of DT implementation. This process begins by inputting sensory data from physical assets to the data wrangler. In our proposed framework, the data wrangler is responsible for cleaning invalid, duplicate, or missing data, converting heterogeneous data formats into a unified data structure. AIenabled data curation helps in improving the data quality by implementing intelligent automated methods to fill in the missing data and to clean the data (such as data denoising, data de-duplication) <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. While stringent security guarantees are inherited from the blockchain, ensuring the trustworthiness of data-generating sources is equally important for critical infrastructures. Therefore, three-fold integrity checking mechanism (engineering knowledge and domain knowledge) is established by: (i) collecting data only from registered devices; (ii) crossvalidating the device data with overlapping fields of view by comparing it pre-defined device performance parameters under threshold monitoring settings; and (iii) minimizing the age of information (AoI) to ensure the freshness of data. Given that blockchain mechanisms do not guarantee the trustworthiness of data at the origin, we can rely on utilizing a blockchainbased layered trust architecture <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref> for sensor data crossvalidation. Engineering knowledge describes the design specifications of the underlying CPS: (i) system-level components (specifying device configuration details and control logic), (ii) network-level information (specifying topology and communication path through logical connections and endpoints), and (iii) the relationship among components (specifying processlevel data aggregation, fine-grained policies and constraints). Such explicit definitions of the technical, topological, and control artifacts can help to generate the network setup of the virtual environment <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Furthermore, such engineering knowledge can also serve as a basis for implicit security rules. For instance, defining a safe state based on normal operations of devices or specific services provided by the process, deriving a whitelist from network-level monitoring based on the authorized addressing and routing information, detecting unknown devices or unidentified connections, identifying abnormal changes in the control logic, etc. In addition to these measures, IoT sensors are calibrated periodically for ageing management and fault diagnosis at the initial stages of data collection. In addition to specifying engineering knowledge, the framework also includes domain-specific knowledge from experts in various fields such as engineers (electrical, mechanical, instrumentation and control), supply chain entities, security professionals, etc. Once generated, the domain knowledge can be used as a reference by different organizations and can be tailored to meet their specific needs.</p><p>Next, to facilitate an abstract view of overall phenomena, DTs must support the correlation of different DTs associated with different physical sub-components. For this purpose, the unified data and the aggregated data from multiple DTs or replicas through composability is accumulated at data fusion. Moreover, auxiliary data (such as supply chain data) can also be provided. Finally, the fused data is inputted back to the physical asset to carry out the physical-digital mapping through data sync. Thus, data interoperability and integration provide a more consistent, comprehensive, and accurate representation than the single perspective of data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B. Blockchain Empowered Digital Twins</head><p>Although DTs provide powerful means to control, govern, and program the lifecycle of physical resources for supporting the provision of product servitization to end-users, these benefits of DTs are based on an assumption about data trust, integrity, and security. Data trustworthiness is considered to be more critical when it comes to the integration and interoperability of multiple components or sub-components among different DTs to provide an aggregated view of the complex physical system. Nevertheless, in real-life scenarios, data breaches could occur due to several reasons, both maliciously or mistakenly <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Therefore, curating and mining actionable insights from the collected data calls for a data storage infrastructure that can manifest the dissemination of trustworthy and secure data <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. In this regard, provenanceenabled blockchain-based DTs can facilitate digital identity and data traceability from disparate data repositories while reasoning about the current state and the chained actions on a data object (such as who, when, where, and how), thereby ensuring trustworthy DTs throughout the product lifecycle <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>Next, the deciding factor is what should be stored on the blockchain while ensuring efficient retrieval of data from lightweight, scalable, and quantum-immune blockchain. In addition to application-or user-specific requirements, datadriven CPS primarily depends on (i) which data is critical, and (ii) which data (or sources) can facilitate track and trace solutions. In our blockchain-based DT framework, we limit the frequent time-consuming access to the blockchain-based storage system by explicitly separating the real-time dynamic (or behavioral) data and the less dynamic (or static) data <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. This strategy is adopted due to the fact that the real-time data evolves frequently with each lifecycle phase and usually amass in intervals ranging from minutes to milliseconds, such as deployed sensors and actuators data providing asset's actual state, while static data changes infrequently with time along the lifecycle of the real-world counterpart, such as provenance data, system historical data, device configuration settings, access levels, and policies.</p><p>In the following, we discuss safety and security (S&amp;S) rules, one of the significant and critical components for securing CPSs through the blockchain-based DT framework.</p><p>S&amp;S rules are generated based on threshold data (upper and lower bounds), consistency checks (pre-defined performance parameters), and fine-and coarse-grained constraints (data accessibility and auditability based on ownership, roles, and access levels). S&amp;S rules can be defined at device-level, such as device configuration details, pre-defined performance parameters, network-level, such as topology, communication path, or process-level, such as data aggregation, relationship between entities. S&amp;S rules support monitoring the actions and events of the participating entities inside the virtual environment, thereby supplementing safety instrumented systems (SIS). Safety rules, for instance, conditional limits for device data (e.g., minimum and maximum temperature), trends/patterns (e.g., excessive vibration or heat, consistency checks (speedvariable), etc. and security rules, for instance, data integrity, access control (authentication and authorization), or correlation of different DTs associated with different physical subcomponents can be stated and integrated. Such IT/OT-system specifications are represented by means of standardized data formats, such as Automation Markup Language (AML), that consider the syntactical and semantic levels to describe the data objects <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p><p>Malicious or accidental, S&amp;S rules must be integrated to detect misconfigurations and to mitigate the outcomes of malfunctioning components and malicious activities in a CPS. Inability to impose such rules leads to devastating results on the system in the form of cyberattacks or Advanced Persistent Threats (APT), for instance, Stuxnet worm and Triton. Furthermore, introducing S&amp;S rules at the design phase can help to lower security and incident-response costs, thereby making later lifecycle phases less prone to errors and incidents <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Depending on the cyber situation, S&amp;S rules can be updated either during or after the operation or process. For instance, in any abnormal event during the ongoing process, the system needs to respond effectively and update the corresponding S&amp;S rules to avoid long-term loss. To strengthen the rationale for integrating blockchain with DTs, the S&amp;S rules must be stored and retrieved from the ledger to ensure their reliability. For instance, a provenance-aware blockchain-based system can track and trace the accountable entity for adding or updating the S&amp;S rules.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C. Threat Intelligence (TI)</head><p>The following questions must be answered to support the reason for combining DT security-operation modes and TI:</p><p>(1) why we need TI in the presence of DTs for predictive maintenance? <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> how to analyze the huge volume of data for creating actionable insights in real-time? and (3) how to ensure integrity and trustworthiness of data collected from the physical world that are then fed into the DTs? Firstly, creating future scenarios, particularly in the absence of direct observation data, is challenging for DTs <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. To predict anomaly detection and perform risk assessment, the predictive capability of Machine Learning (ML) algorithms available through the TI module can play a key role. Thus, TI can provide additional support for DTs to secure CPSs.</p><p>Secondly, the quality of the data matters at par with quantity for ensuring precise predictions and decision-making. Such requirement matters more in the presence of a complex and ever-changing threat landscape and high volume, velocity, and heterogeneous variety of big data. Therefore, we propose a TI module that can learn useful patterns from the collected big data to prevent/detect anomalies and to predict the system behavior in course of disruptions or thwart the attack cycle. Furthermore, the TI module can be integrated into the organizational security management framework, such as Security Information and Event Management (SIEM), to deduce and to check the adherence of security rules. Thirdly, blockchainbased DTs governed by TI can preempt and detect the presence of malicious or mistaken disruptions in the system and can invoke the appropriate defense mechanisms automatically <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. Data-driven TI exploits data from DTs security-operation modes to achieve predictive powers (as shown in Fig <ref type="figure">3</ref>). In the following, we explore how DT security-operation modes operate in combination with TI and under which settings such modes are desirable?</p><p>The replication mode provides digital tracing of real-world events by mirroring data from the physical environment. For replication mode, DTs and their physical counterparts must be constantly connected in a sense that virtual replica must continuously reflect the physical object through log files, sensor measurements, network communication, etc. Depending on the application requirements, data can be collected from the physical space after a certain time interval or even offline.</p><p>The replication mode along with TI can serve as a training and testing platform to improve the stability, performance, and security of infrastructures while operating virtually in an isolated environment disjointed from live systems. Through DTs, attack scenarios can be simulated to analyze system behavior under attack. Collecting data over the course of such events can help to derive patterns to be formulated, tested, and transmitted to real-world systems. Moreover, DTs can aid security professionals by providing red-blue team exercises for cybersecurity training opportunities (i.e., offensive red team launch attacks to uncover system weaknesses while defensive blue team implements adequate solutions). Similarly, DTs in combination with cyber ranges (i.e., virtual environments that provide hands-on cyber skills and security posture testing) can be used to launch attacks against DTs from the cyber range for training and testing purposes <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p><p>Despite various advantages of replication mode, the timedependent record and replay of states may not create future scenarios. Furthermore, practically state replication accuracy depends on the trade-off between budget and fidelity <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. For real-time scenarios, ML predictive capability provided by TI supports DTs. To do so, TI access data from data sync. The reason for accessing data from this module is that it mirrors the sync states of both physical and virtual objects, hence can analyze the behavior of both spaces. Now, based on the inputted parameters that are mapped to the training data, TI learns about the presence of an attack or abnormal situations, and hence generates S&amp;S rules. These rules are then verified on the testing data. In the case of a known threat or attack, alerts are triggered to take further actions, such as executing S&amp;S rules to activate the corresponding mitigation strategies. In the case of an unknown threat or attack, TI may not be able to generate an alarm instantly. Such prediction errors are caused due to model errors coupled with the bias in the data. Under such circumstances, depending on attack intensity, either the device or network log data can be analyzed to identify the root cause of attacks or switched-off the affected device or service. Later on, S&amp;S rules can be created or updated accordingly. While TI predicts existing and potential threats, data sync can also retrieve data from TI to figure out the reason for data inconsistencies.</p><p>The simulation mode runs independently of its physical counterparts. In addition to being reproducible, this mode allows running tests repeatedly by resetting the model through a broad range of specified conditions to support the comprehension of emergent system behavior. The simulation mode supports security by design approach through which it facilitates analyzing process changes, test devices, or detect misconfigurations by performing security tests within the virtual environment. Furthermore, together with TI, it can predict the possibility of attacks or system malfunctioning (i.e., risk assessment) to carry out what-if and cost-benefit analysis.</p><p>While DT security-operation modes offer a variety of advantages, they may pose limitations. For replication mode, synchronization issues between the physical object and its different replicas and the need for input knowledge (events) in advance to produce the same stimuli are required. Similarly, for simulation mode, since the current physical state of the system is not known, hence it has to rely on user-specified settings and parameters. Considering these shortcomings, TI provides auxiliary support for predictive maintenance. Thus, DT security-operation modes together with TI can gain in-sights into the root cause that led the system to unexpected behavior.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>III. A CPS USE CASE: FROM DESIGN TO DISMISSAL</head><p>This section discusses the automotive industry as a CPS use case while mapping them to our proposed framework.</p><p>Before starting the production process, the necessary production details, such as supply chain data, i.e., consignment information, order information, i.e., material stock, production quantity, simulation data, i.e., equipment historical data, prediction of equipment fault, Enterprise Information System data, i.e., product life-cycle data, process document, etc., can be acquired from the storage system for usage (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> step 3a). Additionally, data related to integrity checking mechanism (engineering and domain knowledge) can also be retrieved from the blockchain (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> step 2b), thereby creating a trustworthy manufacturing environment for initiating the production process.</p><p>During the production process, for dynamic job-shop scheduling, machine unavailability (due to machine faults or equipment deterioration) and uncertain disturbances (due to job tardiness or urgent job arrival) usually cause performance deterioration or even production disruption <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. In this regard, DT-based intelligent manufacturing plays a significant role in production optimization problems through fault diagnosis and performance degradation prognosis. For instance, to minimize the makespan and production cost, DTs keep monitoring and analyzing the physical machine's current status based on constraints such as tool wear data, machine performance in the ongoing process, etc. Hence DTs can predict the suitable time for machine maintenance or triggering timely rescheduling, thereby avoiding business and economic setbacks.</p><p>Monitoring the spatio-temporal resolution of system state through time, outliers, and changes can aid in identifying anomalies or malicious activities by enabling the detection of possible S&amp;S rules violations. Therefore, to analyze the relationships between the dynamic variables and historical variables based on thresholds and consistency checks, we can rely on replication and simulation mode. For instance, on the automotive shop floor, the assemblage of vehicle parts performed by a robotic arm must be monitored and configured first based on simulation settings artifacts to deal with incident handling (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2 step 8</ref>). The incident data (including log data, provenance data, etc.) can evaluate the risk assessment in terms of detection reliability and severity to enable incident investigation through the simulation mode. Based on the incident data produced by DT-based security simulation, S&amp;S rules are constructed or improved and finally are updated at blockchain (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2 step 9b</ref>). Thus, enforced through S&amp;S rules, such proactive strategy can help detect safety-or security-related attacks instantly during the actual manufacturing of vehicles and hence can radically reduce maintenance overheads to alleviate product defects and support secure and trusted manufacturing.</p><p>Another example scenario is the conveyor system in the automotive industry. The velocity of the conveyor system, which is driven by the motor, must be monitored against a certain threshold (defined in S&amp;S rules) to avoid attacks (such as Man-in-the-Middle attack) targeting the manipulation of the conveyor speed. Through the replication of states to DTs by incorporating real-time data from live CPS (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> step 6a, 6b, and 6c), the intrusion prevention and detection mechanism (IPS &amp; IDS) at TI continuously monitor the behavior of ongoing operations for any rule violations (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> step 7a and 7b). However, in the course of advanced stealthy attacks, S&amp;S rules might be limited to detecting known misbehavior. Therefore, TI can analyze security and log data to identify potential threats.</p><p>The process of collecting and analyzing data continues even after the vehicle production process. To optimize operational control, fault diagnostics, and prognostic health management, the sensors attached to the connected vehicle (such as camera, GPS, infrared detectors, etc.) collect data during or after the drive. Following a synergic and continuous interaction between the prototype and the asset, the accumulated data is then fed to the DTs, which self-adapts to the asset and extracts new knowledge for model calibration for the next production processes. Furthermore, such data can be used by TI to study the adversarial space and to update S&amp;S rules for advanced attacks. The proposed framework can be significantly beneficial for the safe (or fail-safe) operation of autonomous vehicles where safety and reliability are highly deemed. The dismissal of the object is followed by the decommissioning of the DT because of obsolescence or other reasons.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>IV. CONCLUSION AND OUTLOOK</head><p>This article focuses on securing CPSs by integrating TI and blockchain for intelligent and trusted DTs. To enforce cyber reconnaissance, we devise a TI-aided blockchain-based DT framework that can ensure anomaly prevention and detection in addition to responding against novel attack vectors before putting the physical assets in the live systems. Furthermore, the proposed framework adopts DT security-operation modes in combination with TI for predictive maintenance and enhancing the resilience of the CPS against attacks.</p><p>Implementing intelligence-driven architectures enables greater visibility of cyber threats and minimizes the threat landscape; however, it necessitates methodological and theoretical solutions to address longstanding challenges. For instance,</p><p>• Due to the black-box nature of AI models, decisions made by the resulting systems suffer from a loss of transparency and comprehensibility, hence can lead to a negative impact on the trustworthiness of the system <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>.</p><p>Hesitation is even higher in safety-critical CPSs where explainability becomes crucial as slight dysfunction of AIbased systems may lead to erroneous decisions resulting in endangering human life or economic disaster. • After deployment in the real world, ML models are expected to perform deftly on unseen testing data. However, CPS underpinned by AI are vulnerable to adversarial perturbations under which wrongdoers try to morph its adversarial input data to augment the misclassification rate in the ML model. Attackers may begin with AI reconnaissance (i.e., observe the model's behavior and learn the decision logic or knowledge bases to morph the malicious payloads) and, without being detected, can feed their adversarial data to launch data exfiltration attacks. More concretely, democratizing AI is a double-edged sword. On the one hand, lack of transparency of ML predictive models require the removal of the opaqueness of AI models by explaining their inner working. However, on the other hand, complete transparency into the inner working of AI models may expose them to adversarial attacks by allowing them to make inferences from live cyber data or executing model poisoning into the training workflows.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Overview of the proposed framework.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Securing Cyber-Physical Systems: A blockchain-based DT framework.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>DT Security-Operation Modes Machine Learning</head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Simulation data, Replication data</cell><cell>Trigger alerts</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Threat Intelligence</cell><cell>and Incident response</cell></row><row><cell>Blockchain</cell><cell>Engineering knowledge,</cell><cell>Predict threat events and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Domain knowledge, System historical data,</cell><cell>Generate/update S&amp;S rules</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Provenance data,</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>S&amp;S rules</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>SIEM Figure 3. Overview of threat intelligence module.</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unleashing the Digital Twin&apos;s Potential for ICS Security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marietheres</forename><surname>Dietz</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-6885-4622</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gunther</forename><surname>Pernul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/msec.2019.2961650</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Security &amp; Privacy</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Secur. Privacy</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1540-7993</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1558-4046</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-07" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trustworthy Digital Twins in the Industrial Internet of Things with Blockchain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sabah</forename><surname>Suhail</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rasheed</forename><surname>Hussain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raja</forename><surname>Jurdak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Choong</forename><forename type="middle">Seon</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/mic.2021.3059320</idno>
		<idno type="arXiv">arXiv:1709.10000</idno>
		<ptr target="https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11585" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Internet Computing</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Internet Comput.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1089-7801</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1941-0131</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="1" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intrusion detection system: A comprehensive review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hung-Jen</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chun-Hung</forename><surname>Richard Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ying-Chih</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kuang-Yuan</forename><surname>Tung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jnca.2012.09.004</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Network and Computer Applications</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Journal of Network and Computer Applications</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1084-8045</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2013-01" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twins for Cyber-Physical Systems Security: State of the Art and Outlook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Ekelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-25312-7_14</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Security and Quality in Cyber-Physical Systems Engineering</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="383" to="412" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trustworthy Digital Twins in the Industrial Internet of Things with Blockchain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sabah</forename><surname>Suhail</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rasheed</forename><surname>Hussain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raja</forename><surname>Jurdak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Choong</forename><forename type="middle">Seon</forename><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/mic.2021.3059320</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Internet Computing</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Internet Comput.</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1089-7801</idno>
		<idno type="ISSNe">1941-0131</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="1" />
			<date type="published" when="2021" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Challenges of Leveraging Threat Intelligence to Stop Data Breaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amani</forename><surname>Ibrahim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dhananjay</forename><surname>Thiruvady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean-Guy</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohamed</forename><surname>Abdelrazek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fcomp.2020.00036</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/fcomp.2020.00036" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Computer Science</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Front. Comput. Sci.</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2624-9898</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">36</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-28" />
			<publisher>Frontiers Media SA</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A trust architecture for blockchain in IoT</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Volkan</forename><surname>Dedeoglu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raja</forename><surname>Jurdak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guntur</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Putra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ali</forename><surname>Dorri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Salil</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Kanhere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3360774.3360822</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3360774.3360822" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services</title>
				<meeting>the 16th EAI International Conference on Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019-11-12" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="190" to="199" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Security-Aware Virtual Environments for Digital Twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthias</forename><surname>Eckhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Ekelhart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3198458.3198464</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical System Security</title>
				<meeting>the 4th ACM Workshop on Cyber-Physical System Security<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-05-22" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="72" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twin: Values, Challenges and Enablers From a Modeling Perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adil</forename><surname>Rasheed</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0003-2690-983X</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Omer</forename><surname>San</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-2241-4648</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Trond</forename><surname>Kvamsdal</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-1615-7649</idno>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/access.2020.2970143</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Access</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">IEEE Access</title>
		<idno type="ISSNe">2169-3536</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21980" to="22012" />
			<date type="published" when="2020" />
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CyberFactory#1 — Securing the industry 4.0 with cyber-ranges and digital twins</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adrien</forename><surname>Becue</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yannick</forename><surname>Fourastier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><surname>Praca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexandre</forename><surname>Savarit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claude</forename><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Baptiste</forename><surname>Gradussofs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Etienne</forename><surname>Pouille</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carsten</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/wfcs.2018.8402377</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2018 14th IEEE International Workshop on Factory Communication Systems (WFCS)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-06" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deriving a Cost-Effective Digital Twin of an ICS to Facilitate Security Evaluation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Bitton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tomer</forename><surname>Gluck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Orly</forename><surname>Stan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Masaki</forename><surname>Inokuchi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoshinobu</forename><surname>Ohta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoshiyuki</forename><surname>Yamada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tomohiko</forename><surname>Yagyu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuval</forename><surname>Elovici</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asaf</forename><surname>Shabtai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-99073-6_26</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computer Security</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cham</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="533" to="554" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Twin Enhanced Dynamic Job-Shop Scheduling</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Meng</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-2253-4025</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Tao</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-9020-0633</idno>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Y C</forename><surname>Nee</surname></persName>
			<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-1029-9988</idno>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jmsy.2020.04.008</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Manufacturing Systems</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Journal of Manufacturing Systems</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0278-6125</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="156" />
			<date type="published" when="2021-01" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>digital Twin towards Smart Manufacturing and Industry 4.0</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">&quot;Do you trust me?&quot;</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katharina</forename><surname>Weitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Schiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruben</forename><surname>Schlagowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tobias</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elisabeth</forename><surname>André</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3308532.3329441</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th ACM International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents</title>
				<meeting>the 19th ACM International Conference on Intelligent Virtual Agents<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="9" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Security and Privacy Issues in Internet of Things</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liehuang</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Keke</forename><surname>Gai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Meng</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-21766-2_3</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Blockchain Technology in Internet of Things</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="29" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Contact her at sabah@khu.ac.kr</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online Value Co-Creation in the Healthcare Service Ecosystem: A Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Atae</forename><forename type="middle">Rezaei</forename><surname>Aghdam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hasti</forename><surname>Ziaimatin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5130/acis2018.cf</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Australasian Conference on Information Systems 2018</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>University of Technology, Sydney</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Raja Jurdak is a professor at Queensland University of Technology</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Contact him at r.jurdak@qut.edu.au</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Domain Model for Information Systems Security Risk Management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raimundas</forename><surname>Matulevičius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-61717-6_2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Fundamentals of Secure System Modelling</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="30" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Raimundas Matulevičius is a professor at University of Tartu</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Contact him at raimundas.matulevicius@ut.ee</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Effects of Smartphone Use on Structured Social Network Types among Retired Older Adults in South Korea</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sa</forename><forename type="middle">Rang</forename><surname>Um</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eun</forename><forename type="middle">Young</forename><surname>Chio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sung</forename><forename type="middle">Eun</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">In</forename><forename type="middle">Jung</forename><surname>Chio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Young</forename><forename type="middle">Sun</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.31888/jkgs.2018.38.3.481</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Korea Gerontological Society</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Korea Gerontol Soc</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">1225-1356</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="499" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-08-30" />
			<publisher>Korea Gerontological Society</publisher>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Choong Seon Hong is a professor at Kyung Hee University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Contact him at cshong@khu.ac.kr</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
