<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
				<availability status="unknown"><p>Copyright Springer International Publishing</p>
				</availability>
				<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bharat</forename><surname>Vagadia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Part III Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization Disruptive Applications Data Processing and AI Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization Data Capture and Distribution Data Connectivity: Telecommunications and Internet of Things C</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<title level="m">Future of Business and Finance</title>
						<idno type="ISSN">2662-2467</idno>
						<idno type="eISSN">2662-2475</idno>
						<imprint>
							<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
							<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="176"/>
							<date type="published" when="2020" />
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-030-54494-2_5</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.6.2" ident="GROBID" when="2021-06-09T13:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Data is the lifeblood within the digital ecosystem and more broadly the economies of the future. Whilst there is increasing focus on data protection (e.g. the EU General Data Protection Regulation 'GDPR'), the broader role of data in enabling the development and growth of a convergent ecosystem has only recently been brought into sharp focus. Artificial intelligence, virtual reality, augmented reality, as well as many applications used in the digital environment require vast amounts of data inputs (sometime diverse sets of data that may be geographically dispersed) and vast computing resources to process these.</p><p>When I talk about data, I'm referring to any form of information; text, speech, video, structured and unstructured data. The value of such data is generated by a number of factors, including: ease of access, ease of use, providence of the data, its accuracy, its ability to be distributed to a wider stakeholder base and their ability to disseminate and aggregate the data as they see fit.</p><p>This section details the key developments in terms of data integrity, control and tokenization, looking specifically at Ecommerce, digital identity, security, encryption and cryptography, digital signatures, Blockchains, smart contracts, token economics and data privacy, as these are key technological developments that are important to deliver data integrity, trust and security that customers, policy makers and regulators demand.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Data Value and Tradability</head><p>Creating an ecosystem for data collection, distribution, usage and adequate value creation requires an ecosystem for the data itself. Just as public utilities, such as power and telecommunications have significant positive externalities as more people use them, data could be seen in a similar context. In an environment where Artificial Intelligence (AI) can have profound impacts on society, it can be socially disadvantageous to have data monoliths that control access to such data and possibly use such data to create less desirable outcomes for society.  This should however not mean that data is freely given away. In order to create an data ecosystem, it requires a framework where individuals and organisations are provided both incentives and safeguards for them to provide access to data they may own, or control.</p><p>Governments are, or should be, increasingly looking at understanding the data value chain and facilitating data exchange platforms that enable the exchange of data between data providers and data acquirers. The data value chain must also be fully cognisant of the need to protect the privacy of personal data. Today, we have an incredibly diverse set of data that is being generated and most if not all, is being used by entities without the actual data subject being aware of its value. Some of the data is being created by individuals and a lot of it is being created by firms, who again like individuals cannot determine its value. As we move forward into the digitally disruptive era, more and more data will be generated through IOT, which itself may have value that is socially and economically good for it to be shared more widely. Without incentives for such data owners/controllers, the data may be kept in silos or hoarded-thereby reducing its true economic value.</p><p>Digital monopolies including Facebook, Google and Amazon, get data from users for free. Every like, search and purchase feeds the learning system to further improve the algorithms; in turn bringing more customers and engagement. Digital monopolies are searching for more and more data to feed their algorithms. Facebook buying WhatsApp and Instagram. Google with self-driving cars and Google Home and Amazon with Alexa Echos and Dots, are all attempts to gather more and more data.</p><p>Whilst monetisation of personal data from each individual may not amount to much and be too small for anyone to care about, given the economies of scale and data aggregation ability of these digital giants, they can extract considerable value from such data.</p><p>One way to solve this asymmetry of value is the creation of a marketplace for buying and selling data. A data exchange would create a business model for sharing data. Individuals can sell it instead of giving it away for free; organisations can monetise it instead of letting it sit idle on databases; and machines can buy and sell data automatically to increase their utility. Individuals may be able to choose which of their particular data is sold, rented or leased for a time bound period.</p><p>Given the non-rival nature of data (i.e. multiple uses of the same data does not deplete its intrinsic value unlike physical goods), companies and researchers should be incentivised to contribute and tap into such data exchanges, with great potential for value creation. These exchanges would also address information asymmetries that particularly affect small and medium enterprises, which are often unaware of the potential of the data they hold or could have access to.</p><p>Data exchanges could stimulate market competition more broadly in the data ecosystem by providing companies with the means to challenge multinationals' power in data markets. As this data commons grows with more datasets, it will attract more data buyers, creating powerful network effects. A platform based data exchange can also enforce data quality standards, ownership and usage rules, as well as paying sellers to rent or sell their data. As data becomes more valuable (and being capable of being monetised), advances in data processing techniques and other 'lean' and 'augmented' data learning techniques will accelerate. We may not need for example, a whole fleet of autonomous cars on the road to generate data about how they'll act. A few cars, plus sophisticated mathematics, will be sufficient (akin to what is sometimes called digital twins) discussed in subsequent chapters.</p><p>The European Commission has recently published plans for an initiative on 'Industrial Data Spaces' 1 -modelled after the 'German Industrial Data Space'-as a platform seeking to deliver secure data exchange in business ecosystems on the basis of standards and by using collaborative governance models. <ref type="bibr">2</ref> Access to data will be covered in the next chapter in further detail. Within this chapter, we are focusing on data integrity, security, distribution and secured access. The mechanisms for guaranteeing data integrity and secure data distribution are only now beginning to be addressed. This is where Blockchains and distributed ledgers more generally come to play. Decentralisation technologies may be an important component to the creation of a true global public utility for data. The transparency, usage provenance, tamper-evidence and censorship resistance features of Blockchain technology can provide for such a global public utility. These will be discussed later in a little more detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Data/Cyber Security Risks</head><p>Digital security risk has traditionally been approached as a technical problem but the changing nature and scale of digital security risk is driving countries to re-evaluate their strategies and policies in this area. In recent years, many governments and stakeholders have emphasised the importance of considering digital security risk from an economic and social perspective. The digital ecosystem is premised on the interconnection of various devices and networks and supported by individuals having confidence and trust to participate in the system. These individuals will be asked to trust the system with their financial transactions, their privacy and their very own identities. In order to do so, data security will be firmly at the centre of mind for them and all ecosystem participants. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.1 illustrates the common security threats faced by consumers. To understand the growth in Blockchains and cryptocurrencies, a basic understanding of security is useful.</p><p>To understand how data can be secured is a vast and complex field, that has been covered by many academics, security firms and experts. Whilst I do not intend to cover this vast area here, it would be helpful to understand some of the common security vulnerabilities that allow unscrupulous individuals or even nations to gain access to unlawful data, and how advances in cryptography (on which Blockchain is built) and other techniques may alleviate these vulnerabilities. A word of caution; no matter how good any particular technology is, its efficacy is limited if it is not effectively adopted and implemented by management teams and correctly used by employees or by consumers who want out of the box solutions. So whilst robust systems and firewalls may provide comfort, if the softer aspects of human behaviour are not addressed, the security vulnerabilities remain. In fact, the situation may be worsened because management is led to believe the purchase of expensive security systems has provided a certain level security, when the reality is, that this security infrastructure could be broken by unintentional behaviour of employees, clicking an email link without much thought.</p><p>A common and unfortunate trend is the widening gap between the time (minutes or even seconds) it takes an attacker to compromise a system and exfiltrate data and the time (weeks or months) it takes an organisation to discover a breach. Worse still, typically it's a security blogger who sounds the alarm, not the organisation's own security measures.</p><p>Security threats are nevertheless only going to increase, driven by increasing use of third party supply chain partners which you cannot control, the proliferation of IOT devices which may be difficult to secure, the use of public cloud computing that you have less control over, the use of mobility and mobile devices creating additional points of security vulnerabilities, as well as increasing levels of digitisation within firms, exposing additional data sets to potential security vulnerabilities.</p><p>Recent examples include security incidents which have interrupted essential utility services such as electricity distribution (e.g. 2015 attack against Ukraine power grid), destroyed physical industrial facilities (e.g. 2014 attack against a German steel mill), interrupted for several hours broadcasting of an international television channel (e.g. 2015 attack against TV5 Monde), interrupted access to over 60 major online services (e.g. 2016 'Dyn attack'), undermined large firms' reputation (e.g. Yahoo in 2016, Target Store in 2013) and functioning (e.g. Saudi Aramco Most large organisations impose security policies and systems to safeguard their organisation. The challenge is choosing a security framework that is both holistic and detailed, but which does not stifle the actual running of the business. A number of frameworks currently exist, including:</p><p>• NIST: the National Institute for Standards and Technology (NIST) Cybersecurity</p><p>Framework; 3 and NIST Special Publication 800 series; 4 • CIS: the Center for Internet Security (CIS) Controls for Effective Cyber Defense; 5 • ISO: the International Organisation for Standardization (ISO) standards; <ref type="bibr">6</ref> • CoBIT: the Control Objectives for Information technology (CoBIT) standards; 7 • DHS: the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) cybersecurity evaluation toolkits; 8 • HITRUST: the Health Information Trust Alliance (HITRUST) Common Security Framework (CSF); 9 • FFIEC: the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council (FFIEC) Cybersecurity Assessment Tool. <ref type="bibr">10</ref> Aside from the above, a number of other standards organisations (e.g. SANS) have published guidelines for cyber security and created accreditation processes to further assess risk management strategies.</p><p>Given the near-certainty that a breach will occur even with the best cyber security policies and practices in place, post-breach loss management becomes important. In addition to the increase in cyber security standards, governments and industries are promoting and in some cases mandating, cyber security insurance in order to mitigate the financial risks to companies and consumers. As a result, it is important for organisations to familiarise themselves with the cyber insurance market and decide how to integrate such policies into their overall Enterprise Risk Management (ERM) plans. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Protocol Vulnerabilities</head><p>Many of the attacks that are utilised today take advantage of some of the inherent vulnerabilities designed into the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP)/Internet Protocol (IP) protocol suite. TCP/IP is a suite of protocols that can be used to connect dissimilar brands of computers and network devices. The largest TCP/IP network is the Internet. Protocols are nothing more than a set of formal rules or standards that are used as a basis for communication. Before network devices are able to exchange data, it is necessary for the devices to agree on the rules (protocol) that will govern a communication session. The TCP/IP suite has become widely adopted, because it is an open protocol standard that can be implemented on any platform regardless of the manufacturer. In addition, it is independent of any physical network hardware.</p><p>Most attacks use the functioning of TCP/IP to defeat the protocol. The TCP/IP protocol is an element within the wider OSI reference model. Forgive me if you believe I am teaching you to suck eggs, but a baseline understanding is vital to understand where security vulnerabilities emanate and how new cryptography techniques are seeking to work around these vulnerabilities.</p><p>The OSI reference model is a seven layer model that was developed by the International Standards Organisation (ISO) in 1978. The OSI model is a framework for international standards. The OSI architecture is split into seven layers:</p><p>1. The physical layer: addresses the physical link and is concerned with the signal voltage, bit rate and duration (and the equivalent for wireless communication); 2. The data link layer: is concerned with the reliable transmission of data across a physical link. In other words, getting a signal from one end of a wire to the other end. It handles flow control and error correction; 3. The network layer: handles the routing of data and ensures that data is forwarded to the right destination; 4. The transport layer: provides end-to-end control and constructs the packets into which the data is placed to be transmitted or 'transported' across the logical circuit; 5. The session layer: handles the session set-up with another network node. It handles the initial hand shake and negotiates the flow of information and termination of connections between nodes; 6. The presentation layer: handles the conversion of data from the session layer, so that it can be 'presented' to the application layer in a format that the application layer can understand; 7. The application layer: is the end-user interface. This includes interfaces such as browsers.</p><p>The TCP/IP protocol suite is a condensed version of the OSI reference model consisting of the following four layers: (i) Application Layer (which combines the Application, Presentation and Session layers of the OSI model); (ii) Transport Layer; (iii) Internet Layer (which combines the Internet and Network layer of the OSI The IP portion of TCP/IP is the connectionless network layer protocol. It is sometimes called an 'unreliable' protocol, meaning that IP does not establish an end-to-end connection before transmitting datagrams <ref type="bibr">11</ref> and contains no error detection process. IP operates across the network and data link layers of the OSI model and relies on the TCP protocol to ensure that the data reaches its destination correctly.</p><p>The TCP portion of TCP/IP comes into operation once a packet is delivered to the correct Internet address. In contrast to IP, which is a connectionless protocol, TCP is connection-oriented. It establishes a logical end-to-end connection between two communicating nodes or devices. TCP operates at the transport layer of the OSI model and provides a virtual circuit service between end-user applications, with reliable data transfer, which does not exist in the datagram-oriented IP.</p><p>Software packages that follow the TCP standard run on each machine, establish a connection to each other and manage the communications exchanges. TCP provides the flow control, error detection and sequencing of the data; looks for responses; and takes the appropriate action to replace missing data blocks. The end-to-end connection is established through the exchange of control information. This exchange of information is called a three-way handshake.</p><p>Another important TCP/IP protocol is the User Datagram Protocol (UDP). Like TCP, UDP operates at the transport layer. The major difference between TCP and UDP is that UDP is a connection-less datagram protocol. UDP gives applications direct access to a datagram delivery service, like the service IP provides. This allows applications to exchange data with a minimum of protocol overhead. The UDP protocol is best suited for applications that transmit small amounts of data, where the process of creating connections and ensuring delivery may be greater than the work of simply retransmitting the data (such as many IOT devices). Another situation where UDP would be appropriate is when an application provides its own method of error checking and ensuring delivery of packets.</p><p>Many security threats are carried out using the IP network as well as hijacking the ports used within a device for receiving data packets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Network and System Threats</head><p>Networks and systems face many types of threats, including viruses, worms, trojan horses, trap doors, spoofs, masquerades, replays, password cracking, social engineering, scanning, sniffing, war dialling, denial-of-service attacks, and other protocol based attacks, some of these are briefly explained below: <ref type="bibr">11</ref> The datagram is the packet format defined by IP. • A virus is a parasitic program or fragment of a code that cannot function independently. It is called a virus, because like its biological counterpart, it requires a 'host' to function. A virus is usually spread by executing an infected program or by sending an infected file to someone else. In general, virus scanning programs rely on recognising the 'signature' of known viruses, turning to a database of known virus signatures that they use to compare against scanning results. • A worm is a self-contained and independent program that is usually designed to propagate or spawn itself on infected systems and to seek other systems via available networks. • A trojan horse is a program or code fragment that hides inside a program and performs a disguised function. This can be accomplished by modifying the existing program or by simply replacing the existing program with a new one.</p><p>The trojan horse program functions much the same way as the legitimate program, but usually it also performs some other function, such as recording sensitive information or providing a trap door. • A trap door or back door is an undocumented way of gaining access to a system that is built into the system by its designer(s). It can also be a program that has been altered to allow someone to gain privileged access to a system or process.</p><p>There have been numerous stories of vendors utilising trap doors in disputes with customers. The current security debate between the USA and Huawei of China is primarily around possibilities of trap door being inserted by Huawei, giving access to sensitive data utilising the networks delivered by Huawei, to the Chinese government. • A logic bomb is a program or subsection of a program designed with malevolent intent. It is referred to as a logic bomb, because the program is triggered when certain logical conditions are met. This type of attack is almost always perpetrated by an insider with privileged access to the network. The perpetrator could be a programmer or a vendor that supplies software. • A port scanner is a program that listens to well-known port numbers to detect services running on a system that can be exploited to break into the system. Most intrusion detection software monitor for port scanning, which can trace the scan back to its origination point. However, some programs create a half-open connection that doesn't get logged and cannot therefore be easily detected. • Spoofs cover a broad category of threats. In general terms, a spoof entails falsifying one's identity or masquerading as some other individual or entity to gain access to a system or network or to gain information for some other unauthorised purpose. There are many different kinds of spoofs, these include: -IP Address Spoofing: takes advantage of systems and networks that rely on the IP address of the connecting system or device for authentication. Packet filtering routers are sometimes used to protect an internal network from an external un-trusted network. These routers only allow specified IP addresses to pass from the external network to the internal network. If a hacker is able to determine an IP address that is permitted access through the router, he or she can spoof the address on the external network to gain access to the internal network. The hacker in effect masquerades as someone else. -Sequence Number Spoofing: TCP/IP network connections use sequence numbers. The sequence numbers are part of each transmission and are exchanged with each transaction. The sequence number is based upon each computer's internal clock and the number is predictable because it is based on a set algorithm. By monitoring a network connection, a hacker can record the exchange of sequence numbers and predict the next set of sequence numbers. With this information, a hacker can insert himself into the network connection and effectively, takeover the connection or insert misinformation. The best defence against sequence number spoofing is to encrypt the connection link. -Session High jacking: Is similar to sequence number spoofing. In this process, a hacker takes over a connection session, usually between a client user and a server. This is generally done by gaining access to a router or some other network device acting as a gateway between the legitimate user and the server and utilising IP spoofing. Since session high jacking usually requires the hacker to gain privileged access to a network device, the best defence to take is to properly secure all devices on the network. Something that may not be possible in an IOT environment, where most devices are rather rudimentary. Whilst all the above present worrying areas that need to be safeguarded, what we are seeing today are many unscrupulous individuals or nations engaging in an Advanced Persistent Threat (APT) that may seek to utilise all of the above vulnerabilities. Telecom operators find themselves at the forefront of this battle, with operators such as Deutsche Telekom registering close to 1 million hacker attacks a day in 2014. <ref type="bibr">12</ref> Whilst organisations may deploy systems to monitor communication to their network ports, websites and other entry points, the attackers have started to use communication that is more stealthy and which is less likely to be picked up by an organisations' monitoring systems. Such traffic is usually obfuscated or hidden through techniques that include:</p><p>12 https://www.euractiv.com/section/digital/news/one-million-cyber-attacks-a-day-on-deutschetelekom-network/ • Encryption: with SSL, SSH (Secure Shell), or some other custom application. Proprietary encryption is also commonly used. For example, BitTorrent is known for its use of proprietary encryption and is a favourite attack tool-both for infection and ongoing command and control; • Circumvention: via proxies, remote desktop access tools (such as LogMeIn!, RDP, and GoToMyPC), or by tunnelling applications within other (allowed) applications or protocols; • Port evasion: using network anonymizers or port hopping to tunnel over open ports. For example, botnets are notorious for sending command and control instructions over IRC (Internet Relay Chat) on non-standard ports; • Fast Flux (or Dynamic DNS): to proxy through multiple infected hosts, re-route traffic and make it extremely difficult for forensic teams to figure out where the traffic is really going.</p><p>Recent attacks are unfortunately taking advantage of the resiliency built in to the Internet itself. A botnet can have multiple control servers distributed all over the world, with multiple fallback options. Bots can also potentially leverage other infected bots as communication channels, providing them with a near infinite number of communication paths to adapt to changing access options or update their code as needed.</p><p>Botnets are a key component of targeted, sophisticated and ongoing attacks. These types of botnets are very different than their larger brothers. Instead of attempting to infect large numbers of machines to launch malicious large-scale attacks, these smaller botnets aim to compromise specific high-value systems that can be used to further penetrate and intrude into the target network. In these cases, an infected machine can be used to gain access to protected systems and to establish a backdoor into the network in case any part of the intrusion is discovered. These types of threats are almost always undetectable by antivirus software. They represent one of the most dangerous threats to the enterprise because they specifically target the organisation's most valuable information, such as research and development, intellectual property, strategic planning, financial data and customer information.</p><p>Unfortunately, it is also true that in order to maximise their accessibility and use, many applications are designed from the outset to circumvent traditional port-based firewalls by dynamically adjusting how they communicate. Many new business applications also use these same techniques to facilitate ease of operation while minimising disruptions for customers, partners and the organisation's own security and operations departments. For example, RPC (remote procedure calls) and SharePoint use port hopping because it is critical to how the protocol or application (respectively) functions, rather than as a means to evade detection or enhance accessibility. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Creating Trust in the Data Ecosystem</head><p>IOT devices present a variety of potential security risks that could be exploited. Although these risks exist with traditional computers and computer networks, they are heightened in the IOT environment.</p><p>A lack of embedded security could enable intruders to access and misuse information collected and transmitted to or from the IOT device. For example, new smart televisions enable consumers to surf the Internet, make purchases and share photos. Any security vulnerabilities in these televisions could put the information stored on or transmitted through the television at risk. If smart televisions or other devices store sensitive financial account information, passwords and other types of information, unauthorised persons could exploit vulnerabilities to facilitate identity theft or fraud. Smart televisions have the processing power to potentially build in security protection-many other IOT devices simply do not have the processing power to do so.</p><p>As more connected devices are installed, the number of vulnerabilities are increasing exponentially. Security vulnerabilities in a particular device may facilitate attacks on another connected network or connected systems. A compromised IOT device could be used to launch a denial of service attack. <ref type="bibr">13</ref> Denial of service attacks are more effective the more devices the attacker has under his or her control.</p><p>Securing connected IOT devices is challenging given that companies entering the IOT market generally may not have experience in dealing with security issues. The other factor behind these risks is that although some IOT devices are highly sophisticated, many others may be inexpensive and essentially disposable devices. In those cases, if a vulnerability were discovered after manufacture, it may be difficult or impossible to update the software or apply a patch. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> And if an update is available, many consumers may never hear about it. Companies, particularly those developing low-end devices may lack economic incentives to provide ongoing support or software security updates at all, leaving consumers with unsupported or vulnerable devices shortly after purchase. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> Policy makers need to consider if certification regimes are appropriate for IOT devices and give consideration to changing their product liability regimes to place a higher degree of accountability <ref type="bibr">13</ref> O'Brien, D. (2014). The internet of things: new threats emerge in a connected world. SYMANTEC (Jan. 21, 2014)-describing worm attacking IOT devices that connects them to a botnet for use in denial of service attacks. <ref type="bibr">14</ref> See Article 29 Data Protection Working Party, Opinion 8/2014 on Recent Developments on the Internet of Things 9 (Sept. 16, 2014). For example, most of the sensors currently present on the market are not capable of establishing an encrypted link for communications since the computing requirements will have an impact on a device limited by low-powered batteries. <ref type="bibr">15</ref> Schneier, B. (2014). The internet of things is wildly insecure -and often unpatchable. WIRED (Jan. 6, 2014)-The problem with this process is that no one entity has any incentive, expertise, or even ability to patch the software once it's shipped. The chip manufacturer is busy shipping the next version of the chip, and the [original device manufacturer] is busy upgrading its product to work with this next chip. Maintaining the older chips and products just isn't a priority. on the device manufacturers as well as other players involved in the ecosystem. A fine balance is needed. Placing very high liability risks to product manufacturers through the product's lifecycle, when they such manufacturers have no control over how the product may be used and connected which other networks and devices will only slow down innovation and entrepreneurship. In a world of IOT, where devices could cost less than a dollar, it will be impossible to apply security at the device layer. Security must therefore be applied at the perimeter. Telecommunications operators may be uniquely placed to provide security at the perimeter.</p><p>There are already established security practices within enterprises for securing its infrastructure which could be easily extended to IOT infrastructure. Software and applications are available to harden the systems and monitoring systems readily available. However, organisations need to go back to basics; segregating the network, limiting access to certain ports, enforcing authenticated access, using different virtual machines to limit potential exposure to the network, using clusters for different critical functions. The concept of 'security by design' needs to be considered, accepting that IOT device manufacturers will not have adequate security built into their devices. Another important area that needs to be considered is to have incident response teams, tools and communication processes to respond to what many accept are likely to be security incidents to even the most secure networks. To be prepared for mounting cyber threats, leaders and even the boards need to be adequately educated and resources provided to the security teams. However, the security team cannot be expected to deal with these issues in isolation. It is an organisation-wide effort, especially as many of the security incidents that have plagued organisations have been enabled by employees breaching security protocols rather than vulnerabilities in the infrastructure itself. The security team needs to work with the rest of the organisation and be integrally involved in the launch of new products/services which could expose the organisation to new threats.</p><p>In addition to risks to security, privacy risks flowing from IOT are also clearly of concern. Some of these risks involve the direct collection of sensitive personal information, such as precise geolocation, financial account numbers, or health information; risks already presented by traditional Internet and mobile commerce, others arise from the collection of personal information, habits, locations and physical conditions (of objects and/or people) over time. Even where direct personal data may not be collected, collection of ancillary or meta data may be enough to provide enough data to infer personal information.</p><p>Researchers are beginning to show that existing smart phone sensors can be used to infer a user's mood; stress levels; personality type; bipolar disorder; demographics (e.g., gender, marital status, job status, age); smoking habits; overall well-being; progression of Parkinson's disease; sleep patterns; happiness; levels of exercise; and types of physical activity or movement. <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Although a consumer may today use a <ref type="bibr">16</ref> Peppet, S. <ref type="bibr">(2015)</ref>. Regulating the internet of things: first steps towards managing discrimination, privacy, security &amp; consent, 93 TEX. L. REV. 85, 115-16. fitness tracker solely for wellness-related purposes, the data gathered by the device could be used in the future to price health or life insurance (lower risk premiums for regular exercisers) or to infer the user's suitability for credit or employment. The risks are greater than just privacy and customer consent, when customers are unaware how personal and non-personal data is and will be used, by whom and for what purposes. By intercepting and analysing unencrypted data transmitted from a smart meter device, researchers in Germany were able to determine what television show an individual was watching. <ref type="bibr">17</ref> Security vulnerabilities in camera-equipped devices have also raised the spectre of spying in the home. These examples are just a small measure of what is to come. In a digital ecosystem where access to personal and non-personal data can drive economic and societal benefits, an ecosystem of trust needs to be established, for consumers to share their information and for organisation's to use such information in a transparent ethical manner. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.2 illustrates the need for trust in the wider digital eco-system.</p><p>Confidentiality, integrity and availability, also known as the 'CIA' triad, is a model designed to guide policies for information security within an organisation. The elements of the triad are considered the three most crucial components of security. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.3 details how these elements are linked to advances in encryption, hash functions, digital IDs and Blockchains. Understanding this triad and the underlying technologies is important to understand how and why Blockchain technology may be useful.</p><p>That requires some form of identify and authentication system -is someone impersonating you? Identify as a service: e.g. Facebook That requires customers being clear about what digital footprint organisations hold about them That requires a grown-up relationship with customers. When customers realize the value of their data, how will organisations establish a credible transaction with customers for usage of their (valuable) data? </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Data Confidentiality: Cryptography and Encryption</head><p>Encryption is a foundational technology for data security. Encryption is used to ensure that sensitive data and communication are not accessed by bad actors. However, encryption can also be used by bad actors to shield communications from law enforcement.</p><p>In the last few years, encryption has become increasingly salient as the private sector has invested in differentiation on the basis of user-friendly encryption to secure increasing amounts of personal sensitive data (e.g. what Apple has been attempting to do). On the other hand, some policy makers increasingly insist on weaker encryption to enable law enforcement officials to intercept communications. <ref type="bibr">18</ref> (Apples battles with USA law enforcement officials). Where the right balance lies is a fundamental question for society (where they actually have a choice) and this varies by country.</p><p>Cryptography is the science concerned with the study of secret communication, whilst encryption is a process or algorithm (known as a cipher) to make information hidden or secret. A cryptosystem has (at least) five ingredients: Plaintext, Secret Key, Ciphertext, Encryption Algorithm and Decryption Algorithm. Remember, security usually depends on the secrecy of the key, not the secrecy of the algorithms.</p><p>There  key pair which are related to each other and include DH (Diffie-Hellman keys), SSL, RSA and SSH. In both the cases the keys are generated by random number generators. The cryptographic keys must be established between the sender and the receiver either manually or using trusted third party key management. The types and strength of cryptosystems can be classified along three dimensions: (i) Type of operations used for transforming plaintext into ciphertext: either binary arithmetic (shifts, XORs, ANDs, etc. which are typical for conventional or symmetric encryption) or integer arithmetic which is typical for public key or asymmetric encryption; (ii) Number of keys used: symmetric or conventional systems use a single key, whereas in asymmetric or public key systems, two keys are used, one to encrypt and one to decrypt; and (iii) How plaintext is processed: one bit at a time; a string of any length; or a block of bits.</p><p>Encryption advances are being made on all three dimensions in an attempt to make the encryption process even more resilient. An encryption scheme is generally considered computationally secure if the cost of breaking it (via brute force) exceeds the value of the encrypted information; or the time required to break it exceeds the useful lifetime of the encrypted information. In the case of the German Enigma encryption machine for example, the machines settings were changed daily, based on secret key lists distributed in advance. This meant that the code needed to be solved within the day. 19</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.1">Symmetric Key Encryption</head><p>When most people think of encryption, it is symmetric key cryptosystems that they think of. Symmetric key, also referred to as private key or secret key, is based on a single key and algorithm being shared between the parties who are exchanging encrypted information. The same key both encrypts and decrypts messages.</p><p>The strength of the scheme is largely dependent on the size of the key and on keeping it secret. Generally, the larger the key, the more secure the scheme. In addition, symmetric key encryption is relatively fast. The strength of the encryption algorithm also depends on how many rounds the plaintext block is transformed into the ciphertext block; the more rounds the greater the security. The main weakness of the system is that the key or algorithm has to be shared. You can't share the key information over an unsecured network without compromising the key. As a result, private key cryptosystems are not well suited for spontaneous communication over open and unsecured networks. In addition, symmetric key provides no process for authentication (ensuring the person claiming to be the recipient is the rightful recipient) and no proof against repudiation (preventing the recipient denying (repudiating) that a message was sent or received or that a file was accessed or altered, when in fact it was). This ability is particularly important in the context of e-commerce or creating a data commons platform for instance. <ref type="bibr">19</ref> The military Enigma had 158,962,555,217,826,360,000 different settings.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4.2">Asymmetric Key Encryption/Public Key Cryptosystems</head><p>Asymmetric Key Encryption was invented between 1974 and 1978. There are two keys: private and public. Encryption is done with the public key, whilst decryption is done with the private key. In the context of digital signatures, signing is done by the private key, whilst verification is done by the public key. Whilst Asymmetric Key Encryption is much more secure than symmetric key encryption, it does require much more computation and is much slower to compute than conventional cryptography (approx. 1000 times slower) and therefore results in low data throughput. It is therefore commonly combined with conventional cryptography, e.g., to encrypt session keys to balance the need for security with throughput.</p><p>With the aid of public key cryptography, it is possible to establish secure communications with any stranger when using a compatible software or hardware device. For example, if 'A' wishes to communicate in a secure manner with 'B', a stranger with whom 'A' has never communicated before, 'A' can give 'B' their public key. 'B' can encrypt its outgoing transmissions to 'A' with 'A's public key. 'A' can then decrypt the transmissions using their private key when they receive the encrypted message. Only 'A's private key can decrypt a message encrypted with 'A's public key. If 'B' transmits to 'A' his public key, then 'A' can transmit secure encrypted data back to 'B' that only 'B' can decrypt. It does not matter that they exchanged public keys on an unsecured network. Knowing an individual's public key tells you nothing about his or her private key. Only an individual's private key can decrypt a message encrypted with his or her public key. The security breaks down if either of the parties' private keys is compromised.</p><p>Unlike symmetric key cryptosystems, public key allows for secure spontaneous communication over an open network. There are three public key algorithms in wide use today, with advances being made in another: Diffie-Hellman; RSA; the Digital Signature Algorithm (DSA) and Elliptic Curve Cryptography (ECC). phy appears to be elliptic-curve cryptography (ECC). EEC's strength comes from the fact that it is computational very difficult to solve the elliptic curve discrete logarithm problem. The appeal of ECC algorithms is the fact that they hold the possibility of offering security comparable to the RSA algorithms using smaller keys. Smaller keys mean that less computation is required. Less time and CPU translates into less cost associated with using these algorithms. As a result, interest in these algorithms is growing.</p><p>It is important to remember that as computing power increases and becomes less expensive, the cryptographic key sizes will have to increase to ensure the same levels of security.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Data Integrity: Hash Functions</head><p>To attain a high level of confidence in the integrity of a message or data, a process must be put in place to prevent or detect alteration during transit. One technique employed is called a hash function, which helps identify if a message or file has been altered in any way during transit.</p><p>A hash function takes a message of any length and computes a product value of fixed length. The product is referred to as a 'hash value'. The length of the original message does not alter the length of the hash value. Using the actual message or file, a hash function computes a hash value, which is a cryptographic checksum of the message. This checksum can be thought of as a fingerprint for that message. The hash value can be used to determine if the message or file has been altered since the value was originally computed. Using e-mail as an example, the hash value for a message is computed at both the sending and receiving ends. If the message is modified in any way during transit, the hash value computed at the receiving end will not match the value computed at the sending end and you will know that the email has been compromised during transit.</p><p>There are a number of techniques for hashing developed over time, some of the important ones include:</p><p>• MD4 was developed by Ron Rivest. MD4 is a one-way hash function that takes a message of variable length and produces a 128-bit hash value. MD4 has however been proven to have weaknesses. • MD5 was also created by Ron Rivest as an improvement on MD4. Like MD4, MD5 creates a unique 128-bit message digest value derived from the contents of a message or file. • The Secure Hash Algorithm are a family of cryptographic hash functions published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) as a USA Federal Information Processing Standard. SHA-0 is the original version of the 160-bit hash function published in 1993 under the name 'SHA'. It was withdrawn shortly after publication due to an undisclosed 'significant flaw' and replaced by the slightly revised version SHA-1, which is a one-way hash algorithm used to create digital signatures. SHA-1 is similar to the MD4 and MD5 algorithms, but is slightly slower, however it is reported to be more secure. Cryptographic weaknesses were discovered in SHA-1 and the standard was no longer approved for most cryptographic uses after 2010. SHA-2 includes two similar hash functions, with different block sizes, known as SHA-256 and SHA-512. SHA-3 is a hash function formerly called Keccak, chosen in 2012 after a public competition among non-NSA designers. It supports the same hash lengths as SHA-2, but its internal structure differs significantly from the rest of the SHA family. SHA-3 was released by NIST in August 2015 as a subset of the broader cryptographic primitive family 'Keccak'. 21 SHA-3 uses a concept called the sponge effect. SHA-3 is faster than SHA-1 and SHA-2. • RIPEMD is a hash function that was developed through the European Community's project RIPE.</p><p>Blockchain technology incorporates hashing as a key component of its operation. Each Blockchain protocol can decide which hashing algorithm to utilise. For instance, Bitcoin uses the SHA-256 hashing algorithm, whilst Ethereum uses SHA-3. <ref type="bibr">21</ref> Designed by Joan Daemon, Michael Peeters and Gilles Van Assche. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.6">Data Availability and Access: Digital Signatures</head><p>Availability is a wide ranging area and includes the functioning of information systems used, the security controls used to protect the data and the communication channels used to access which I covered earlier. Here when I say availability, I am actually refereeing to access controls and in particular authentication. To have a high level of confidence and trust in the integrity of information received over a network, the transacting parties needs to be able to authenticate each other's identity. While confidentiality is ensured with the use of public key cryptography, there is no authentication of the parties' identities.</p><p>To ensure secure business transactions on unsecured networks like the Internet, both parties need to be able to authenticate each other's identities. Authentication in a digital setting is a process whereby the receiver of a message can be confident of the identity of the sender.</p><p>The take up of digital products and services can be significantly undermined where legal mechanisms for digital authentication are not established. The lack of secure authentication has been a major obstacle in achieving widespread use of e-commerce in many countries for example. That has impeded their ability to extract considerable value from a range of e-transactions including cutting bureaucratic inefficiencies and delivering fiscal savings. In Haiti and the Philippines, for instance, the cost per transaction of some social assistance programs fell by around 50% per transaction once payments had been digitalised. <ref type="bibr">22</ref> Two general challenges apply to electronic transactions. In countries where rules for electronic transactions (e-transactions) and laws for electronic signatures (e-signatures) are not in place, commerce is slowed down significantly or significantly undermined in the case of international transactions. Secondly, parties need to find ways to ensure the people signing documents are who they say they are, without necessarily seeing them in person; and that the transaction document in question has not been tampered with, copied or otherwise changed-things more or less impossible in international transactions without expensive middle men (i.e. banks).</p><p>At present, no universal system of standards, technologies or regulations exists for e-transactions. Among international institutions, the United Nations Commission on International Trade Law (UNCITRAL) has taken steps to increase the uniformity of a country's legal rules governing e-transactions, e-signatures and digital authentication. more than 30 have turned to the MLES as the basis for their national legislation, and 18 states have signed (and nine have ratified) the ECC. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> UNCITRAL model laws, though not legally binding, are designed to guide countries in drafting legislation, while the ECC, as a treaty, is 'hard law' that allows for less variation on formal adoption. Not surprisingly, enactment of national and sub national laws along the lines suggested by UNCITRAL is uneven, even among countries that have committed to the model law-e.g. several states have enacted the MLES without referring to its Article 12 on cross-border recognition of e-signatures for instance. A number of free trade agreements (FTAs) include provisions on e-transactions, e-signatures and digital authentication, which may well spur growth in countries enacting relevant laws in this area.</p><p>One process used to authenticate the identity of an individual or entity involves some form of digital signature. It is worth clarifying the differences between e-signatures, digital signatures and digital authentication:</p><p>• An electronic signature (e-signature) is any electronic symbol, process or sound that is associated with a record or contract where there is intention to sign the document by the party involved. It signals intent, including acceptance, as to the content of an electronic record. Practically speaking, the technologies used for e-signatures include email addresses, enterprise IDs, personal ID numbers (PINs), biometric identification, social IDs, scanned copies of handwritten signatures and clickable 'I accept' boxes on websites. Electronic signatures are however vulnerable to tampering. • A digital signature, digital certificate or advanced e-signature is characterised by a unique feature that is in digital form, like a fingerprint that is embedded in a document. The signer is required to have a digital certificate so that he or she can be linked to the document. A digital certificate is used to validate the document and ascertain its authenticity and integrity. It uses cryptography to scramble signed information into an unreadable format and decodes it again for the recipient. When a digital signature is applied to a document, the digital certificate is bound to the data being signed into one unique fingerprint. Certification Authorities (CAs) often provide certification services for verifying the signer's identity. The EU, distinguishes between digital signatures and what it calls 'qualified e-signatures' (or qualified digital signatures). While both rely on encryption and CAs to identify the signer, the qualified e-signatures also require the signer to use a qualified signature creation device (QSCD), such as a smart card, token or cloud-based trust service. The QSCD verifies the digital identity and can only be given to users once they have passed a Know-Your-Customer (KYC) process. <ref type="bibr">23</ref> States party to the ECC are Cameroon, Congo, the Dominican Republic, Fiji, Honduras, Montenegro, the Russian Federation, Singapore and Sri Lanka. For the updated treaty status, see "United Nations Convention on the Use of Electronic Communications in International Contracts". • Digital authentication refers to the techniques used to identify individuals, confirm a person's authority or prerogative, or offer assurance on the integrity of information. 'Authentication' can mean different things in different national legal contexts, with the challenge of doing it remotely over networks. Digital authentication can rely on a varied set of factors, such as those concerning knowledge (e.g. passwords, answers to a pre-selected security question), ownership (e.g. possession of a one-time password) or inherence (e.g. biometric information). Depending on the level of security desired, a digital authentication system could be single, double or multi-factor.</p><p>To sign a message, senders usually append their digital signature to the end of a message and encrypt it using the recipient's public key. Recipients decrypt the message using their own private key and verify the sender's identity and the message integrity by decrypting the sender's digital signature using the sender's public key.</p><p>For example, if 'A' has a pair of keys, its private key and its public key. 'A' sends a message to 'B' that includes both a plaintext message and a version of the plaintext message that has been encrypted using 'A's private key. The encrypted version of 'A's text message is 'A's digital signature. 'B' receives the message from 'A' and decrypts it using 'A's public key. 'B' then compares the decrypted message to the plaintext message. If they are identical, then 'B' has verified that the message has not been altered and that it came from 'A'. 'B' can authenticate that the message came from 'A' because 'B' decrypted it with 'A's public key, so it could only have been encrypted with 'A''s private key, to which only 'A' has access.</p><p>The strengths of digital signatures are that they are almost impossible to counterfeit and they are easily verified. However, if 'A' and 'B' are strangers who have never communicated to each other before and 'B' received 'A's public key, but had no other means to verify who 'A' was, other than 'A's assertion that it was who it claimed to be, then the digital signature is useless for authentication. It will still verify that a message has arrived unaltered from the sender, but it cannot be used to authenticate the identity of the sender.</p><p>In cases where the parties have no prior knowledge of one another, a trusted third party is required to authenticate the identity of the transacting parties. A digital certificate issued by a Certification Authority (CA) utilising a hierarchical PKI can be used to authenticate a sender's identity for spontaneous, first-time contacts. A digital certificate issued by a trusted/known third party (CA) binds an individual or entity to its public key. The digital certificate is digitally signed by the CA with the CA's private key. This provides independent confirmation that an individual or entity is in fact who it claims to be. The CA issues digital certificates that vouch for the identities of those to whom the certificates were issued. If 'A's public key is presented as part of a digital certificate signed by a known CA, 'B' can have a high level of confidence that 'A' is who and what they claim to be.</p><p>The CA and the CA's public key must be widely known for the digital certificate to be of practical value. The CA's public key must be widely known so that there is no need to authenticate the CA's digital signature. You are relying on the CA's digital signature to authenticate the certificate owner's identity and to bind that identity to their public key. In its simplest form, a digital certificate would include the name and address of the individual/entity, certificate expiration date, serial number for the certificate and the individuals or entities public key. A digital certificate could contain other information as well. Depending on the type of certificate, it could include information on access privileges, geographic location of the owner, or the age of the owner. When fully implemented, digital certificates will most likely take several forms.</p><p>A digital signature used in concert with a digital certificate potentially possesses greater legal authority than a handwritten signature. The inability to forge a digital signature, the fact that the digital signature can verify that the document has not been altered since it was signed and the certificate verifying the identity of the signer make a digitally signed document irrefutable.</p><p>The whole digital certification process requires a certification authority that is well trusted, well known and capable of issuing digital certifications, with the initial user verification process (KYC) that is robust and non-reputable. Typically a certification authority will be a government agency, or a large telecommunications organisation that has the infrastructure, skills and resources required to perform some initial KYC procedures and subsequent management of digital certificates. In a digital world, the certification authority is likely to become the future credit agencies, rating everyone as a good or bad 'risk'.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.7">National Digital Identities</head><p>There are few things more central to a functioning society and economy than identity. Without a way to identify each other and our possessions we would be back to the primitive days where village elders were used to help identify individuals. Printed documents such as passports, national ID cards and driver's licences offer proof of a person's identity. Similarly, online electronic information can be linked to an individual or another entity to offer proof of identity. Digital identity is today used by a computer system to identify an individual or corporation or a machine. However, over 1 billion people in the developing world lack any form of officially recognised identification, either paper or electronically based according to the World Bank ID4D database. <ref type="bibr">24</ref> The remaining 6 billion plus people have some form of identification, but over half cannot use it effectively in today's digital ecosystems. This identity gap is a serious obstacle for participation in political, economic, and social life. Without a secure way to assert and verify their identity, a person may be unable to open bank account, vote in an election, access education or healthcare, receive a pension payment, or file official petitions in court. Furthermore, poor identification systems mean that states will have difficulty collecting <ref type="bibr">24</ref> World Bank Global ID4D Dataset, 2018. taxes, targeting social programs and ensuring security. Achieving inclusive development therefore requires a sustained effort to address the world's identity gap, as reflected in the new Sustainable Development Goals (SGDs). <ref type="bibr">25</ref> Digital ID has the potential to unlock new opportunity for the 3 billion plus individuals who have some form of high assurance ID but limited ability to use it in the digital world. Moving from purely physical ID to digital ID programs and creating digital infrastructure and applications that use digital ID for authentication, could enable these users to take advantage of the efficiency and inclusion benefits that digital interactions offer. <ref type="bibr">26</ref> In many countries, access to banking services may not be available and large swathes of the population could miss out on the digital transformation dividend. Unlike a paper based ID such as most driver's licenses and passports, a digital ID can be verified remotely over digital channels, often at a lower cost, if the digital ID has the following attributes:</p><p>• Is verified to a high degree of assurance. High assurance digital ID meet both government and private sector institutions' standards for initial registration and subsequent acceptance for a multitude of important civic and economic uses. This attribute does not rely on any underlying technology. A range of credentials can be used to achieve unique high assurance authentication and verification, including biometrics, passwords, QR codes and smart devices with identity information embedded in them; • Is unique. With a unique digital ID, an individual has only one identity within a scheme and every scheme identity corresponds to only one individual. This is not characteristic of most social media identities today for example; • Established with individual consent. Consent means that individuals knowingly register for their digital ID, with control over what personal data will be captured and how they will be used. This element is now becoming important as privacy becomes more and more important and as cyber-crime is on a rise.</p><p>The technology needed for digital ID is ready and more affordable than ever, making it possible for emerging economies to leapfrog paper based approaches to identification. <ref type="bibr">27</ref> Biometric technology for registration and authentication is becoming more accurate and less expensive. <ref type="bibr">28</ref> For example, iris-based authentication technologies can give false acceptance rates as low as 0.2% and false rejection rates of less than 0.01%. <ref type="bibr">29</ref> The average selling price of a fingerprint sensor found in a <ref type="bibr">25</ref> GSMA. (2016). Digital identity: towards shared principles for public and private sector cooperation. A joint World Bank Group, GSMA Secure Identity Alliance Discussion Paper, July 2016. <ref type="bibr">26</ref> McKinsey. (2019). Digital identification A key to inclusive growth. 27 Bujoreanu, L., Mittal, A., Noor, W. (2018). Demystifying technologies for digital identification. World Bank. <ref type="bibr">28</ref> World Bank. (2017). Technology landscape for digital identification, identification for development. <ref type="bibr">29</ref> World Bank. (2017). Technology landscape for digital identification, identification for development. mobile phone fell by 30% in 2017 alone. <ref type="bibr">30</ref> Bar codes on cards, which once stored only numerical data, can now store signature, fingerprint, or facial data. <ref type="bibr">31</ref> A 2019 McKinsey report estimates that improved customer registration and on-boarding costs through digital IDs can be reduced by 90%, saving up to US$1.6 trillion globally. <ref type="bibr">32</ref> It further suggests that extending full digital ID coverage and usage could unlock economic value equivalent to between 3 and 13% of GDP in 2030 in a number of countries. <ref type="bibr">33</ref> Perhaps the most important regulation dealing with identity in the EU is the EU Regulation 910/2014 on electronic identification and the associated set of standards for electronic identification and trust services for electronic transactions in the European Single Market. Better known as the electronic IDentification, Authentication and trust Services regulation (eIDAS). The eIDAS regulation was born out of the Electronic Signatures Directive of 1999, which it superseded. Unfortunately, for various reasons, including the fact that as a directive and not a regulation, it left discretion over implementation into local law in the hands of Member States, leading to a fractured, non-interoperable set of standards; it fell short of its ambitions. As a binding regulation, eIDAS is mandatory for Member States and so will be applied uniformly. The eIDAS package includes: eID: a way for businesses and consumers to prove their identity electronically; eTimestamp: electronic proof that a set of data existed at a specific time; eSignature: expression in an electronic format of a person's agreement to the content of a document. eIDAS recognizes three levels of esignatures: Simple, Advanced and Qualified; eSeal: guarantees both the origin and the integrity of a document; Qualified Web Authentication Certificate: ensures websites are trustworthy and reliable; Electronic Registered Delivery Service: protects against the risk of loss, theft, damage or alterations when sending documentation; Legal recognition of electronic documents: assurance that an electronic document cannot be rejected by the court for the reason that it is electronic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.7">National Digital Identities 129</head><p>Numerous new national digital ID programs (including card and/or mobile-based schemes) have been launched or initiated in other countries. Examples include new schemes in India, Algeria, Cameroon, Jordan, Italy, Senegal and Thailand, major announcements in the Netherlands, Bulgaria, Norway, Liberia, Poland, Jamaica, Sri Lanka and a pilot scheme in Myanmar. Most of these programs now include 30 Burt, C. (2017). Fingerprint cards reports cost cutting and changing focus after tough 2017. BiometricUpdate.com, 09 February 2018. <ref type="bibr">31</ref> Burt, C. (2017). Fingerprint cards reports cost cutting and changing focus after tough 2017. BiometricUpdate.com, 09 February 2018. <ref type="bibr">32</ref> In India, the use of Aadhaar for KYC verification reportedly reduced costs for financial institutions from approximately $5 to approximately $0.70 per customer. Banks reduced their KYC costs by eliminating manual processing of paper documentation and the need for in-person verification of the account holder's identity, reducing the costs of bank accounts and expanding opportunities for financial access. <ref type="bibr">33</ref> McKinsey. (2019). Digital identification: a key to inclusive growth. Brazil has a potential for 13% improvements to GDP from digital ID, whilst Nigeria, Ethiopia, India, China, USA, UK has the potential for 7%, 6%, 6%, 4%, 4% and 3% respectively. biometrics, the majority in the form of fingerprints. Schemes such as the Gov.UK Verify initiative were also introduced in 2016 <ref type="bibr">34</ref> and Australia announced the first phase of its digital identity program, which was launched in 2017. Whilst there is an increasing number of countries experimenting with digital IDs, a 2016 study of 48 national identity programs found that very few could be used in a wide variety of sectors. <ref type="bibr">35</ref> Remember that it is not digital identity itself, but the myriad of applications it enables citizens to access that is important. Digital ID systems take one of three forms: centralised, federated, or decentralised. All three have both advantages and disadvantages for advanced digital IDs. Hybrid models are also possible, for example, a centralised basic digital ID with federated add-on services:</p><p>• In a centralised system, a single provider, typically a government agency, is integrated into all use cases and must generate adoption and use and bear all costs. Examples include the national advanced digital ID programs in Estonia 36 and India's Adhaar card. Benefits include streamlined service delivery and high data aggregation capabilities, with tools like distributed storage helping avoid data consolidation. Such a setup does however concentrate risk and liability, placing a significant burden of trust on the government agency; • In a federated system, ownership of the system is shared among multiple standalone systems that share common standards. Examples include SecureKey Concierge in Canada, which is led by financial institutions and GOV.UK Verify, a basic digital ID launched by the UK public sector (although adoption has been poor). A federated structure distributes cost and dilutes potential for abuse but also requires coordinated decision making, introducing complexity that may dis-incentivise institutions from participating as ID providers; • Decentralised models operate with no institutional owners and hinge on distributed ledgers, for example through Blockchain and other technologies to establish and manage identities. Such models remain in the early stages of development. Although it is not an ID system, Solid launched by Tim Berners-Lee in September 2018, provides an example. <ref type="bibr">37</ref> In many cases, the lines between basic and advanced digital ID may blur because broader digital ecosystems can be built on top of a basic digital ID that provides the <ref type="bibr">34</ref> In the United Kingdom, HM Revenue and Customs' Connect computer draws on information from a wide range of government and corporate sources, as well as individual digital footprints, to create a profile of each taxpayer's total income. Such analytical capability could even be used to assess the behavioral impact of new tax and spending policies. <ref type="bibr">35</ref> Review of national identity programs, International Telecommunication Union, May 2016. <ref type="bibr">36</ref> Estonia uses platform technology to connect Uber drivers directly with the tax office, adding income from rides directly to their tax return. Estonia stands out in its use of digital platforms for delivering government services. <ref type="bibr">37</ref> Solid is a new open-source framework seeking put data back in the hands of individuals rather than data monoliths. underlying ability to authenticate over digital channels. Increasingly, in more developed countries, we are likely to see digital IDs progress from what are today fairly basic digital IDs, to more advanced digital IDs. These are likely to be more sophisticated and include within the digital ID itself, a range of individual preferences for the types of data which can be shared and under what circumstances, which the individual can specify and change over time.</p><p>It may now be possible (given increasing smart phone penetration and advances in cryptography) to build new identity frameworks based on the concept of decentralised identities-potentially including an interesting subset of decentralised identity known as Self Sovereign Identity ('SSI'). These frameworks put the user at the centre of the framework, where the user 'creates' their own identity, generally by creating his or her own unique identifier (or a number of them) and then attaching identity information to that identifier. By associating verifiable credentials from recognised authorities (or even data from a social media accounts, e-commerce transactions) users can in effect create the digital equivalents of physical world credentials like passports, national IDs and driving licences. By setting up a system in which the user controls not just the identity but also the data associated with it, it may be possible to create self sovereign identities.</p><p>While Blockchain is not required for decentralised identity, it can be a powerful solution for different aspects of the decentralised identify framework. It provides infrastructure for managing data in a decentralised, but in a trustworthy way. This can help mitigate the use of trusted third parties or provide censorship resistance in certain circumstances. Some of the benefits of using Blockchain based solutions for digital ID include:</p><p>• Blockchain addresses can be used for digital IDs: these are unique, generated by the user themselves and already leverage public/private key cryptography; • Blockchains could be used as digital ID registries: providing information on who is related to specific IDs and how to access information about them; • Notarisation: a Blockchain could 'notarise' credentials through the use of hash functions. This doesn't mean storing the credentials on the Blockchain, which may run afoul of regulations like the GDPR. Instead it acts as a timestamp and electronic seal. This both provides proof of when the credential was created, as well as 'seals' that credential by making any tampering of the credential evident to outside observers. For example, a university might send the hash of a diploma to the Blockchain at the time of graduation. This provides the student with both a timestamp of when the diploma was issued as well as a way to prove at any time in the future that the diploma being presented is the one that was registered at that time; • Facilitate smart contract execution: <ref type="bibr">38</ref> For example, a user can agree to share certain information with a social media platform but only for a limited amount of time. This consent can be recorded as a transaction on the Blockchain along with its expiry date. The social media company would then have to delete the information at the expiry date and put proof of that deletion on the Blockchain.</p><p>A collection of enterprise providers, start-ups and nonprofits, including Microsoft, Evernym, Tierion, Uport and Sovrin Foundation are working to create an identity infrastructure in which users are no longer tied to dominant platforms or centralised intermediaries, such as credit bureaus. The Decentralised Identity Foundation, the ID2020 public-private partnership and the World Wide Web Consortium are shepherding the creation of open standards to make this vision reality. The State of Illinois has launched a pilot project to issue digital birth certificates on a Blockchain based approach. <ref type="bibr">39</ref> In another example, Civic offers Blockchain based identity verification services. Users who provide personal information, validators who verify it and large service providers who connect their user profiles to the system all receive compensation in the form of Civic's CVC tokens. These tokens can be used to pay for validating information.</p><p>Having explained some of the benefits and uses of Blockchains, in the digital ID context, it would be appropriate to explain what it is and how it works more broadly.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.8">Blockchain</head><p>Blockchain has received much attention in the past 2-3 years as a significant enabling technology. It was originally used in the context of Bitcoin but soon came to prominence for its potential for use more broadly. Many have claimed it has been an over hyped technology, very much a technology looking for a solution, rather than a solution to real world problems. I suspect it may have been over hyped by the Blockchain evangelicals who saw its ability to get rid of centralised authorities towards a more egalitarian decentralised model. However, there are many cases where it might be useful and some use cases are beginning to emerge. Whether it has the profound impact that many had hoped for, is however far from clear. It is still a very nascent technology and like the TCP/IP protocol, is likely to take time for it to be adopted more broadly and for relevant use cases and infrastructure to be widely deployed.</p><p>38 Smart contracts are programmed to generate instructions for downstream processes (such as payment instructions or moving collateral) if reference conditions are met. Like passive data, they become immutable once accepted onto the ledger. <ref type="bibr">39</ref> Douglas, T. (2017). Illinois announces key partnership in Birth Registry Blockchain Pilot. GovTech. 08 September 2017. Blockchain at its core, is a form of distributed ledger, which its advocates claim has the promise to reshape industries by enabling trust, providing transparency and reducing friction across business ecosystems potentially lowering costs, reducing transaction settlement times and improving cash flow. Today, they claim, trust is placed in banks, clearinghouses, governments and many other institutions as central authorities-this centralised trust model adds delays and friction costs (commissions and fees) to transactions and places control at the hands of centralised authorities. Blockchain provides an alternative trust model and removes the need for central authorities in arbitrating transactions. Blockchains, it is claimed, gives power back to the people and may remove the need for centralised regulation. As digital economy expert Arun Sundarajan of New York University observes, if you look back at history, every time there was a big expansion in the world's economic activity, it was generally induced by the creation of a new form of trust. <ref type="bibr">40</ref> Its primary value is its ability to deploy cryptography to reach consensus across parties in the ledger. No single entity can amend past data entries or approve new additions to the ledger. Whilst I don't want to go into the intricacies of how Blockchains actually operate, I think some background is useful to understand broadly what makes the technology different and how it might operate in the real world. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.4 details the various steps involved in completing a transaction on Blockchain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.8">Blockchain 133</head><p>A new block is verified on the Bitcoin Blockchain roughly every 10 min. Each block has a fixed size, so transactions often must wait until the next block. The requisite confidence level (and thus delay) to accept a block as valid, depends on the risk profile of the activity. Someone with little at stake (buyer accepting Bitcoin for a purchase of a coffee) will prioritise speed over small, incremental robustness, while one engaged in a large, important transaction (paying for a car) will be willing to wait for more confirmations before accepted payment. Anyone can decide the level of assurance they want by tolerating additional delay. Users can however pay higher transaction fees to incentivise miners to include their transaction in a block they construct. By 2017, Bitcoin transaction fee routinely were several dollars per transaction and sometimes much more, making small value micropayments impractical. <ref type="bibr">41</ref> Aside from payments, in the real world, to represent physical items onto the Blockchain, QR codes are used. These QR codes are printed onto a physical item in a manner that they cannot be tampered with. As that physical items moves through the supply chain, the QR code gets scanned by systems and its status gets updated on the Blockchain.</p><p>Trust in transactions is not brokered by intermediaries, but embodied algorithmically in the transaction process itself. The algorithmic consensus process is the trust agent. The Blockchain promises to create an Internet of Value by taking aspects of <ref type="bibr">40</ref>   Transaction initiated between two holders of such software wallets is submitted (broadcast) to the Blockchain for processing.</p><p>Some form of software installed on computer/mobile -commonly called wallets that allow transactions to be submitted to the Blockchain.</p><p>Transaction is placed in a pool of unconfirmed transactions -usually several subdivided local pools. Nodes (miner) select transactions from these pools and form them into a 'block'. Any combination of transactions can be chosen.</p><p>Multiple miners can select the same transactions to be included in their block.</p><p>Node itself confirms if all the transaction are eligible to be executed according to the Blockchain history.</p><p>Node uses its computing power to find the correct 'nounce' and signature. Each block has a different mathematical problem, so every miner will work on a different problem unique to the block they formed.</p><p>The node that finds an eligible signature for its block first, broadcasts its block and its signature to all the other nodes on the Blockchain.</p><p>Other nodes verify the signature's legitimacy and where valid, the block is added to the Blockchain, and is distributed to all other nodes on the network.</p><p>Other miners accept the block and save it to their transaction data as long as all transactions inside the block can be executed according to the Blockchain's history.</p><p>After a new block is added to the Blockchain, the nodes start over again by forming a new block of transactions from the unconfirmed transactions pools.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Start End</head><p>A node is a computer that runs Blockchain software and helps transmit the information across the Blockchain network. Mining Nodes have the ability to add transactions to a Blockchain. Full Nodes hold and distribute copies of the entire Blockchain ledger helping validate the history of the Blockchain. There may be variants of these including super nodes and light nodes. the digital economy that are traditionally centralised and replacing them with distributed trust. Information held on a Blockchain exists as a shared and continually reconciled database. The Blockchain database isn't stored in any single location, meaning the records it keeps are truly public (well in some cases) and easily verifiable. No centralised version of this information exists for a hacker to corrupt. Hosted by potentially thousands of computers simultaneously, its data is accessible to anyone on the Internet. Bitcoin for instance is managed by its network and not any one central authority. Decentralisation means the network operates on a user-to-user (or peer-to-peer) basis. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.5 illustrates the three key characteristics of Blockchains.</p><p>Aside from the obvious applications in finance, it has the potential to be used in a number of other settings. For instance, IOT platforms tend to have a centralised model in which a broker or hub controls interactions between devices, an arrangement that can be expensive and impractical. Blockchain can alter that by decentralising secured and trusted data exchanges and record keeping on IOT platforms, serving as a general ledger that maintains a trusted record of all messages exchanged between IOT devices. However, this still remains a theory as current Blockchain systems simply cannot handle the magnitude and scale of transactions that would be generated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Peer To Peer</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>TransacƟons/Tokens</head><p>[a transaction or token is issued in a decentralised way through the protocol]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cryptographic Protocol</head><p>[protocol allows to transact / exchange online, in a secure, pseudonymous, global]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Register of TransacƟons</head><p>[register of transactions, held in multiple nodes] Worldwide spending on Blockchain solutions was forecast to be nearly US$2.9 billion in 2019, before surging to US$12.4 billion in 2022. <ref type="bibr">42</ref> Gartner predicts value added from Blockchains will grow to more than US$176 billion by 2025 and exceed US$3.1 trillion by 2030. <ref type="bibr">43</ref> According to a 2018 Constellation Research survey, 67% of USA companies are evaluating or implementing Blockchain technology, with a quarter already having projects underway or completed. <ref type="bibr">44</ref> According to the survey, 57% of respondents investing in Blockchain technology agreed, or strongly agreed, that their organisation should adopt Blockchain technology to remain competitive. And of those who declared their Blockchain investments, 68% are spending more than US$1 million, with 27% spending more than US$10 million on Blockchain activity.</p><p>A recent World Economic Forum report stated that over 40 central banks are researching distributed ledger technology for a variety of use-cases. <ref type="bibr">45</ref> Elsewhere in the public sector, there are over 200 Blockchain initiatives spanning 45 countries. <ref type="bibr">46</ref> Currently, finance appears offers the strongest use cases for the technology, in particular, international transactions. Blockchain potentially cuts out the middleman for these types of transactions. Whilst Blockchain can be effective in solving a number of pressing and difficult problems, it should not be over-hyped. In many of the use cases being proposed for Blockchain, many would appear to be hype; there could be many alternative (mostly existing) solutions that could be deployed which would be cheaper, faster and more effective.</p><p>The utopia held by some about the current versions of Blockchains leading to a decentralised world is also a little way off. As will be described later, the nature of decentralised Blockchains has some very fundamental shortcomings. In permissionless Blockchain, 47 as the network grows, the requirements for storage, bandwidth and computing power required by participating nodes in the network also increase. At some point it becomes only feasible for the few nodes that can afford the resources to process blocks leading to the risk of centralisation.</p><p>Before I get into Blockchain in further detail, it may be worth highlighting fundamentally why it was initially created. In the context of Bitcoin, a mechanism was needed to create trust without reliance on a central authority, trust in terms of motives of the various actors. It needed to ensure that all the users of the system could trust the state of the system, in particular the state of financial transactions and provide an audit trail of the transaction history which is irrefutable. It needed to <ref type="bibr">42</ref>  It is also worth stating that Blockchains are not databases, but ledgers. Blockchains are not meant to act as databases. The fact that a block within the chain encapsulates all the historic transactions, can quickly become unwieldy and difficult and slow to operate. Most Blockchains are combined with off-chain databases, for they must be lightweight with limited on-chain storage so that 'anyone' can download a full history of the Blockchain. If Blockchains become too large, fewer people will be able to participate in the network, thus reducing the decentralisation of the network and overall security. A public Blockchain such as Bitcoin, broadcasts all transactions across the network and is totally transparent. Every full node on the network maintains a copy of the entire transaction history all the way back to the so-called 'genesis block', now over 100 gigabytes in size.</p><p>We need to differentiate between two separate concepts here: decentralised and distributed data storages, like IPFS 48 and Swarm. <ref type="bibr">49</ref> Each Blockchain implementation uses different data storage for 'off-chain' data and the balance between 'onchain' and 'off-chain' data depends on the use case. Just like the design of the Internet and the Internet protocol suites, it is expected that Blockchains remain as light as possible to ensure speed and reliability; whilst it will be the 'off-chain' storage that will hold the majority of the data.</p><p>Back to the original utopian view-unfortunately the original Blockchain as used within Bitcoin actually hasn't really fully delivered on its promise:</p><p>• Trust: the aggregation of miners to a few large operators out of China, makes it possible for them to collude and manipulate transactions; • Traceability: there have been forks, <ref type="bibr">50</ref> as they are called in the space, wherein some participants disagree on the validity of some historic transactions and agree to replicate the system status without the 'anomaly', or the fact that users can remain anonymous thereby making traceability unachievable; <ref type="bibr">48</ref> The Inter Planetary File System (IPFS) offers blockchain based distributed cloud storage technology. Instead of storing files in a particular; location, accessible through a URL address, IPFS stores multiple copies of files in pieces, across many hard drives throughout the network. It is designed to use the Filecoin token to incentivise users to contribute storage space. The token provides the intermediation by establishing incentives on both sides. <ref type="bibr">49</ref> Swarm is a censorship resistant, permissionless, decentralised storage and communication infrastructure. <ref type="bibr">50</ref> There are two different versions of forks in cryptocurrencies. A hard fork and a soft fork. When a hard fork takes place there can be a split in a blockchain if there isn't consensus. The hard fork will cause all older versions of the Blockchain to be invalid. However, people can still choose to run the older software if they do not agree with the hard fork decision, i.e. the hard fork didn't achieve consensus amongst the community and miners. This can lead to the creation of a new cryptocurrency, as happened when Ethereum hard forked and Ethereum Classic was created.</p><p>Hard forks can also be used to upgrade the software on a blockchain. If this upgrade has the consensus of the community and the miners then there will be no split on the blockchain. • Tradability: the sheer effort required to solve mathematical problems and reach consensus means that only a limited number of transactions can be completed in a given time period, thereby reducing tradability, e.g. it could not be used to replicate credit card transactions, as the sheer volume would overwhelm the Blockchain system. <ref type="bibr">51</ref> It would however be wrong to assume all Blockchain implementations suffer from these issues. There are in fact two forms of Blockchain; permission-less and permissioned. Bitcoin is a permission-less system (also called a public Blockchain), in that a user does not need permission to join and use the Blockchain. In permissioned Blockchain (sometimes called Private Blockchain), some form of permission is required for a user to be allowed use of the system. <ref type="bibr">52</ref> The problems highlighted above relate primarily to permission-less Blockchains: given that any user (good or bad intentioned) can utilise the system; that a potentially exponential number of users could be added and therefore an explosion in the number of transactions that need to be processed.</p><p>In a public Blockchain, you place your trust in the consensus of a large number of entities, which will in effect vote on the state transitions of your system (i.e. transactions). You hope the good entities will out-vote the bad entities. The system in this sense is trust-less. <ref type="bibr">53</ref> The Blockchain protocols rely on the assumption that the system consists of many small actors that make decisions independently. However, if anyone can take part, the system is vulnerable to what are called 'Sybil attacks', in which an attacker creates many apparently independent voters who are actually under his sole control. If creating and maintaining a voter is free, anyone can win any vote they choose simply by creating enough Sybil voters. It is for this reason that Blockchain protocols require 'miners' to expend significant effort before they can in effect cast their vote-one form of effort is called 'proof of work' (POW). The high cost of adding a block to a chain is not an unfortunate side-effect, it is essential to maintaining the correctness of the Blockchain.</p><p>Permission-less systems defend against Sybil attacks by requiring a vote to be accompanied by a proof of the expenditure of some resource. To vote in a Proof-of-Work (POW) Blockchain, such as Bitcoin or Ethereum, requires computing very <ref type="bibr">51</ref> The time required to process a block of transactions is slow. For example, Bitcoin block times are 10 min, while Ethereum block times are around 14 s. These times are even longer during peak moments. Compare that to the nearly instantaneous confirmations you get when using services like Square or Visa. <ref type="bibr">52</ref> A permission-based framework requires rules to approve/reject authorised participants, including perhaps minimum capital requirements, conduct of business rules and risk management processes. Permission-less systems in contrast, allow anyone to participate as long as they install the software with the requisite protocols. <ref type="bibr">53</ref> Techniques using multiple voters to maintain the state of a system in the presence of unreliable and malign voters were first published in The Byzantine Generals Problem by Lamport et al. in 1982. Alas, Byzantine Fault Tolerance (BFT) requires a central authority to authorise entities to take part. In the Blockchain jargon, it is permissioned. many otherwise useless hashes. The idea is that that the good voters will spend more and compute more useless hashes, than the bad voters. <ref type="bibr">54</ref> Blockchains cannot be described as efficient. Blockchain's utopian vision of a decentralised world is not without substantial costs. Decentralisation has three main costs: waste of resources, scalability problems and network externality inefficiencies. Blockchain has to choose at most two of the following three attributes: (i) Correctness;</p><p>(ii) Decentralisation; and (iii) Cost-efficiency. Permission-less Blockchains choose correctness and decentralisation at the expense of efficiency. Efficiency in terms of the wasted resources spent by miners solving, rather worthless cryptographic problems (some terawatt hours in 2018), as well as inefficiency in terms of the number of transactions that can be processed. Whilst Visa processed some 3526 transactions per second and MasterCard processed 2061 transactions per second, Bitcoin only processed 3.30 transactions per second. <ref type="bibr">55</ref> Permission based Blockchains on the other hand, choose correctness and efficiency at the expense of decentralisation; where ledgers managed by a single entity or a selected number of entities, forgo the desired feature of decentralisation (examples include IBM's Hyperledger Fabric; JP Morgan's Quorum based on Ethereum; and R3 Corda).</p><p>In a traditional centralised ledger, the participant is incentivised to report honestly because he does not wish to jeopardise his future profits. Where the central ledger is removed, how do you incentivise distributed participants to validate the blocks? The distributed participants must be rewarded in some form for them to expend resources in verifying any new transaction. A user of Blockchain wanting to perform a transaction, store a file, record a review, whatever, needs to persuade a node to include their transaction in a block.</p><p>Nodes are usually coin-operated, meaning you need to pay them to do so. In Bitcoin, the successful mining node that solves this useless hash and adds the transaction block to a Bitcoin Blockchain is rewarded with 12.5 Bitcoins (and reducing over time) roughly every 10 min, which was worth around US$100,000 at the time of writing, along with the additional transaction fees. Since mid-2016, the reward has been 12.5 Bitcoin; it will however be cut in half automatically again around 2020.</p><p>Nodes cannot be rewarded in 'fiat currency', because that would need some central mechanism for paying them (going against the decentralisation theme). So the reward has to come in the form of coins generated by the system itself (Bitcoin). <ref type="bibr">54</ref> Note: the mining difficulty is adjusted automatically on Bitcoin network every 2 weeks based on the block production rate. When more miners join the network to mine Bitcoin, the total hashing power increases and therefore it can be assumed that the network altogether will find eligible signatures faster, meaning they will add blocks to the blockchain faster-so the level of difficulty is adjusted to ensure the total hashing power on the network on average produces 1 block per 10 min-given it has been estimated that a blockchain will need approximately 10 min to propagate the latest block(s) to all nodes globally and the system to remain synchronised. <ref type="bibr">55</ref> Securities and Markets Stakeholder Group. (2018). Own initiative report on initial coin offerings and crypto-assets. 19 October 2018 ESMA 22-106-1338. The Blockchain system needs names for the parties to these transactions. There is no central authority handing out names, so the parties need to name themselves. They typically do so by generating a public-private key pair and using the public key as the name. In practice this is implemented in wallet software, which generates and stores one or more key pairs for use in transactions. The public half of the pair is a pseudonym. The security of the system depends upon the user and the software keeping the private key secret. This can be difficult, as Nicholas Weaver's computer security group at Berkeley discovered when their wallet was compromised and their Bitcoins were stolen. <ref type="bibr">56</ref> Given the heavy utilisation of computational resources involved in mining (buying hardware, power, network bandwidth, staff time), PoW is considered to be costly, wasteful and inefficient. Having thousands of miners working on just one solution each time is an excessive use of resources, especially as the only block that has any value thereafter is the one that is solved. With each new block being mined, therefore, there's a significant amount of useless bi-product. What's more, mining is a costly endeavour. Some estimates put the electricity consumption costs of the entire Bitcoin mining operation in the region of US$500 million per year. In fact, one study has equated the entire power consumption of Bitcoin mining to Ireland's average electricity consumption. And that's just for Bitcoin; a whole range of new cryptocurrencies are emerging that utilise some forms of PoW algorithm.</p><p>Given the volatility of many cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin, there are few merchants that accept payment in Bitcoin or other cryptocurrencies today. Nodes only see value in being paid in cryptocurrencies if they can sell their cryptocurrency rewards for 'fiat currency' which they need to pay their electricity bills. Cryptocurrency exchanges are being established to enable this conversion. But the question one must ask is who will be the buyers on the other side of an exchange converting their fiat currency into cryptocurrencies. It can only really be speculators betting that the 'price' of the cryptocurrency will increase. The whole Bitcoin system is premised on the belief that the cryptocurrencies used to reward nodes will increase in value over time.</p><p>Setting up a POW mining operation is a risky business. It requires massive resources in computing and energy, with rewards being granted every 10 min across the node community. A small node will barely make enough rewards over a time period to justify the expense. The only way POW nodes can assure a return on their investment is through pooling their resources with other nodes, contributing their mining power and receiving the corresponding fraction of the rewards earned by the pool. These pools have strong economies of scale, so successful cryptocurrencies end up with a majority of their mining power in 3-4 pools. So you end up with permission-less Blockchain that is actually not decentralised, but centralised around a few large pool of centrally controlled nodes. Permission-less POW Blockchains must therefore trust the humans controlling the dominant mining pools not to collude, as well as the core developers of the protocol itself who provide the ongoing governance function for the Blockchain and carry out updates of the code. You must place your trust in developers of wallet software and developers of exchanges not to write bugs. You must trust the users and owners of the smart contracts built on the Blockchain to keep their secret key, secret and not lose it. Finally, you must trust the speculators to keep providing the funds needed to keep the 'price' of the 'coin (Bitcoin)' to keep going up-otherwise the nodes will simply lose interest and the whole system will fall over. Therefore, where you started out to build a trust-less, decentralised system, you end up with:</p><p>• Untrusted system: a trust-less system that trusts a lot of people you have every reason not to trust; 57 • Centralisation system: a decentralised system that is centralised around a few large mining pools based out of China that you have no way of knowing aren't colluding; • Mutable system: an immutable system that either has bugs you cannot fix, or is not immutable (forks); • Questionable security: a system whose security depends on it being expensive to run and which is thus dependent upon a continuing inflow of funds from speculators.</p><p>These are issues that the Blockchain community has started to recognise and we are likely to see a shift away from the current POW consensus process towards less onerous energy hungry mechanisms, such as Proof of Stake (POS) and others. That journey has just started and it may be a few years before these are developed and trusted.</p><p>It is for these reasons, that the major focus of Blockchains for practical use to date, have been permission-based systems, like IBM's Hyperledger and R3's Corda where accessibility can be controlled by design and participants can opt-in to the desired level of disclosure and shared access. <ref type="bibr">58</ref> Both Hyperledger and Corda allow participants to control who can see what information about the transactions <ref type="bibr">57</ref> As Nick Szabo tweeted, Bitcoin is the most secure financial network on the planet. But its centralised peripheral companies are among the most insecure. It is estimated that 10% of the ether raised in ICOs has already been stolen, mostly from wallets. A particular point of vulnerability at the edge of Blockchain networks lies in exchanges that trade cryptocurrencies for dollars or other government backed currencies. In 2014, the most prominent Bitcoin exchange, Mt. Goz collapsed after hackers were able to steal a significant amount of currency, then worth about US$400 million in a series of thefts. Another major exchange, Bitfinex was hacked in 2016, losing cryptocurrency valued around US$70 million at the time.  submitted to the ledger. This is not to say that permission-less systems are not dead, there are still many applications of permission-less Blockchains, primarily in the field of various cryptocurrencies (albeit using alternatives to POW like POS which is detailed later-however these are facing significant regulatory hurdles). When you delve deeper and overcome the recent hype around Blockchain, you come to the conclusion that whilst permission-less Blockchains are likely to come under increasing pressure, both regulatory and through its own design, there remains potential for permissioned Blockchains. There are an increasing number of applications emerging within a range of industries that are using Blockchain. Some of these include:</p><p>• In the pharmaceutical sector: Farmatrust is developing Blockchain based digital solutions and services which provides accountability and transparency for the entire supply chain from the drug manufacturers to the pharmacies distributed across the country. 59 • In agriculture: Blockchain has been used to manage and authenticate harvesting of resources to ensure sustainable practices. The Instituto BVRio has developed an online trading platform it has termed a 'Responsible Timber Exchange' to increase efficiency, transparency and reduce fraud and corruption in timber trading. 60 • In fishing: Provenance, a UK-based start-up, worked with the International Pole and Line Association (IPLA) to pilot a public Blockchain tuna-tracing system from Indonesia to consumers in the UK. <ref type="bibr">61</ref> Ventures such as FishCoin are developing a utility token tradable for mobile phone top-up minutes in an attempt to incentivise fisheries to provide information on their catch. The data captured is then transferred down the chain of custody until it reaches consumers. Such data could also be invaluable for governments seeking to better manage global fish stocks. 62 • In food supply: Carrefour Supermarkets have recently introduced an application where customers can scan products to receive information on a product's source and production processes. 63 • In ecology: Plastic Bank has created a social enterprise that issues a financial reward in the form of a cryptographic token in exchange for depositing collected ocean recyclables such as plastic containers, cans or bottles. <ref type="bibr">64</ref>   another Blockchain application in development that will enable people to return their used plastic containers in exchange for a token from automated machines in Europe and around the world. <ref type="bibr">65</ref> Gainforest is using Blockchain to incentivise farmers in the Amazon to preserve the rainforest in return for internationally crowd funded financial rewards. Remote sensing using satellites verifies the preservation of a patch of forest, which then triggers a smart contract using Blockchain technology to transfer payment. 66 • In carbon trading: Ben &amp; Jerry's is piloting a Blockchain platform to assign a carbon credit to each tub of ice cream sold, allowing consumers to offset their carbon footprint. <ref type="bibr">67</ref> Poseidon is another company that has developed a platform which enables consumers to offset their carbon. <ref type="bibr">68</ref> Payment goes directly to one of Ecosphere+'s forest conservation projects. The retailer's POS system shows the carbon impact of a product (in KG) and adds the price for the required carbon offset to the customer's bill.  20% of the total cost. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">75</ref> Bank wire transfers can take fees of 10-15%. These new Fintech start-ups are developing permission-based Blockchain systems to reduce these commissions and provide a faster payment system. A May 2016 Goldman Sachs report suggests that strong account and payment information on a Blockchain could improve data quality and reduce compliance costs, savings US$3 to US$5 billion annually in AML expenses. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">76</ref> • In compliance: Start-up Polycoin has an AML/KYC solution that involves analysing transactions. <ref type="bibr">77</ref> Those transactions identified as being suspicious are forwarded on to compliance officers. Another start-up Tradle 78 is developing an application called Trust in Motion (TiM). Characterised as an 'Instagram for KYC', TiM allows customers to take a snapshot of key documents (passport, utility bill, etc.). Once verified by the bank, this data is cryptographically stored on the Blockchain. • In trading: Numerous stock and commodities exchanges are prototyping Blockchain applications for the services they offer, including the ASX (Australian Securities Exchange), the Deutsche Borse (Frankfurt's stock exchange) and the JPX (Japan Exchange Group). <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">79</ref> Nasdaq has launched Linq, a platform for private market trading. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">80</ref> More recently, Nasdaq announced the development of a trial Blockchain project for proxy voting on the Estonian Stock Market. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">81</ref> • In government: Honduras was the first government to announce Blockchain based land registry projects in 2015, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">82</ref> although the current status of that project is unclear. Recently, the Republic of Georgia cemented a deal with the Bitfury Group to develop a Blockchain system for property titles. <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">83</ref> Reportedly, Hernando de Soto, the high-profile economist and property rights advocate, will be advising on the project. Sweden also announced it was experimenting with a Blockchain application for property titles. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">84</ref> Governments are also looking at using Blockchain for managing asset registries, with initiatives or trials being conducted by Sweden, <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">85</ref> UK, <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">86</ref> India, <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">87</ref> Georgia, <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">88</ref> Ghana <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">89</ref> and Russia. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">90</ref> • In digital identities: government are trying to use Blockchain identity services, the foremost being Estonia, with the e-Identity ID card. <ref type="bibr">91</ref> The country's Blockchain enabled platform, known as X-Road, is used to provide integrated services to citizens across multiple programs through their Digital IDs. It also uses the platform technology to connect Uber drivers directly with the tax office, adding income from rides directly to their tax return. Trials are also ongoing or in development in Switzerland, <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">92</ref> Finland, <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">93</ref> India, 94 Japan, <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">95</ref> the USA <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">96</ref> and UNICEF. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">97</ref> The UN is also trialling provision of refugee identities using Blockchains in a collaboration with Accenture and Microsoft. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">98</ref> 146 5 Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization • In cryptocurrencies: some governments are going even further, with trials of payment and cryptocurrencies in Russia, <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">99</ref> Venezuela 100 and the United Arab Emirates <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">101</ref> and with experiments in Japan, <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">102</ref> Singapore <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">103</ref> and Australia <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">104</ref> extending to banking and trading services. Beyond finance, interest has been shown in energy markets in the UK, 105 USA <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">106</ref> and Chile. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">107</ref> • In healthcare: countries such as Estonia, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">108</ref> Sweden <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">109</ref> and the UK, <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">110</ref> as well as several USA states, <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">111</ref> have shown interest in the use of Blockchains to certify patient medical records. Estonia's X-Road interconnects hospitals, clinics, and other organisations. It implements a unified Electronic Health Record that supplies medical practitioners with information about patients' health while protecting their privacy. For example, the 'e-prescription' system allows doctors to create prescriptions and make them immediately available to pharmacies.</p><p>Patients can then collect their medicines directly from the pharmacy without having to visit the doctor for a hard copy of the prescription. The Estonian government claims that the use of X-Road saves Estonians over 800 years of working time every year. <ref type="bibr">112</ref> Several much hyped examples of revolutionary Blockchain opportunities have however failed to meet expectations. A version of Blockchain by Imogen Heap for the music industry, on Ethereum generated sales of US$133. <ref type="bibr">113</ref> Mycelia uses the Blockchain to create a peer-to-peer music distribution system. Founded by the UK singer-songwriter Imogen Heap, Mycelia was meant to enable musicians to sell songs directly to audiences, as well as license samples to producers and allocate royalties to songwriters and musicians, all of these functions being automated by smart contracts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5.9</head><p>Alternative Implementations to POW Blockchains Lightning Network needs to do routing. Many people have pointed out the difficulty of routing in the system. The sender of a payment needs to know not merely a complete path of nodes to the intended recipient, but also the liquidity of each of the channels linking them. It can work only if all users have channels to one or more of a small number of large 'payment hubs' which each have channels to all the other 'payment hubs' with large endowments in each channel.</p><p>Lightning fees are per-hop, so shorter payment chains will require smaller fees than longer ones. This means hubs with many connections will have an advantage over hubs with smaller numbers of connections. Over time the Lightning Network is likely to become more and more concentrated. Unfortunately this sounds a lot like the current banking system and many do not see real value. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.9.2">IOTA</head><p>IOTA is based on the idea of doing away with building a linear chain of blocks of transactions, in which a block validates every preceding block and thus every preceding transaction. Rather, each IOTA transaction validates two randomly selected preceding transactions. Thus it constructs a Directed Acyclic Graph 114 of transactions. By doing so it eliminates the need for miners, which each have to store a copy of the entire chain. The protocol was designed specifically for use within IOT on connected devices, which have limited storage and compute resources. However some observers note that for IOTA to work, IOT devices need to be in sync with what is called a 'tangle'. Something that most IOT devices would not have the capability to do. 115</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.9.3">Ethereum</head><p>Unlike LN and IOTA, Ethereum has been live since mid-2015 and is being used quite extensively by the Initial Coin Offering (ICO) community and many other Blockchain based projects. Ethereum is planning to become a decentralised super-computer wherein anyone, anywhere can rent out some computational power and create decentralised applications (Dapps) which can run on top of the Ethereum platform. Smart contracts are how things get done in the Ethereum ecosystem. When someone wants to get a particular task done in Ethereum they initiate a smart contract with one or more people.</p><p>To create a healthy ecosystem on top of Ethereum, it is absolutely essential that the Dapps built on top of it can interact with one another seamlessly. This is where ERC20 comes in. ERC20 is a guide of rules and regulations that help create a blueprint for Ethereum-based smart contracts. This helps ensure that applications and tokens built on the Ethereum platform are interoperable.</p><p>The Ethereum network however suffers from capacity issues-as was found when cryptokitties popularity exploded in December 2017 with the Ethereum network struggling to keep pace. Ethereum's governance players started to discuss a proposed fix, changing the basis for consensus from Ethereum's Proof of Work (POW) to Proof of Stake (POS), which works similarly to PoW except that instead of computers validating transactions and receiving rewards equivalent to their relative computing power, POS uses token holders. Those who hold tokens can 'stake' their 114 A Directed Acyclic Graph, is a graph data structure that has vertices and edges. (A vertex is a point on the graph, and an edge is the path from one vertex to another.) DAG guarantee that there is no way to start at any vertex and follow a sequence of edges that eventually loops back to that vertex again (i.e. no loops). This allows us to have a sequence of nodes (or vertices) in topological order. <ref type="bibr">115</ref> Tangle the underlying data structure that IOTA is built on, is actually a 'blockless' Blockchain. Rather than transactions created by users being incorporated into blocks by miners, users function as both the miners and the creators of transactions. tokens (staking means to temporarily place the tokens in a locked smart contract, until staking is over) and in exchange, confirm transactions and receive rewards based on the relative number of tokens held. With POS, given you must stake your coins, any malicious behaviour would result in the loss of all staked coins. So if you bought 51% of all tokens, you would immediately lose your substantial investment. However there seem to be a number of problems with POS. The design of these networks is such that early users would get vastly better rewards than later users for the same effort. The individuals who are defining the POS mechanism and defining what 'malicious behaviour' consists of, are all early adopters with large potential stakes they can use to dominate the POS governance process. They will thus garner most of the POS reward, which will reinforce their dominance of the process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.9.4">Cross-Chain Technologies</head><p>As decentralised Blockchains are developed, there is a risk that they will not be able to interact with each other at scale. By enabling ledgers to interact with one another with a communication protocol layer, improvements in security, speed, cost of transactions can be attained. There are multiple approaches to obtaining interoperability. Technology to facilitate interactions between different Blockchains, also known as 'cross-chain' technology are being developed allowing for interoperability by offering a platform that lets various Blockchains interact with one another and in essence function as a single chain. One of the simplest forms is through a relayer. These utilities check for transactions in one chain and 'relay' that information to another. BTC Relay, for instance, allows Ethereum smart contracts to verify a Bitcoin transaction without any intermediary. This enables Ethereum Distributed Apps and smart contracts to accept Bitcoin payments. Real Blockchain interoperability is not possible today, but most use what are called 'hops' to move from one Blockchain to another. A variety of projects, including Cosmos, Ripple's Interledger Protocol and Polkadot hope to deliver cross-chain interoperability so that users need not worry about which coin or which Blockchain powers the application they interact with.</p><p>Nevertheless many users will be concerned that as decentralised ledgers start interacting with each other, privacy will be at risk. Therefore protocols are now being developed that permit data to be shared seamlessly across both centralised and decentralised databases whilst safeguarding privacy. Innovations in cryptography such as Zero-Knowledge Proofs (ZKP), 116 differential privacy, Fully Homomorphic 116 A Zero-Knowledge Proof (ZKP) is when a prover convinces a verifier that they have some secret knowledge, without revealing the knowledge directly. In other words, a program can have secret inputs and the prover reveals nothing to the verifier. ZKPs provide fundamental primitives that can be used to build privacy-preserving mechanisms. ZKPs can be used to guarantee that transactions are valid despite the fact that information about the sender, the recipient, and other transaction details remain hidden. Examples include: https://z.cash/ Encryption (FHE) <ref type="bibr">117</ref> and Secure Multi-party Computation (SMPC) 118 may enable data to remain private and secure but still move through public networks. I suspect you would need a PhD in mathematics or cryptography to really make sense of these innovations, something I do not have and will therefore swiftly move on.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.10">Regulating Blockchain</head><p>There has been a lot of discussion within many regulatory authorities around new emerging Blockchain enabled financial systems which they believe are trying to circumvent existing regulatory rules. Regulatory authorities quite rightly under those circumstances have looked at some implementations of Blockchain and token economics with a degree of suspicion. Attempting to regulate a permission-less system where there is no controlling legal entity is a complicated task. Consequently, regulation so far has targeted cryptocurrency business applications such as exchanges and wallet providers. 119 I am not advocating more regulation per se. Innovation has almost always outpaced regulation. Blockchain development and implementation are happening at a pace well beyond the capacity of regulators to respond. Trying to heavily regulate such a space is likely to do more long-term damage than good. Many regulators and central banks are coming to the conclusion, which I had written about a couple of years back, that Blockchain and associated technologies can actually be tools for regulatory oversight. They can fundamentally improve the transparency of the financial system, embed compliance and real-time reporting, protect the end-to-end integrity of the system and nurture further levels of trust within and outside of the system.</p><p>Whilst good regulation is critical-you cannot have good regulation when you do not know the lay of the land. At the same time, you cannot not regulate, just because you do not have the full facts. The path forward must balance the priorities of regulators to uphold the law, preserve the integrity of capital markets, whilst allowing innovation to flourish.</p><p>We need to move from strict regulation to good governance. Just because you are decentralised does not mean you need to be disorganised. 120 Some regulatory authorities are themselves becoming a full node on the Blockchain with <ref type="bibr">117</ref> A fully homomorphic encryption system enables computations to be performed on encrypted data without needing to first decrypt the data. <ref type="bibr">118</ref> SMPC works by splitting the data into several, smaller parts, each of which is masked using cryptographic techniques. Each small, encrypted piece of data is sent to a separate independent server, so that each server only contains a small part of the data. An individual or organisation looking to discover the 'secret' (i.e., uncover the data) will need to aggregate the encoded data. multi-signatory rights to view all the transactions on the Blockchain. As the regulatory space matures, we may see regulators provided broad rights, which may include broader governance capabilities, which will enable them to not only have broad oversight of all activities, but ensure the network is run in a manner that is not contrary to agreed governing principles. The regulatory authority in this context will move away from a policing force, trying to police a problem it does not really understand. It would instead collaboratively work with the industry to develop regulatory governance mechanisms that can provide the necessary levels of oversight and control required by the regulator to fulfil their statutory duties whilst allowing this nascent technology and business models to grow and flourish. This is already happening with some central banks mandating rights to be a node in many cryptocurrency implementations. Much has also been written about the impact cryptocurrencies can have on the broader global financial systems, some predicting or hoping that central banks' role will become irrelevant with the emergence of decentralised technology (or rather protocol) driven trust creating networks. The evidence to date is that government controlled central banks are unlikely to give up their central role in determining their monetary policy, their ability to manage interest rates, inflation or their currencies. Major established systems are typically more resilient than they appear.</p><p>I believe it is fair to say that decentralised Blockchain based applications must complement the role of central banks and indeed other regulatory agencies, rather than trying to bypass them. This is not to say that Blockchain based models will not be a disruptive force: the tokenization model, in which value resides in the network rather than its controlling operator, offers the potential for disruption-transferring power from the large and few to the small and many.</p><p>Participants on Blockchains need to trust in a decentralised model in which either there is no central control or that they can have effective shared control. At the same time, governments need to trust that their citizens will be protected, taxes will be paid and criminal activity effectively monitored and policed. Whilst Blockchains may have inherent mechanisms of trust built in, these need to be complimented with mechanisms of Governance and Law.</p><p>The role of regulatory authorities (in the financial space at least) is pivoted around three pillars:</p><p>• Pillar I: to protect consumers (sometimes from themselves in the case of investing in high risk investments) or ensure universal access to services for all consumers; • Pillar II: to protect the competitive process and prevent any abuse that may result from market power or dominance (however these maybe defined); • Pillar III: to protect the integrity and security of the system itself-i.e. ensure it is fully trustworthy.</p><p>On the first pillar: consumer protection-Blockchain based systems are helping expand financial inclusion to previously unbanked populations (especially in international transactions), one of the key mandates of regulators. Whilst many regulatory authorities have expressed concerns around cryptoassets, most appear to be reaching at least an interim conclusion that the existing regulatory systems are capable of regulating such activities.</p><p>Sometimes the regulatory solution is to expand the licensing regime to capture these new entities or activities. In some countries, a licensing framework approach for Blockchains applications has also started to emerge, in particular, for cryptocurrency application environments. For example, the State of New York is offering 'BitLicense', which allows business to conduct virtual currency activities on Distrubuted Ledger Technology/Blockchain infrastructure.</p><p>The traditional ethos of high quality regulation being 'technology neutral' means that most of the existing regulatory tools should be capable of regulating these services, whatever technology may be used to deliver it. The broader question of managing cross-border activity which Blockchain enabled systems enable is not a new one. The Internet has vexed many regulatory authorities for many years, without definitive solutions to date. Trying to find solutions for regulation of cross border activities through Blockchain activities may be as futile as ever, although there are some interesting ideas emerging.</p><p>On the second pillar: competition-it is too early for regulatory authorities to have concern in the Blockchain and tokenization space. It is still very much a fragmented space without the emergence of dominant players. However, one area where regulators need to pay attention is the interoperability of different Blockchain based systems. This becomes important, as will be discussed later.</p><p>On the third pillar: system integrity-it is fair to say that regulatory authorities have started from a perspective that Blockchains (read cryptocurrencies and in particular Bitcoin) have inherent regulatory problems; significant volatility, reduced transparency and are being used by unscrupulous people (tax evasion, 121 money laundering, terrorist financing and other Dark Web activities). This is a misconception. Blockchains have five basic principles underlying the technology that actually make the system more transparent, robust and resilient:</p><p>1. Distributed Database: given that each party on a Blockchain has access to the entire database and its complete history, every party can verify the records of its transaction partners directly without an intermediary-there is no single point of failure, improving system resiliency. 122 2. Peer-to-Peer Transmission: given that each node stores and forwards information to all other nodes-there is a single shared version of the truth.</p><p>121 Some countries consider them as digital money (subject to related regulation), while others treat cryptocurrencies as digital products or commodities (subject to VAT). Regulators in the USA have different criteria around Bitcoin for instance: some consider it as money (FinCEN, SEC), while others consider it a commodity (CFTC), or even a property (Internal Revenue Service). <ref type="bibr">122</ref> Most DLT or Blockchain technologies use Public-Private Key Infrastructure (PKI) to secure rights to view and add to blocks-therefore the risk of system security is somewhat transferred to the PKI operator and the individuals that need to guard their respective 'keys'. 3. Transparency: every transaction is visible to anyone with appropriate access to the system. Each node or user on a Blockchain has a unique address that identifies it. Every transaction is associated with such address. Users can choose to remain pseudo anonymous or provide proof of their identity to others. Blockchain transactions are not tied directly to your identity, so they may appear more private. Anyone in the world can create a new wallet anonymously and transact using it. However, it's not quite that simple. The appearance of total anonymity is misleading. It's true that a person can preserve his or her privacy as long as the pseudonym is not linked to the individual, however with a Blockchain platform like Ethereum, users are interacting with smart contracts that handle more than just simple value transfers. All the details about these smart contracts are public on the Ethereum Blockchain, including senders and recipients, transaction data itself, the code executed and the state stored inside the contract. Contrary to popular belief, there is more transparency with Blockchains (that does however lead to difficult questions for organisations that make use of smart contracts for critical business data into a Blockchain where hackers and competitors can view the information). 4. Irreversibility of Records: given that once a transaction is entered in the database and the accounts are updated, the records cannot be altered because they are linked to every transaction record that came before them through hash functions-the data is immutable. Blockchains support more robust automated and accurate record keeping, improving the audit and oversight capabilities for regulatory authorities. 5. Verifiable data and reconciliation: Blockchains provide access to real-time verifiable data, potentially reconciling end-to-end processes that would otherwise be difficult or impossible to do, through smart contracts. Having all the transaction information in a shared register in almost real-time will allow regulatory authorities to monitor financial activity without having to wait to receive the required reports from the various financial institutions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.10">Regulating Blockchain 153</head><p>Furthermore, where Blockchains are combined with trustworthy multi-signature and cryptography functions, the security of the entire system and data can be enhanced. Using the technology, data can be hashed onto the Blockchain and only accessed with signature approval from a predefined group of people; something that would enable the open transparent nature of Blockchain technology to be reconciled with data protection regulations such as GDPR. One aspect of GDPR that many commentators state may not gel well with Blockchain technology is the 'right to be forgotten'. I suspect this a red herring-GDPR was never intended to be used by unscrupulous individuals to use the GDPR provisions to wipe clear illegal transactions or activities. The 'right to be forgotten' is not an unconstrained right. Technology solutions could enable the right to be forgotten to be implemented for all practical purposes, in that relevant data about the person is no longer publicly visible, even if such data is not deleted from the Blockchain.</p><p>When you examine the inherent principles underlying Blockchain technology, you come to realise that Blockchain technology (especially in the context of smart contracts) can support the regulatory authority systematically adhere to the third regulatory pillar: making the end-to-end system more trustworthy. It can more effectively and efficiently bridge the gap of trust between those they regulate and the public. The real issue to implementing this solution is that many permissioned Blockchains are global in nature and may have multiple consortia. A regulatory authority's powers are however local in nature. One solution that is being promoted is that regulatory authorities from different geographies have presence in each of the global consortia, with access rights to the information needed to perform their supervision activities related to the entities that fall under their jurisdiction. Then, information extracted by one regulatory authority from every consortia is shared in a private 'regulatory authority' network-thus combining all the information needed for monitoring global transactions.</p><p>For a regulator friendly system to work, there needs to be interoperability of different Blockchains for which the regulatory authority may need to be a node, as well as interoperability with existing systems. A regulator having to have nodes on multiple Blockchains, each potentially with different protocols and reporting standards will make the life of the regulator difficult. There is already some collaboration in this space. In September 2017, R3 announced that it had developed a prototype of a system together with the UK Financial Conduct Authority, the Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc and another global bank, built using R3's Blockchain called Corda, which enables banks to generate automated delivery receipts for the regulator each time a mortgage is booked. There are other projects like Polkadot, Atomic Swap and others with a similar aim.</p><p>A common set of standards and format needs to be agreed about the precise regulatory information that needs to be stored in the ledger, so regulators can easily extract the needed data. The International Organisation for Standardization (ISO) is developing technology-agnostic standards for Blockchain and distributed ledger technologies. Namely, ISO has established a technical committee (ISO/TC 307) that is currently working to develop 11 ISO standards, with 42 participating entities and 12 observing members. This would have a significant impact on the standardisation of Blockchain and distributed ledger technologies, one that might be comparable to the effect of W3C on the World Wide Web.</p><p>An alternate and perhaps more effective approach than standardising technology, is to standardise data formats. Since network participants will often need to implement data processing capability on their own specialised software platforms, it might be more versatile to standardise on data exchange formats and trusted sources of data (oracles), but leave the choice of technology to the network participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.11">Smart Contracts</head><p>The digital nature of the ledger enables smart contracts, which means that Blockchain transactions can be tied to computational logic and in essence be programmed. Therefore, users can set up algorithms and rules that automatically trigger transactions between nodes. Smart contracts can be programmed to generate instructions for downstream processes such as payment instructions, if and when reference conditions are met. Like passive data, they become immutable once accepted onto the ledger. Counterparties need to establish obligations and settlement instructions (put assets under custody of the smart contract(s) and establish conditions for execution). Upon an event trigger (e.g. transaction initiated/information received); the contract would be executed based on terms of the contract. Movement of value based on conditions being met, which could be 'on-net' or 'off-net' (e.g. issuance of settlement instructions and reconciliation), would occur and the distributed ledger updated.</p><p>Unlike a normal contract, which is drafted by a lawyer, signed by partaking parties and enforced by law, a smart contract sets out a relationship with cryptographic code. In simple terms, smarts contracts are self-executing, written into code, and built as complex 'if-then' statements (meaning that they will only be fulfilled if the established conditions are met). Smart contracts tend to be written in a JavaScript-like language and embedded in Ethereum's Blockchain. They are today mainly used to implement Initial Coin Offerings, games such as Cryptokitties and gambling parlours, but have the potential for a wide range of activities, replacing many of today' manual contract execution processes.</p><p>Most smart contracts will need to interface with the outside world. Those outside sources are called 'oracles'. 123 Some oracles are just traditional data feeds designed with interfaces for smart contracts to process them in an automated way. Oracles can also be humans who can feed information into a smart contract-especially in the context of arbitration-here each of the two parties has a private key and a third key is given to an expert human arbitrator. The smart contract requires two of three keys in order to execute. If the parties agree that the contract has been fully performed, they provide their keys and the smart contract executes. If there is a dispute, the parties turn to a human arbitrator who either provides a key along with that of the party seeking to enforce the contract or refuse it, therefore preventing completion of the transaction. Some believe that smart contracts may be the most transformative Blockchain application. A firm could signal via Blockchain that a particular good has been received or the product could have GPS functionality, which would automatically log a location update that in turn, triggers a payment, eliminating inefficiencies, unnecessary intermediary costs and reduce the potential for fraud or errors.</p><p>The implications go beyond these immediate transactions. Firms are built on contracts, from incorporation to buyer-supplier relationships to employee relations. If contracts are automated, then what will happen to traditional firm structures, <ref type="bibr">123</ref> Smart contracts use what are called oracles. An oracle is a party which relays information between smart contracts and external data sources. It essentially acts as a data carrier between smart contracts on the Blockchain and external data sources off the Blockchain. So one approach to keeping information 'private' is simply to use oracles to fetch private information from an external data source. processes and intermediaries like lawyers and accountants? And what about managers? Taken to the extreme, smart contracts have been deemed potentially revolutionary across a range of industries with some observers going as far as saying that they will replace traditional contracts and lawyers. Those who say smart contracts will render lawyers useless usually believe the entire legal agreement is expressed in its code. Essentially meaning that code is law and as such lawyers are unlikely to be required.</p><p>That assumption remains open to question. Most current implementations of smart contracts are aimed at complementing lawyers rather than replacing them. Virtually every economist who has studied the issue, argues that in practice complete contracts are simply not possible. The world is a complicated place, the future is largely unknowable and we humans have limited intelligence. These and other factors combine to make it prohibitively difficult and most likely impossible to write a complete contract-one that truly does away with the need for lawyers. Agreements incorporating smart contracts will not be immune to disputes and legal challenges. Parties will disagree about the terms governing their performance and disagree on how the smart contract was intended to operate. There could also be bugs in the smart contract itself, creating complications or misaligned incentives. The risk of mistakes becomes magnified as smart contracts increasingly interact with outside data provided by trusted oracles, but also require humans to perform their terms. <ref type="bibr">124</ref> Parties aggrieved at the results of a smart contract will still need to resort to litigation; in order to reverse the position of the parties. Rather than seeking to have alleged promissory obligations fulfilled, complaining parties will now seek to undo or reverse completed transactions. Claims of breach will transform into claims of restitution. This will affect legal standards such as causes of action and burdens of proof, with unpredictable consequences.</p><p>The problem with smart contracts is that they are publicly accessible and anything stored within smart contracts is open for anyone to view. While this provides openness and transparency, it also makes smart contracts very attractive targets for hackers. The first big smart contract was The Decentralized Autonomous Organisation ('DAO'), operating without a corporate hierarchy, organised around the concept of a town hall, with the potential to give voice to all investors. The DAO was designed as a series of contracts that would raise funds for Ethereum based projects and disperse them based on the votes of members. An initial token offering was conducted, exchanging ethers for 'The DAO tokens' that would allow stakeholders to vote on proposals, including ones to grant funding to a particular project. That token offering raised more than US$150 million worth of ether at thencurrent prices, distributing over 1 billion The DAO tokens. In May 2016 however, news broke that a flaw in The DAO's smart contract had been exploited, allowing the removal of more than 3 million ethers (worth around US$55 million at the time). Subsequent exploitations allowed for more funds to be removed, which ultimately triggered a 'white hat' effort by token holders to secure the remaining funds. The loot 124 OpenLaw, 2018. was restored by a 'hard fork', the Blockchain's version of mutability. Since then it has become the norm for 'smart contract' authors to make them 'upgradeable', so that bugs can be fixed. 'Upgradeable' is another way of saying 'immutable in name only'.</p><p>In the case of The DAO, the difference between a legitimate transaction and theft came down to intent, which is something that computers cannot determine under the terms of the smart contract. These are the sort of things that courts tease out all the time.</p><p>The DAO raised many novel legal questions. Most importantly, did the exploit break laws and if so, which ones? For example, did the person or group that exploited The DAO commit theft or fraud or violate cyber security laws? Was The DAO a partnership? Did token holders have fiduciary responsibilities to each other? Do The DAO programmers or curators have any liability for the exploitation of The DAO tokens? Which courts around the globe have jurisdiction over each of these issues? Given these inherent legal issues, software vendors have explicitly avoided accepting liability for the damages caused by vulnerability exploitation. As software has become embedded more deeply into processes integral to an individual, business or even a nation-state, the potential damages associated with exploiting software vulnerabilities have also grown.</p><p>One way to conceptualise how liability could be distributed is based on risk. In thinking about assigning responsibility for securing vulnerabilities, two main questions emerge. The first is, who is liable or otherwise responsible for securing software? At least four broad sets of liability regimes exist, ranging from no liability to holding vendors liable for their software:</p><p>• No liability, code close-sourced: this is the current norm where counterparties to software vendors may negotiate some level of accountability by exception. In this regime, if damages arise as a consequence of a vulnerability being exploited, the vendor is not held responsible; • No liability, code open-sourced: in exchange for being released of liability, vendors could be required to open-source underlying code. In theory, users and implementers of software would be more empowered to address vulnerabilities on their own. In this regime, if a vendor has open-sourced the code, the vendor is not responsible for consequences of software being exploited; • User, implementer liable: users and implementers could be held liable for damages arising from software being exploited. In practice, such a regime would create heightened incentives for users to contract for secure software. Within this context, the possibility also exists of differential liability that differs between enterprises with dedicated security teams and consumers (with more responsibility being attached to entities 'that should know better'); • Vendor liable: vendors could be held liable for damages arising from software being exploited. For example, if a vendor did not issue a patch for a known software vulnerability, the vendor would be held liable if damages arose as a consequence (thereby heightening incentives for vendors to design and maintain secure software). The second question is around how liability should shift when software transitions to its end of life, or vendors go out of business? Given that most software vendors cannot afford to support software ad infinitum, there are justifiable concerns around attaching liability to software for perpetuity. To address those concerns, some commentators have proposed a sliding scale of liability, such that liability shifts as software enters 'end of life'. For example, software may begin as a vendor's responsibility but as it becomes 'end of life', liability may be transferred to users/ implementers. In such a regime, vendors would be held responsible for designing and maintaining secure software and there would be commercial incentives for users and implementers to upgrade to newer versions of software, when available. The whole debate around liability is also becoming heightened in the context of AI and who is liable for developing products that incorporates AI. This is discussed in a subsequent chapter.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.12">Token Economics, Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings (ICO)</head><p>Blockchains create the potential to tokenize (monetise) literally everything. I have already talked about tokens in the context of cryptocurrencies and Bitcoin specifically. However tokens can be used in a range of applications. Tokenization basically allows for fractional ownership of different assets categories, which can lower barriers to investment, improve liquidity, and facilitate tradability. Blockchains through tokenization enable fractional ownership of these asset categories whereby any owner can represent his property with a property address and wallet address on the Blockchain platform and issue a number of security tokens against that specific property.</p><p>Tokens themselves are simply a type of value instrument. The rules under which these instruments are generated, distributed and managed are decided by community members through agreed governance rules or by the organisation issuing the tokens. Cryptocurrency networks are in essence technologies of governance. The ability for tokens to enable speedy, secure and low friction value transfer will underpin the highly automated IOT economy and provide a mechanism for its governance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.12.1">Token Classification</head><p>Although there is no established classification of tokens, the categorisation introduced by the Swiss Financial Market Supervisory Authority ('FINMA') based on the economic functions of the tokens proves to be widely accepted, which nevertheless is being modified over time as necessary: 125 • Utility Tokens are intended to provide access to a specific application or service but are not accepted as a means of payment for other applications. The value of the service or product depends on the perception of the investor, making him comparable to a purchaser of a product or service. These are comparable to a voucher and to crowd funding by coupon. They allow prefunding of a future business without diluting ownership; • Asset Tokens (or Security Tokens) represent assets such as a debt or equity claim against the issuer as they promise the owner a share in the future profits or capital flows of the underlying company (sale of the tokens, dividends, interest). They resemble bonds, financial instruments or derivatives. Security tokens are expected to grow to the largest token market because of the benefits of fractional ownership and increased liquidity. These types of tokens fall under existing securities laws and markets; • Payment Tokens represent a means of payment for goods and services and are true virtual currencies with the most prominent example being Bitcoin. It is used as a form of payment and store of value, designed to serve the purpose of bolstering an independent and peer-to-peer monetary system-although some of these payment tokens are not used as payment instruments but as speculative investments. In addition, since no central bank intervenes to smooth extreme price fluctuations, payments token volatility is much higher than fiat currencies, as has been the case with Bitcoin-which has proved to be too volatile to be used as a payment token. For example Bitcoin rose from around US$5950 to above US$19,700 within 1 year-and likewise the depreciation has been equally rapid. It is highly unlikely that retailers would accept Bitcoins as a means of payment, when it is as volatile as this; • Stable Coin Tokens which are a subset of payment tokens, take cognisance of the fact that a currency should act as a medium of monetary exchange and a mode of storage of monetary value and that such value should remain relatively stable over longer time horizon. Users will refrain from adopting it if they are not sure of its purchasing power tomorrow. The reason fiat currencies remain stable is because there are reserves that back them and central banks with the authority and power to stabilise the currency. Stable coins aim to replicate this stability by either holding reserves such as a basket of fiat currencies, precious metals or commodities, or pegging the stablecoin to something more stable with algorithms that perform the equivalent function of a central bank for fiat currencies.</p><p>Tokens combining several features of these different token categories are referred to as Hybrid Tokens.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.12.2">Regulating Cryptoassets, ICOs and Cryptocurrencies</head><p>Globally, governments and regulators have been slow off the mark when it comes to cryptocurrencies. Most have sat on the fence. Most believed this was fad and would soon disappear. For a majority of the period, the key cryptocurrency has been Bitcoin, which has been on a roller coaster ride with volatility changing by the hour. Under these circumstances most governments thought Bitcoin would effectively self-destruct and they didn't need to spend considerable time or effort trying to understand its effects, whether it needed to be regulated and how. <ref type="bibr">126</ref> That has recently changed, as more and more cryptocurrencies have emerged and their role has extended.</p><p>One of the key moments came when tokens where being used as a means of raising funds, so called Initial Coin Offerings (ICO). These ICOs can be thought of as an evolution of crowd funding where future users can finance the development of solutions and in turn become stakeholders in the system. An ICO like an IPO in mainstream investment, are a means of fundraising, used primarily by firms looking to create a new coin, app, or service whereby interested investors buy into the offering, either with fiat currency or with pre-existing digital tokens. In exchange for their support, investors receive a new cryptocurrency token specific to the ICO that could be classified as a security or utility token.</p><p>ICOs have become an increasingly popular method for start-ups and other companies to raise capital. Investors participate in the fundraising by transferring fiat currencies or cryptocurrencies, such as Bitcoin or Ether, to the issuer in exchange for these new digital tokens. Nevertheless, many investors had to take a hair-cut on their investments in ICOs and brought the issue to the attention of regulators. This opened Pandora's box for all things crypto. A report by ESMA Security and Markets Stakeholder Group, published in 2018, claims that 78% of listed coins/tokens were scams, whereas only 7% were deemed to be successful. <ref type="bibr">127</ref> The report also claimed that nearly 60% of these were issued in the USA and Switzerland in 2017, but by 2018, this had dwindled to 14% with the majority (60%) being issued from the Cayman Islands and Virgin Islands due to regulatory concerns.</p><p>The ICO Governance Foundation (IGF), a global self-regulatory initiative for token offerors based on a Swiss foundation, is developing standard registration form for ICOs, a registration database for investors and certification of custodial organisations to handle funds contributed to ICOs, in an attempt to provide some reassurance to investors and regulators.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.12.3">The Debate Between Utility and Securities Tokens</head><p>The most vital key question which arises when looking at cryptocurrencies is whether these tokens are utility tokens, security tokens, payment tokens or something else. Each carries very different policy and regulatory concerns. <ref type="bibr">126</ref> Liechtenstein is one of the few countries to have passed the Blockchain Act, which provides a comprehensive legal framework for digital assets. The Act will come into force on 1 January 2020. <ref type="bibr">127</ref> ESMA. (2018). Advice to ESMA: own initiative report on initial coin offerings and cryptoassets. ESMA22-106-1338, published 19 October 2018. The popularity of selling tokens via ICOs as a means of start-up fundraising has exploded in the last few years. Figures show approximately US$31.7 billion has been raised through some 1790 ICOs at the time of writing this book, dwarfing the amounts raised for Blockchain projects via traditional venture capital. <ref type="bibr">128</ref> The majority of ICOs are within the finance, trading, investment and payment sectors (over 37%).</p><p>The purchase of tokens issued in connection with an ICO can be qualified as a purchase of commodities, a purchase of rights or a purchase of securities, which may ultimately subject ICOs and their 'Whitepapers' to prospectus or other disclosure requirements. Regulations may not necessarily be limited to those of the jurisdiction governing the ICO. When marketed to investors residing or domiciled in another jurisdiction, financial regulatory rules of such jurisdiction may equally apply to the ICO. A governing law clause does not dispense the ICO issuer from compliance with such financial regulation.</p><p>The difficulties of applying the existing regulatory regime in the token space can be seen clearly when it comes to the use of cryptoassets. There a range of (conflicting) opinions from regulators on cryptoassets, from outright scepticism and bans in some countries, to more cautious investor warnings from others, 129 while yet other countries have introduced regimes to attract more crypto activity. <ref type="bibr">130</ref> In the USA, the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) has confirmed that investment and hybrid investment/utility tokens pass the so called 'Howey test', meaning those tokens are 'investment contracts' and therefore subject to USA securities laws. EU law relies on the transfer of units in the secondary market rather than on the investment character of the instrument to determine if they are a security instrument/token.</p><p>From a regulatory perspective, attempting to regulate a permission-less system like Bitcoin, where there is no controlling legal entity, is a complicated task. Consequently, regulation so far has targeted cryptocurrency business applications such as exchanges and wallet providers. <ref type="bibr">131</ref> Regulators tend to focus on cryptocurrency exchanges, because they provide a nexus between the cryptocurrency market and the traditional financial sector. In contrast, for permissioned systems where access is conditional and the participants are pre-screened, the existing regulatory framework should be able to provide sufficient oversight since the actors are already subject to regulatory obligations. Regulatory authorities have not been shy about enforcing regulations related to cryptoassets. A crypto exchange was fined US$110 million for failure to detect suspicious transactions and file suspicious activity reports. <ref type="bibr">132</ref> A key moment that brought regulatory authorities to the forefront has been Facebook's Libra project-which effectively proposes to issue stablecoins as an alternative to fiat currency (with the ability to trade in and out of Libra into fiat currencies). When an organisation with two and half billion users proposes an alternative to fiat currencies, it was no surprise that governments, central banks and regulators took notice. Policy makers are concerned about the risks that such stablecoins pose. They unsurprisingly want to prevent stablecoins from influencing open market operations, affecting monetary bases, weakening capital controls, draining deposits and increasing systemic risk. Facebook had aimed to launch Libra in the first half of 2020. Facebook knew people wouldn't trust it to wholly steer the cryptocurrency, so they recruited the founding members of the Libra Association, a not-for-profit consortium which would oversee the development of the token, based in Switzerland. Members of the association included, amongst others: Payment providers (MasterCard, PayPal, Visa), Technology and platforms (Booking Holdings, eBay, Facebook, Spotify, Uber), Telecommunications providers (Iliad, Vodafone) and a number of venture capital firms, as well as Non-profit and multilateral organisations and academic institutions. In total 28 founding members were listed. However USA lawmakers formally called on Facebook to cease all development of its Libra cryptocurrency in a letter sent to executives. Democrats from the USA House of Representatives wrote an open letter to Facebook, calling on a moratorium to all Libra development, while the Financial Services Committee and affiliated subcommittees held hearings to determine how it would operate and what safeguards would be implemented to protect user privacy. Many of the founding consortium members have since exited following this strong resistance from both the USA and other governments.</p><p>President Donald Trump signalled that cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin and Facebook's proposed Libra digital coin will face the full force of USA regulators if they want to become a bank. In a post on Twitter, as is his preferred medium, he said "If Facebook and other companies want to become a bank, they must seek a new banking charter and become subject to all banking regulations, just like other banks, both national and international". The USA Congress is considering introducing a bill to stop the launch of Libra, until regulatory questions about the project and its governance can be resolved. <ref type="bibr">133</ref> It is also perceivable that Facebook's Libra may have also been blocked by the USA as they wanted the cryptocurrency tied to the US dollar, rather than a basket of currencies as has been proposed. The Libra project is meeting with resistance in the UK as well. The Bank of England said that the Libra cryptocurrency project would need to grant access to the Bank of England for the purpose of monitoring payment chain information. China, in the meantime believes Libra is doomed to fail because it lacks international regulatory or political support. <ref type="bibr">134</ref> The vice chairman of the China International Economic Exchange Center predicts that China's central bank instead will be the first to issue a Central Bank Digital Currency-a centrally controlled and managed currency.</p><p>Much of the resistance whilst coming from governments (central banks losing control and the fear that Facebook will get even more access to consumer data (although the Libra prospectus made it clear that Facebook will not have access to the data generated by these transactions)), is also being driven by incumbent banks, who have a lot to lose if Libra becomes successful as a payment platform and reduce significantly, the commissions the banks and other players in the value chain get for every transaction.</p><p>As predicted, advanced economies are starting to coordinate on cryptocurrency regulation, as they have on other measures to prevent money laundering and tax evasion. But that leaves out a lot of disgruntled players-including Cuba, Iran, Libya, North Korea, Somalia, Syria, Venezuela and Russia, all of whom are labouring under USA financial sanctions. Their governments will not necessarily care about global externalities if they encourage cryptocurrencies that might have value in their home markets. In response to Iran's actions, USA lawmakers have introduced at least two bills explicitly aiming to curb the development of a statebacked 'Digital Rial'. Bill S.3758 (sec 306), sponsored by Senate Republicans in December 2018, aims to "impose sanctions with respect to Iranian financial institutions and the development and use of Iranian digital currency. . .". <ref type="bibr">135</ref> The bill, has been read twice and was deferred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. The Bill requests the USA Secretary of the Treasury to report to Congress on Iran's efforts and its potential implications, alongside other measures. It further quotes the Civil Defense Organisation of Iran as having stated that "cryptocurrencies can help bypass certain sanctions through untraceable banking operations." In another example, Venezuela has allegedly issued the 'petro' digital currency on the NEM Blockchain platform in February 2018, in part to serve as a mechanism to attract government financing during rapidly deteriorating domestic economic conditions and a plummeting Bolivar. It is supposedly backed by the state's oil and mineral reserves. The 'petro' may also support sanctions circumvention.  Within the USA, the Commodities Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) has designated certain cryptoassets as commodities. Crypto futures, swaps, options, and other derivative contracts are subject to the same regulatory protocols as physical assets in this class. These regulations are focused on ensuring orderly markets and protecting against market manipulation. Exchanges will need to continue to enhance their surveillance for manipulation and fraud and act accordingly if malfeasance is detected. <ref type="bibr">136</ref> The SEC has concluded that certain cryptoassets, issued as part of ICOs, are securities under the Securities Act of 1933 and the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, which means they must be registered with the SEC-they have also made it clear that Bitcoin is not a security. <ref type="bibr">137</ref> The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) of the USA Treasury, considers crypto exchanges money service businesses, which means they are subject to existing banking regulations like the AML, Know Your Customer (KYC) and various financial reporting requirements. <ref type="bibr">138</ref> Organisations that trade crypto futures will be required to conduct business through a registered futures commission merchants (FCM) or introducing brokers (IB), which are regulated by the CFTC and National Futures Association (NFA). Furthermore, organisations wanting to offer futures trading will themselves be required to register with the CFTC and NFA as an FCM or IB.</p><p>The New York State Department of Financial Services (NYDFS) has required any entity operating in the crypto business in the state of New York and/or with New York residents to apply for a BitLicense. Other states have required crypto businesses to operate under money transmitter laws. Organisations that provide crypto custody services, perform exchange services, or issue crypto (virtual currency, money transmitter and exchange services) are subject to state money transmitter obligations, many of which require compliance with FinCEN's KYC and AML. The NYDFS BitLicense builds significantly on top of those requirements and includes, for example, significant cyber security requirements.</p><p>The USA Internal Revenue Service (IRS) has also issued guidance that some cryptoassets are to be treated as property and are subject to tax upon sale or exchange.</p><p>In Europe, some cryptoassets qualify as transferable securities and as such the legal framework for the regulation and supervision of financial instruments applies, including: the Prospectus Directive, the  with the fundamental concern that they have the potential to become investment objects. Payment tokens are not currently covered by MiDID II nor the Prospectus Regulation or the Market Abuse Regulation. Asset tokens generally come under the purview of financial regulation, especially where they give rights to a financial entitlement or entitlement in kind and are transferable. All cryptoassets and related activities are generally subject to Anti-Money-Laundering ('AML') provisions. China restricted its banks from using cryptocurrencies, banned ICOs and restricted cryptocurrency exchanges. South Korea has also banned ICOs. Algeria, Bolivia, Morocco, Nepal, Pakistan and Vietnam ban all cryptocurrency activities; Qatar and Bahrain bar domestic cryptocurrency activities; and Bangladesh, Colombia, Iran, Lithuania, Lesotho and Thailand ban financial institutions from facilitating transactions involving cryptocurrencies. <ref type="bibr">139</ref> Egypt has banned the use of cryptocurrencies to conduct commerce, Taiwan has prohibited its banks from accepting or transacting cryptocurrencies, Indonesia has prohibited the use of cryptocurrencies for payment and Vietnam does not allow cryptocurrencies to be used as a legal means of payment. <ref type="bibr">140</ref> In India, a government panel has recommended banning cryptocurrencies, which has been challenged in the courts.</p><p>In the middle of the spectrum, some governments are seeking to balance encouraging financial innovation and managing the risks posed by cryptocurrencies, whilst providing greater clarity surrounding the emergence of cryptocurrencies. These governments stop short of banning cryptocurrencies but are not actively seeking to become cryptocurrency hubs. Most major advanced economies, including the United States, Euro zone countries and the United Kingdom, have adopted this type of approach.</p><p>At the extreme end are countries that are embracing crypto developments. Switzerland is seeking to create a cryptocurrency industry, or 'Crypto Valley' located in the canton of Zug. The jurisdiction has tried to attract cryptocurrency companies and exchanges through the early adoption of regulations designed to provide regulatory certainty. Companies that created and promote Ethereum, the second largest cryptocurrency by value, are located in Zug and as many as 200 to 300 cryptocurrency entities have opened there in recent years. <ref type="bibr">141</ref> Singapore is also striving to become a cryptocurrency hub, with analysts describing its regulators as well-informed and transparent, compared to regulatory uncertainties in other jurisdictions.  However, the global picture is one of scepticism, especially in regards to stablecoins. On 13 October 2019, following Facebook's Libra, the Financial Stability Board (FSB) wrote to the G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors highlighting the regulatory challenges that the introduction of Global Stable Coin (GSC) would pose. <ref type="bibr">143</ref> According to the direction, GSC would raise new challenges for financial stability, consumer and investor protection, data privacy and protection, financial integrity (including AML/CFT and KYC compliance), mitigation of tax evasion, fair competition and anti-trust policy, as well as market integrity. On 17 October 2019, the Bank for International Settlements (BIS) referred to the challenges highlighted by the FSB and concluded that no GSC project would be authorised unless the challenges and risks outlined were adequately addressed. <ref type="bibr">144</ref> Both France 145 and Germany 146 have expressed views that GSC will not be allowed in their countries. I suspect this reaction is against the Facebook Libra proposals. Stablecoins that are relatively small in scale and whose purpose is well defined and designed to solve real problems are likely to be allowed over time. The question really will be, where that threshold lies.</p><p>At the moment however, the global response towards stablecoins is for governments to develop their own Central Bank Digital Currencies. According to a January 2019 report by the BIS, at least 40 central banks around the world are currently, or soon will be, researching and experimenting with Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC). <ref type="bibr">147</ref> In many of these CBDC pilots, the central bank issues digital tokens on a distributed ledger that represent and are redeemable for, central bank reserves in the domestic currency held in a separate account with the central bank. The agents in the system use the CBDC to make interbank transfers that are validated and settled on the distributed ledger. The central banks typically use a 'permissioned' Blockchain network, including: R3's Corda, the Linux Foundation's Hyperledger Fabric, J.P. Morgan's Quorum, or some form of an Ethereum Blockchain network. <ref type="bibr">148</ref> China has been proactively exploring its application of CBDC. A senior official at the Chinese central bank has stated that China's digital currency will be similar to Libra in that it will have the ability to be used across major payment platforms, <ref type="bibr">143</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.13">Privacy and Data Protection</head><p>In a world where data is becoming the new oil, the incentives to steal, pilfer, illegally sell or otherwise abuse data, increases dramatically. It therefore becomes natural for individuals to guard against access to their personal data. Artificial Intelligence (AI) is increasing the ability to derive intimate information from individuals public or aggregated data. This means that freely shared information of seeming innocence; where you ate lunch or what you bought at the grocery store, can lead to insights of a deeply sensitive nature. With enough data about you and the population at large, firms, governments and other institutions with access to AI will 1 day make guesses about you; what you like and whom you like.</p><p>On the other hand, significant economic and social value can be accrued when data is being used more intelligently and combined. It is therefore vital that a happy balance is found between these two extremes. Data integrity, control, security and protection are pivotal to the growth of the digital economy.</p><p>Many countries recognising this have sought to introduce data protection laws. The most stringent of these was the introduction of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) <ref type="bibr">149</ref> within the EU which enhanced upon the previous data protection directive. The GDPR was designed with the data economy in mind and was primarily a response to the power of large data processors such as Google having access to and processing the personal details of European residents whilst potentially being outside the jurisdiction of the EU. The extraterritorial provisions were largely to curtail such possibilities. GDPR is an example of a principles-based regulation. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.6 illustrates typical data protection principles-these are incorporated within the GDPR.</p><p>Many other countries, including the USA and China have a taken a less aggressive approach to data protection. Whilst Europe's practice of data minimisation and high data privacy standards can be seen as a disadvantage against the likes of China, where personal data flows more freely, in the long run, digital 'prosperity' will inevitably have to go hand in hand with citizens' well-being.</p><p>GDPR applies to both 'controllers' and 'processors'. A controller determines the purposes and means of processing 'personal data', whilst a processor is responsible for processing personal data on behalf of a controller. Both have legal obligations under GDPR. 'Personal data' refers to any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified, in particular by reference to an identifier: including name, identification number, location data or online identifier, 149 https://ec.europa.eu/info/priorities/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/2018-reformeu-data-protection-rules/eu-data-protection-rules_en reflecting changes in technology and the way organisations collect information about people. GDPR's principles of 'purpose specification' and 'limitation' requires that personal data must be collected for specified explicit and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a way incompatible with those purposes. Therefore the purposes of the processing must be determined prior to the collection of personal data by the data controller, who must also inform the data subject. When data controllers decide to process data in the digital space, they must ensure that personal data is not illegally processed for further purposes by it, or other stakeholders along the value chain. This will be a real challenge as we enter into an interconnected digital world where value will be created by sharing data across ecosystem players.</p><p>GDPR sets out a number of other important principles, amongst which include:</p><p>• Transparency: privacy notices for data sharing must be easy to access and to understand, explaining how data are processed, what are the individuals rights and how they can be enforced; • Consent: valid consent must be explicit for data collected and the purpose for the data collection must be stated. Data controllers must be able to collect 'consent' from end users (opt-in) and consent must be able to be withdrawn; • Erasure: data subjects have rights for their personal data to be deleted (right to be forgotten); • De-identification by default: whereby personal data is de-identified, sanitised or deleted as soon as there is no valid legal basis for processing/storage; • Data minimisation by default: reducing the collection of personal data and its processing; • Use of encryption by default: for personal data in transit and rest.</p><p>GDPR grants data subject rights not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling which produces legal effects concerning him or her or similarly significantly affects him or her (Article 22 GDPR). Profiling is defined in Article 4(4) as 'any form of automated processing of personal data consisting of the use of personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to the use of natural person, in particular to analyse or predict aspects concerning that natural person's performance at work, economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behaviour, location of movements'. As is clear, its scope is broad. Where organisations contemplate using automated decision making, GDPR also requires them to undertake a data protection impact assessment and assess the risks involved.</p><p>GDPR certainly goes much further than many other data protection regimes, some would argue it goes too far and potentially impedes the ability for innovative data driven businesses to thrive within the EU at the expense of less onerous regions. Nevertheless that sense of control over our data footprint is rather misleading. Whilst we have control over what information we share with digital platforms and mobile applications and have the ability to consent to the personal information that firms collect and use. Much of the valuable data about us is inferred beyond our control and without our consent. Digital firms can make observations of our behaviour through the metadata. This is data that provides context to our actions, such as where we were located when we ticked the do not consent box; the mobile phone we used; the network we were connected to; which other devices we may have used to access the same website; how long we spent reading certain articles; which links we clicked on; the pace and accuracy of our keystrokes when typing; or how we navigated through a page or app including touch screens. These patterns potentially help a firm build a psychological profile of us: our wealth, our intelligence level, our interest in certain subjects, what we like and don't like etc. This psychological profile is then fed into big datasets and analysed for similarities and differences with other profiles using AI to try and second guess what interests us, what we might be looking to buy, the type of brands we will most likely be associated with, and in turn push adverts to us-this explains the less sinister version. IOT and smart applications heightens the risks to personal privacy and the confidentiality and integrity of organisational data even further. Some IOT consumer applications, particularly those related to health and wellness, collect sensitive personal data that consumers might not wish to share, or data that you may not associate as directly being personal data, yet it might be used to infer your behaviours and profile you. Consumers may have no idea what kind of information is being acquired about them and why. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.7 illustrates the need for trust and transparency.</p><p>An important aspect that must be given consideration for digital transformation to take place and for participants to be provided the mechanisms to trust the various actors in the value chain is around building trusting relationships between data owners, data users and the various intermediaries. In a world where it will become increasingly difficult to establish data ownership, focus must shift to data control, To reap the benefits of the digital ecosystem, organisations and people need to trust the eco-system</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Asymmetries of power between the citizen and those controlling information about them</head><p>It requires treaƟng people with respect: having clear data ownership rights, the rights around the use of derivative data and customers' rights to consent and to withdraw such consent It calls for a need to be transparent with customers (even when using dumb devices)… E.g. Users of health/personal IoT devices like Fitbit may have allowed the equipment/service provider to take data for giving summary of lifestyle behaviors users Now an insurance company can acquire access to this data and modify the health insurance premiums based on the lifestyle behaviors -the device wearers may not have consented to this This could lead to discrimination and denial of services and to the detriment of users reflecting the right of a person or organisation to control and grant access rights to personal data and non-personal data and how this information can be shared with others (enhanced consent). It also reflects the fact that digital data can and in most cases will be shared and processed.</p><p>A common understanding of ownership rights to data produced by various connected devices will be required to unlock the full potential of IOT. Who has what rights to the data from a sensor manufactured by one company and part of a solution deployed by another in a setting owned by a third party will have to be clarified. For example, who has the rights to data generated by a medical device implanted in a patient's body? The manufacturer of the device? The health-care provider that implanted the device and is managing the patient's care? Or the patient themselves?</p><p>While ownership is important, appropriate license rights may provide an entity with everything it needs to conduct its analysis or monetisation activity, whilst allowing the 'owner' to retain rights of how such data is collected, processed and shared.</p><p>Often, collected data may need to be used for purposes other than its original intent, without express consent from the generator/owner of the data. Such use poses risks to the development of trust between the data subject and the whole digital ecosystem. The issue is really what data is being used. If it is meta data-i.e. data that is not personally identifiable or not provided by the data subject per se, but generated as a consequence of the data subject's use of a service, then what control do users have? Where such derived data are used to make decisions that affect the individual, albeit in another context, it is likely that it needs to be monitored and managed carefully.</p><p>This brings another area that needs to be managed carefully. Gaining consent from a data subject for collection and use of their personal information and importantly to allow such consent to be withdrawn or amended over time by the data subject (as required by GDPR). A important colliery to this is what happens to the data that has been shared with other parties or partners in the value chain-how will modifications to consent be communicated and given affect by all the actors in that value chain? These flows of data also raises an interesting question about liability across the value chain, especially when the value derived by each party in that chain may not correspond with the liability they are asked take on-different participants will have different thresholds for accepting their share of liability as their levels of economic benefit in the processing chain are different. The legal framework today handles single accountability scenarios well, but we are fast moving away from that world. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>.8 illustrates the need for establishing liability across the value chain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.13.1">Anonyimization Techniques</head><p>A common way to improve privacy is to de-aggregate date and anonymize it. De-aggregation breaks up a logical group of data into isolated pieces which in itself may not make much sense or help create any value. Policy makers and A number of techniques are emerging to enable the anonymization of data including:</p><p>• Differential privacy: Adding noise to the process (to the inputs, the calculations themselves or to the outputs). For example, census data is often anonymized with noise to protect the privacy of individual respondents; in the United States, differential privacy will be used for the 2020 Federal Census. 150 • Federated analysis: Conducting analysis on disparate datasets separately and then sharing back the insights from this analysis across the datasets. <ref type="bibr">151</ref> The technique has been widely used by large technology companies. <ref type="bibr">152</ref>   TensorFlow Federated, <ref type="bibr">153</ref> an open-source framework that allows machine learning to be performed on federated datasets. • Homomorphic encryption: Encrypts the data so that analysis can be performed on it, without the information itself ever being readable. <ref type="bibr">154</ref> The first fully homomorphic encryption (FHE) system was proposed in 2009 by Craig Gentry. 155 • Zero-knowledge proofs: Allows for one party to prove to another some specific information without sharing anything other than the intended information. <ref type="bibr">156</ref> As with federated analysis, the technique is being used in conjunction with other emerging technologies. • Secure multiparty computation (SMC): As with homomorphic encryption and zero-knowledge proofs, this technique allows for individual privacy to be maintained when sharing information with untrusted third parties. SMC relies on 'secret sharing', <ref type="bibr">157</ref> where sensitive data from each contributor is distributed across every other contributor as encrypted 'shares'. <ref type="bibr">158</ref> The first live implementation of SMC was in 2008, when it was used to determine sugar beet market prices in Denmark without revealing individual farmers' economic position. 159</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.13.2">Reliability and Accuracy Standards</head><p>Already a number of critical services like healthcare monitoring and weather monitoring are transitioning to more IOT type devices. This impacts people's lives and livelihood. So there are expectations of an extremely high level of reliability and accuracy of data coming from IOT devices, as the central processing algorithms and control functions rely entirely on the incoming data. To make IOT devices for all such applications affordable and increase their adoption, we run the risk of compromising on their reliability and accuracy of data capture, data transport and local computation capabilities. Policy makers and regulatory bodies must consider appropriate standards on how to balance affordability and quality, as well as the management of multiple hand-offs for data along the value chain.  </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.13.3">Data Mobility</head><p>Data portability can empower individuals, thus leading to better functioning and competitive markets and ultimately growth and consumer welfare benefits. Data portability can be seen through a data protection lens and can also be considered as a means to achieve the free flow of data in a world where a few data monoliths are attempting to control data. At a consumer's request, their data can be seamlessly shared by a business with the consumer's chosen third party. Personal data mobility however goes beyond just data portability. Data portability typically just refers to consumers being able to themselves request access to and move data from one business to another. Data mobility encompasses the ability for that data to be moved or shared directly between a business and a third party at the customer's request.</p><p>Data portability and mobility is expected to increase competition between providers of digital goods and services. However it does pose policy and implementation challenges, including concerns regarding data security and implementation costs, as well as practical issues such as when a request is made to port a photograph of two friends from one social network service to another, how can the rights of the second individual's privacy rights be respected here?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.13.4">Open Data</head><p>The value of many IOT, smart cities and applications of AI, is possible when public sector agencies release key sets of governmental data to the public for any use, or reuse, in an easily accessible manner. The value can be significantly increased when the data is discoverable, actionable and available in standard formats for machine readability. Much of the value of digital transformation can be destroyed if market participants are not provided access to such data. Recent McKinsey research found that open data could unlock some US$3 trillion in annual value. <ref type="bibr">160</ref> Research by Deloitte found that the release of open data by Transport for London is generating annual economic benefits and savings of up to £130 million a year. <ref type="bibr">161</ref> At the same time, evidence suggests that large data holdings are at the heart of some platform markets to be dominated by single players and for that dominance to be entrenched in a way that lessens the potential for competition for the market. In these circumstances, if other solutions do not work, data openness, could be the necessary tool to create the potential for new companies to enter the market and challenge an otherwise entrenched firm. Policy makers will need to carefully define </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>#</head><label></label><figDesc>Springer Nature Switzerland AG 2020 B. Vagadia, Digital Disruption, Future of Business and Finance, https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-54494-2_5</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>1 109 C</head><label>109</label><figDesc>European Commission. (2017). Legislative priorities for 2018-2019. Published on 14 December 2017. 2 Industrial Data Space Association. See http://www.industrialdataspace.org/en/ 5.2 Data/Cyber Security Risks</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5.1 Data privacy and security</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>and (iv) Network Access Layer (which combines the Data Link and Physical layers of the OSI layers).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_14"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5.2 Creating trust with data</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_15"><head>Fig. 5. 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 5.3 The CIA triad</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_20"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>These include: UNCITRAL Model Law on Electronic Commerce (MLEC) (1996); UNCITRAL Model Law on Electronic Signatures (MLES) (2001); United Nations Convention on the Use of Electronic Communications in International Contracts (ECC) (2005); UNCITRAL Model Law on Electronic Transferable Records (MLETR) (2017). To date, over 70 states have enacted the MLEC, while 22 Zimmerman, J., Bohling, K., Parker, S. (2014). Electronic G2P payments: evidence from four lower-income countries (English). CGAP focus note; no. 93. Washington, DC; World Bank Group.5.6 Data Availability and Access: Digital Signatures 125</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_29"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>If a Bitcoin owner wants to speed up their transaction, they can choose to offer a higher mining reward.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_30"><head>Fig</head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5.4The workings of Blockchain</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_31"><head>Fig</head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5.5 Blockchain-decentralised trust</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_32"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>IDC. (2019). Worldwide blockchain spending guide. See https://www.idc.com/getdoc.jsp? containerId¼IDC_P37345 43 Gartner. (2017). Forecast: blockchain business value, worldwide 2017-2030. 44 Sato, C., Wang, R. (2018). Constellation research 2018 digital transformation study. 45 World Economic Forum. (2019). Central banks and distributed ledger technology: how are central banks exploring blockchain today? 46 OECD. (2018). Blockchain and its use in the public sector. Observatory of Public Sector Innovation.47 Permission-less blockchains participates can join the network by downloading a software application like a wallet, and do not need permission or approval from another entity. of assets (Bitcoins) between different participants. In essence, Blockchain in the context of Bitcoin needed to provide: Trust, Traceability and Tradability.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_36"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>56 Weaver, N. (2018). Risks of cryptocurrencies communications of the ACM, June 2018, Vol. 61 No. 6, Pages 20-24. https://doi.org/10.1145/3208095</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_37"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>58  A May 2016 Goldman Sachs report suggests that strong account and payment information on a Blockchain could improve data quality and reduce compliance costs, savings US$3 to US$ 5 billion annually in AML expenses. See: Schneider, J., Blostein, A., Lee, B., Kent, S., Groer, I., Beardsley, E. (2016). Profiles in innovation: Blockchain-putting theory into practice. Goldman Sachs, 24 May 2016.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_44"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>5.9.1 Lightning NetworkThe Lightning Network (LN) sits on top of the Bitcoin network with a goal of moving most transactions off the Bitcoin Blockchain and thus presumably to make them cheaper and faster. The key ideas behind Lightning were proposed by Joseph Poon and Thaddeus Dryja in a 2015 white paper, but it's taken 3 years to translate the proposal into fully working code. Today, three different companies-San Francisco start-ups Blockstream and Lightning Labs and Paris start-up ACINQ are working on parallel implementations of the Lightning technology stack. The trio released version 1.0 of the Lightning specification in December 2017 and the companies are now racing to get their software ready for use by the general public.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_45"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>112 https://e-estonia.com/solutions/interoperability-services/x-road 113 Gerald, D. (2017). Imogen Heap: 'Tiny Human'. Total sales: $133.20. https://davidgerard.co.uk/</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_48"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>119 Massari, J. et al. (2018). The fragmented regulatory landscape for digital token. Harvard Law School Forum on Corporate Governance and Financial Regulation. 120 Tapscott, T. (2018). 2018 Blockchain regulation roundtable: addressing the regulatory challenges of disruptive innovation. Blockchain Research Institute.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_56"><head>125</head><label></label><figDesc>Securities and Markets Stakeholder Group (2018). Own Initiative Report on Initial Coin Offerings and Crypto-Assets. 19 October 2018 ESMA 22-106-1338. 5.12 Token Economics, Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_59"><head>128</head><label></label><figDesc>Figures as of 8 December 2019 from: https://www.coinschedule.com/stats.html 129 Many EU jurisdictions have issued warnings on the use of cryptocurrency but continue to apply existing legal principles. 130 Gibraltar and Malta are examples of countries advocating cryptocurrency. See Gibraltar Finance. 2018. "Token Regulation: Proposals for the Regulation of token Sales, Secondary token Market Platforms, and Investment Services Relating to Tokens." Parliament of Malta, Virtual Financial Assets Act 2018. 131 Massari, J., Nazareth, A., Zweihorn, Z. (2018). The fragmented regulatory landscape for digital tokens. Harvard Law School Forum on Corporate Governance. See: https://corpgov.law.harvard. edu/2018/03/26/the-fragmented-regulatory-landscape-for-digital-tokens/</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_60"><head>132</head><label></label><figDesc>Source: U.S. Treasury Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN), FinCEN Fines BTC e virtual currency exchanges $110 million for facilitating ransomware, Dark Net Drug Sales (July 27, 2017). 133 Discussion Draft, 116th Congress, 1st Session (18 October 2019). See: https://financialservices. house.gov/uploadedfiles/bills-116pih-ssa.pdf 5.12 Token Economics, Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings (</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_63"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>142 139 The Law Library of Congress. (2018). Regulation of cryptocurrency around the world. Global Legal Research Center, Law Library of Congress, June 2018. See: https://www.loc.gov/law/help/ cryptocurrency/cryptocurrency-world-survey.pdf 140 The Law Library of Congress. (2018). Regulation of cryptocurrency around the world. Global Legal Research Center, Law Library of Congress, June 2018. See: https://www.loc.gov/law/help/ cryptocurrency/cryptocurrency-world-survey.pdf 141 Irrera, A., Neghaisi, B. (2018). Switzerland seeks to regain cryptocurrency crown. Reuters, July 19, 2018. 142 Yang, J. (2018). Singapore is the crypto sandbox that Asia needs. TechCrunch, September 22, 2018.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_65"><head>including</head><label></label><figDesc>WeChat and Alipay, which both dominate the mobile payment market in China.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_66"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5.6 General data protection principles</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_68"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Fig. 5.7 Creating trust in data usage</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_69"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>to consider setting out clear guidelines that industry can follow to capitalise on the use of personal data but with appropriate safeguards in place, including recommended anonymization techniques.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_70"><head>3Fig. 5. 8 5</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Fig. 5.8 Liability across the value chain</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_72"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>which personal data can be shared and in what format it can shared. Where risks of data monopolies are unacceptably large, policy may need to focus on creating data exchanges and trusts, accessible by all participants and not the few.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>There were two variants of symmetric systems until 2005; DES and AES:• Data Encryption Standard (DES): DES is a symmetric block cipher (shared secret key), with a key length of 56-bits and 16 rounds (shifts, XORS).</figDesc><table><row><cell>Published as the</cell></row><row><cell>USA Federal Information Processing Standards (FIPS) 46 standard in 1977, DES</cell></row><row><cell>was officially withdrawn in 2005. The federal government originally developed</cell></row><row><cell>DES encryption to provide cryptographic security for all government</cell></row><row><cell>communications. Although its short key length of 56 bits criticised from the</cell></row><row><cell>beginning, makes it too insecure for most current applications, it was highly</cell></row><row><cell>influential in the advancement of modern cryptography.</cell></row><row><cell>• Advanced Encryption Standard (AES): Published as a FIPS 197 standard in 2001,</cell></row><row><cell>is a more mathematically efficient and elegant cryptographic algorithm, but its</cell></row><row><cell>main strength rests in the option for various key lengths. AES allows you to</cell></row><row><cell>choose a 128-bit, 192-bit or 256-bit key, making it exponentially stronger than the</cell></row><row><cell>56-bit key of DES. AES offers vast speed improvements over DES.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Will crowd based capitalism replace managerial capitalism? http://reinvent.net/innovator/arunsundararajan 41 Marshall, A. (2017). Bitcoin scaling problem explained. CoinTelegraph, 02 March 2017.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>FinTech start-ups Transferwise and Remitly 72 are disrupting the global payments (remittances) market, estimated at over US$600 billion in 2016.73  The global remittance industry takes out US$40 billion annually in fees.74  Such fees typically stand around 2-7% of the total transaction value, depending on the volume of the corridor and foreign exchange fees represent</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Charity Digital</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">News. 7 November 2017.</cell></row><row><cell>66 See:</cell><cell>https://www.technologyrecord.com/Article/gainforest-microsoft-and-the-un-join-on-</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">sustainability-project-83119</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">67 Cuff, M., (2018). Ben and Jerry's scoop blockchain pilot to serve up carbon-offset ice-cream.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">BusinessGreen, 30 May 2018.</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">68 Carbon on Blockchain, Poseidon Foundation: See: https://poseidon.eco/carbon.html</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">69 Ecosphere+: https://ecosphere.plus</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">70 https://www.fastcompany.com/3060459/how-sneaker-designers-are-busting-knockoffs-with-</cell></row><row><cell>bitcoin-tech</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell cols="2">71 https://www.coindesk.com/ethereum-used-first-paid-energy-trade-using-blockchain-technology</cell></row></table><note>69   • In retail: shoe designer Great released its Beastmode 2.0 Royale Chukkah collection in 2016 with a Blockchain enabled smart tag that enables customers to confirm the authenticity of their trainers with their smart phone. Customs officials used the same technology to seize US$50 million of its counterfeit shoes entering the USA in 2014. 70 • In energy distribution: Consensys is partnering on Transactive Grid, working with the distributed energy firm, LO3. A prototype project currently up and running uses Ethereum smart contracts to automate the monitoring and redistribution of micro grid energy. This so-called 'intelligent grid' is also an early example of emerging IOT use cases. 71 • In finance:65 Clark, A. (2017). Blockchain based recycling initiative to benefit third sector. 72 Vijaya, R. (2016). Mitigating the effects of de-risking in emerging markets to preserve remittance flows. IFC. 73 Ratha, D. (2016). Migration and remittances Factbook 2016, Third Edition. World Bank Group. 74 Pitchbook. (2016). Can blockchain live up to the hype? Press Release, October 4.</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>134 LaVere, M. (2019). Chinese Official Slams Libra, Says Central Bank will Issue Digital Currency First. See: https://www.cryptoglobe.com/latest/2019/10/chinese-official-slams-libra-says-centralbank-will-issue-digital-currency-first 135 S.3758-Blocking Iranian Illict Finance Act. 115th Congress (2017-2018). See: https://www. congress.gov/bill/115th-congress/senate-bill/3758/text</figDesc><table><row><cell>164</cell><cell>5 Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Transparency Directive, MiFID II, the Market Abuse Directive, the Short Selling Regulation, the Central Securities Depositories Regulation and the Settlement Finality Directive. Utility tokens are generally not covered by financial regulation. The key test is if they are transferable, 136 Foxley, W. (2019). CFTC Chairman Confirms Ether Cryptocurrency Is a Commodity. See: https://www.coindesk.com/cftc-chairman-confirms-ether-cryptocurrency-is-a-commodity 137 United States Securities and Exchanges Commission. Cipher Technologies Bitcoin Fund. Financial Crimes and Enforcement Network. (2014). Administrative ruling on the application of FinCEN's regulations to a virtual currency trading platform (October 27, 2014).5.12 Token Economics, Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings (ICO) 165</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Letter</cell></row><row><cell>dated</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>October</cell><cell>2019.</cell><cell>See:</cell><cell>https://www.sec.gov/Archives/edgar/data/1776589/</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">999999999719007180/filename1.pdf</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>138</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_9"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Financial Stability Board. (2019). To G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors. See: https://www.fsb.org/wp-content/uploads/P131019.pdf 144 Bank for International Settlements. (2019). Investigation the impact of global stablecoins. Report of the G7 Working Group on Stablecoins. See: https://www.bis.org/cpmi/publ/d187.pdf 145 Rattaggi, M., Longchamp, Y. (2019). International regulators tackle the issues of stable coins and digital money. See: https://www.seba.swiss/research/International-regulators-tackle-the-issuesof-stable-coins-and-digital-money/#1 146 https://www.bis.org/cpmi/publ/d187.pdf 147 Bank for International Settlements. (2019). Proceeding with caution-a survey on central bank digital currency. BIS Papers No 101. January 2019. See: https://www.bis.org/publ/bppdf/ bispap101.pdf 148 World Economic Forum. (2019). Central Banks and distributed ledger technology: how are Central Banks Exploring Blockchain Today? World Economic Forum Whitepaper, March 2019. 5.12 Token Economics, Cryptocurrencies and Initial Coin Offerings (ICO) 167</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_10"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>In March 2019, TensorFlow (a widely used open-source library for machine learning) published That requires the establishment of clear liability across the value chain for customer data and derivative data usageThe analysis and control actions change multiple hands in a typical IoT ecosystem E.g. a wearable device might capture heartbeat and few other indicators, then transmits it to some processor of the data, which uses algorithms</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>from another provider to</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>calculate health risks and the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>need for emergency response,</cell></row><row><cell>So, if something goes wrong in that value</cell><cell>and sends it to a healthcare</cell></row><row><cell>chain -who is accountable?</cell><cell>provider, who in turn uses a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>different service for patient</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>monitoring, who…..</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_11"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>153 Ingerman, A., Ostrowski, K. (2019). Introducing TensorFlow Federated. See: https://medium. com/tensorflow/introducing-tensorflow-federated-a4147aa20041 154 Branscombe, M. (2019). Is homomorphic encryption ready to deliver confidential cloud computing to enterprises? See: https://www.techrepublic.com/article/is-homomorphic-encryptionready-to-deliver-confidential-cloud-computing-to-enterprises 155 https://crypto.stanford.edu/ 156 Goldwasser, S., Micali, S., Rackoff, C.(1985). The knowledge complexity of interactive proofsystems. See: https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id¼22178 157 Two-party computation is a special case of SMC where only two entities are involved in the datasharing (as opposed to multiparty computation, where a number of entities can be involved).</figDesc><table><row><cell>174</cell><cell>5 Data Integrity, Control and Tokenization</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>multiparty-computa</cell></row><row><cell>tion-in-practice</cell><cell></cell></row></table><note>158 Shamir, A., Rivest, R., Adleman, L. (1979). Mental Poker. Massachetts Institute of Technology. 159 https://ercim-news.ercim.eu/en73/special/trading-sugar-beet-quotas-secure-</note></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="20">Pretty Good Privacy (PGP) is an encryption program that provides cryptographic privacy and authentication for data communication.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot">t r a c k ers of t w a r e . c o m</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="160">McKinsey. (2013). Open data: Unlocking innovation and performance with liquid information. 161 Deloitte. (2017). Assessing the value of TfL's open data and digital partnerships. July 2017. See: http://content.tfl.gov.uk/deloitte-report-tfl-open-data.pdf 5.13 Privacy and Data Protection</note>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Distributed Ledger Technology and Blockchain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harish</forename><surname>Natarajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Solvej</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Gradstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1596/29053</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
			<publisher>World Bank, Washington, DC</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Washington, D.C</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Profiles in innovation: blockchain-putting theory into practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Blostein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Kent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Groer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Beardsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-05" />
			<publisher>Goldman Sachs</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page">24</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Organization of the Provincial Stock Exchanges, 1914–1960</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Rizzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4324/9781315020471-19</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/10-stock-exchanges-blockchain" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Provincial Stock Exchanges</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Routledge</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013-11-05" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="248" to="264" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Nasdaq Exec: exchange Is &apos;All-In&apos; on using blockchain technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>French</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.thestreet.com/investing/nasdaq-all-in-on-blockchain-technology-14551134" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A BLOCKCHAIN-BASED AUDITABLE AND SECURE VOTING SYSTEM</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Madhukara</forename><surname>Kekulandara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.23860/thesis-kekulandara-madhukara-2020</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/nasdaq-shareholder-voting-estonia-blockchain" />
		<imprint>
			<date>2016</date>
			<publisher>University of Rhode Island</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The first government to secure land titles on the bitcoin blockchain expands project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurashin/2017/02/07/the-first-government-to-secure-land-titles-on-the-bitcoin-blockchain-expands-project" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Republic of georgia to pilot land titling on blockchain with economist Hernando De Soto, BitFury</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurashin/2016/04/21/republic-of-georgia-to-pilot-land-titling-on-blockchain-with-economist-hernando-de-soto-bitfury/#3e96f70844da" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Pioneer in real estate blockchain emerges in Europe</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Anand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.wsj.com/articles/a-pioneer-in-real-estate-blockchain-emerges-in-europe-1520337601" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Swedish government land registry soon to conduct first blockchain property transaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zuckerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cointelegraph.com/news/swedish-government-land-registry-soon-to-conduct-first-blockchain-property-transaction" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">UK land registry begins new phase of blockchain research project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/tag/hm-land-registry" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Indian state wants to use blockchain to fight land ownership fraud</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cnbc.com/2017/10/10/this-indian-state-wants-to-use-blockchain-to-fight-land-ownership-fraud.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The First Government to secure land titles on the bitcoin blockchain expands project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Shin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurashin/2017/02/07/the-first-government-to-secure-land-titles-on-the-bitcoin-blockchain-expands-project/#167b5fa04dcd" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blockchain and distributed ledger technologies � Overview of and interactions between smart contracts in blockchain and distributed ledger technology systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Aitken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3403/30384568</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/rogeraitken/2016/04/05/bitlands-african-blockchain-initiative-putting-land-on-the-ledger/#405d82507537" />
		<imprint>
			<date>2016</date>
			<publisher>BSI British Standards</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Russia&apos;s Government to test blockchain land registry system</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/russias-government-test-blockchain-land-registry-system" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Zug ID: exploring the first publicly verified blockchain identity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Kohlhaas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://medium.com/uport/zug-id-exploring-the-first-publicly-verified-blockchain-identity-38bd0ee3702" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Finland solves refugee identity with blockchain debit cards</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Suberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cointelegraph.com/news/finland-solves-refugee-identity-with-blockchain-debit-cards" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The AI‐powered Internet Celebrities and Fans Economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rueter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781119749073.ch4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.secureidnews.com/news-item/digital-id-japan-powered-blockchain" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Digital ID in Japan to be powered by blockchain</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020-12-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inert announces partnership with Sievgen</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Douglas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.mprp.2017.08.016</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.govtech.com/data" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Metal Powder Report</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Metal Powder Report</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0026-0657</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">72</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">365</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017-09" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Five examples of United Nations agencies using blockchain technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Vota</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ictworks.org/united-nations-agencies-using-blockchain-technology/#.Wuhijn8h1hE" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accenture and Microsoft add blockchain tech to biometrics ID platform</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/s0969-4765(17)30141-8</idno>
		<ptr target="http://fortune.com/2017/06/19/id2020-blockchain-microsoft" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biometric Technology Today</title>
		<title level="j" type="abbrev">Biometric Technology Today</title>
		<idno type="ISSN">0969-4765</idno>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2017</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017-07" />
			<publisher>Elsevier BV</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regional government in Russia to test blockchain payments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Milano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/regional-government-russia-test-blockchain-payments" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UAE—Saudi Arabia Negotiating Behaviour (1970—4)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Buntinx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5040/9781350989337.ch-004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://themerkle.com/uae-and-saudi-arabia-collaborate-on-new-central-bank-digital-currency-research" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The UAE and Saudi Arabia</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>I.B.Tauris</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The AI‐powered Internet Celebrities and Fans Economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Rueter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/9781119749073.ch4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.secureidnews.com/news-item/digital-id-japan-powered-blockchain" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Digital ID in Japan to be powered by blockchain</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020-12-07" />
			<biblScope unit="page" from="105" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">APAPO builds on work to protect psychological testing data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Basu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/e562102011-006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://govinsider.asia/smart-gov/singapore-government-builds-blockchain-system-to-protect-banks" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010" />
			<publisher>American Psychological Association (APA)</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Australia&apos;s ASX selects blockchain to cut costs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mathew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Irrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-asx-blockchain/australias-asx-selects-blockchain-to-cut-costs-idUSKBN1E037R" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">US Government lab looks to blockchain for P2P energy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sundararajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/us-government-lab-blockcypher-tap-blockchain-for-p2p-energy-transactions" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Chile is using Ethereum&apos;s blockchain to track energy data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Floyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.coindesk.com/chile-to-use-ethereums-blockchain-to-track-energy-data" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Guardtime secures over a million Estonian healthcare records on the blockchain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Allison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.ibtimes.co.uk/guardtime-secures-over-million-estonian-healthcare-records-blockchain-1547367" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Nordic way to blockchain in healthcare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Marenco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.himss.eu/himss-blog/nordic-way-blockchain-healthcare" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">UK&apos;s first trial of blockchain in healthcare</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.telegraph.co.uk/business/business-reporter/blockchain-trial-in-healthcare" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Massachusetts general Hospital piloting Blockchain projects with Korean start-up</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Miliard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.healthcareitnews.com/news/massachusetts-general-hospital-piloting-blockchain-projects-korean-start-up" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
